<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Top Stories Slider &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/top-stories-slider/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:26:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>China: Humanitarian Aid is a Given</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/china-humanitarian-aid-is-a-given-ready-to-be-published/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As more debate arises in the Security Council on the Russia-Ukraine War, China raises its position on the solution by vetoing the resolution of humanitarian]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As more debate arises in the Security Council on the Russia-Ukraine War, China raises its position on the solution by vetoing the resolution of humanitarian aid in the council.</p>



<p>The reason for this is that China believes through this crisis the Security Council has failed to commit to helping the major crisis going on within Ukraine. If the Security Council cannot commit to the bigger task that was at hand the act for humanitarian aid should be put at a pause.</p>



<p>The Security Council failed to amend a peace talk between Russia and Ukraine and has failed to release any statement on the matter. The representative from China commented, &#8220;it shows a lack of commitment towards ending a War&#8221; and putting funds toward humanitarian aid would be unreasonable due to the lack of commitment the Council has. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BREAKING NEWS: Classified US Government Documents released to the Public</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/breaking-news-classified-us-government-documents-released-to-the-public/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To our fellow Americans,&#160; This letter was drafted by Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson depicts the status of women in the eyes of the U.S.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To our fellow Americans,&nbsp;</p>



<p>This letter was drafted by Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson depicts the status of women in the eyes of the U.S. Cabinet and Vice President. This letter was in response to the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women after they proposed multiple resolutions to address the labor standards of women, women&#8217;s civic engagement, and women’s engagement in the ongoing Missile Crisis in Cuba. To highlight some of his sentiments, he stated that the sentiments of the PCSW were not priorities, and the administration does not have the time to address any of these issues.</p>



<p>The women in America should not take elements of this letter and be content. The women in America should take this letter as an opportunity to prove to their governmental representatives that their contributions to the public sphere are still relevant to embody the capitalist values of our society.</p>



<p><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/k2LLD4vH6iG_JblqhSpS7QsFl6lsj-xA1Nq8CGOue96ary85kG9YWrti95zeUa6wg-fztL4HtSOOYSDmge2APDOfS56tYtsynR3JC_DMGzOxAPsU6RjT2FKPo9LubOa6dkEjcORgJqsKT6JUqrZ9Obi98ZavgddFmkZIYNaOczrI3aFtS7hyuom5QlUSKg" width="93" height="93"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/9NG4gKNdsHHLkjYuYZtZWGnZdQI03dXQybaSSuIXeeYcNA_usYSBVFcvxgO8NW6CVW0gGiuxV6Iz5rU8EJyVO_aVxx3I1oSQ3VPCuDLORUw8Gq6rZ6otpPz0L8FXCl-eHAi-PV-AXTsq-h1zW6OCxhm7rFB-qqWKgvvxINpdOp6-38nkewZyZdMsdC0oWQ" width="160" height="84"></p>



<p>Letter from LBJ</p>



<p>Office of President John F. Kennedy</p>



<p>Washington D.C.<br>October 1962</p>



<p>_____________________________________________________________________________</p>



<p>October 1962, Washington D.C. &#8211;</p>



<p>While your input on policy has been appreciated previously. I have the unfortunate task of informing your commission that we currently cannot pursue your policies regarding women in the workplace. They may have some potential, but because of the events occurring in Cuba, the President does not have the time to review them.</p>



<p>Your commitment to our nation is admirable, and I have nothing but respect for Mrs. Roosevelt. However, while we struggle with a response to this crisis, we cannot spare any time to review this report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Office of the Vice President of the United States of America</p>



<p>Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson</p>



<p>The letter, when delivered to Mrs. Roosevelt, the former first lady,&nbsp; <em>may</em> have contributed to her death, it seemed to have caused her weak heart to give out. Unfortunately, she passed away later that night, and America lost a national treasure. Now the American people are faced with a decision, will we tolerate her death? Will we let Mr. Vice President Lyndon B Johnson gets away with his disregard for women or will we stand up to him? <strong>America stands true today, and America will stand strong tomorrow, with women behind it.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Concerned American Citizen</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNSC: Disappointment Over Veto</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/unsc-disappointment-over-veto/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UN Security Council is facing debates over the humanitarian aid paper as China has used its veto power and has vetoed the idea of]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The UN Security Council is facing debates over the humanitarian aid paper as China has used its veto power and has vetoed the idea of humanitarian aid for the Russia-Ukraine war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The sole purpose of this paper was to help both sides in the conflict, as seen in the proposed paper, by being able to have equal sponsors and aid sent on both sides for the reason of basic human equality. It was supposed to help the millions of civilians living in distress, which now seems a hard goal to reach. </p>



<p>The United States has had very strong opinions regarding this situation as they do not support the use of the veto. The United States is against China’s veto in the humanitarian aid paper as there was perhaps no true basis for China to use its powers. It is also important to note that this humanitarian aid paper was supported by the Russian Federation. </p>



<p>In an interview with the United States, they expressed their deep disappointment, saying, “humanitarian aid was crucial, and support for both eastern and western powers was on this paper. It is disappointing that China has used its veto powers.” </p>



<p>Changes occur rapidly within this conflict and the UNSC’s debate only further stretches out the future of this nation. </p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Castro announces nuclear capabilities, takes credit for downed U2 spy plane</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/castro-announces-nuclear-capabilities-takes-credit-for-downed-u2-spy-plane/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="CIMUN XX - A speech by Castro" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pYF3LZ5qoaU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PR China Broadens Foreign Affairs</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/pr-china-broadens-foreign-affairs-edit-suggested/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:23:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=201</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recent development in the border dispute between India and People&#8217;s Republic of China seems to be making its way to resolution and some harmony between]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Recent development in the border dispute between India and People&#8217;s Republic of China seems to be making its way to resolution and some harmony between the countries. Ministers of the People&#8217;s Republic of China have opened up on their desire for sanctity and peace with India in terms of the conflict. They have also been speaking about their motivations to build longer ties with foreign nations in general.</p>



<p>The violent border dispute has led to the unfortunate loss of around 1,300 Chinese lives, always keeping China on the defense. However, developments show an inclination by China for outreach to India on the matter with optimistic perspectives. Agreement with peace is driven to be made with India through varied forms of cooperation such as trade or research developments. The Chinese Minister of Foreign Affairs claims, &#8220;China obviously strives in order to emphasize the importance of communication, and in doing so China hopes to reach out with India in order to promote peace at the Border.&#8221; This attempt at an agreement is forthcoming, yet still in the works as updates have shown. Despite the fluctuating history between China and India, this may be hopeful for the two nations&#8217; futures.</p>



<p>Not only is mutuality with India in the focus of this cabinet but also other foreign affairs and allies with other Asian nations. PRC desires to mitigate their isolationist ways by industrializing and potentially uniting with other nations to have a mutual respect and spread their socialist idealism. The PRC&#8217;s Head of Publicity Department spoke to this topic: &#8220;In a new and open and growing China we need to be open to partners no matter where they come from because ultimately we all share the ultimate goal of socialism, of liberation for the people, for the workers, and simply put the happiness of every citizen.&#8221; China&#8217;s initiative for a new age of growth and global connections is an opportunity for many other nations as well as for China and self-development.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X unveils plan for &#8216;everything&#8217; app</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/x-unveils-plan-for-everything-app/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Social network company X (formerly known as Twitter) has recently announced its transition from solely social media into an &#8220;everything app.&#8221; Everything apps, also called]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Social network company X (formerly known as Twitter) has recently announced its transition from solely social media into an &#8220;everything app.&#8221; Everything apps, also called &#8220;super apps,&#8221; are mobile apps that can handle many aspects of digital life. These aspects include but are not limited to: direct messaging, video calls, location sharing, mobile payments, online shopping, games, online banking, and delivery services. </p>



<p>In an closed door interview with the Washington Post, X Director of Human Resources and Chair of Legal Department released specifics on some of the new features coming to the platform. These features will all be contained within a new app called X-Connect. It should be noticed that this will separate the parent company X from the daughter everything app that will be X-Connect, a situation similar to that of Uber and UberEats. Some of the features that can be expected to be found on X-Connect are an in-app browser extension, a professional business social network, an in-app streaming platform, and an artificial intelligence (A.I.) assistant.</p>



<p>Moreover, during a press conference Thursday, X Director of Public Relations made the promise that X will be the app that connects us all, in addition that &#8220;[X] will be the app that everyone has and everyone uses&#8221;. If the features that the company plans to release can successfully connect with its intended global audience, X&#8217;s aspirations may not be as unobtainable as they may seem.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNGA: The Real &#8220;Heroes&#8221; of Climate Change</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/unga-the-real-heroes-of-climate-change/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UNGA plans for solving the climate crisis have reached a stalemate. The general assembly is slow on their topic and the world does not]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The UNGA plans for solving the climate crisis have reached a stalemate. The general assembly is slow on their topic and the world does not have enough time for them to take their sweet time. No solution of any kind has been mainly addressed, countries are not getting anywhere on there on a plan of any kind. However, many countries pushed for the topic of climate change to be primarily addressed. </p>



<p>Since the 1850s, the climate crisis has shadowed the world every day. The climate of the world has been majorly changing the ideologies of countries through the years. Today the climate crisis is a major crisis for each and every country and the UNGA is taking their time on the issue that has increasingly been affecting every country. The UNGA will be wiped out because of climate change before they can help climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Delegations such as New Zealand have stated that “These solutions have taken much longer than they would like” and climate change is going to affect countries faster than we think. Other countries such as Tanzania say ,“ They agree with the resolutions going on currently.” The UNGA needs to pick a common direction and recommend a plan before it&#8217;s too late. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>City council looks to abandoned buildings to house migrants</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/city-council-looks-to-abandoned-buildings-to-house-migrants/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ari Ramjit, Pan African News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 20:55:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=263</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[2 full committee sessions done. 5 different blocs, 5 different focused problems, 4 different working papers and 1 passed ordinance. There has been a lot]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>2 full committee sessions done. 5 different blocs, 5 different focused problems, 4 different working papers and 1 passed ordinance. There has been a lot of debate on whether the aldermen of the Chicago City Council should focus on the migrants coming into the state or the Chicagoans that are already there. Their solution? Combine. </p>



<p>During the past committee session, the council, specifically Ald. Dowell, 3rd, Ald. Lee, 11th, Ald. Reilly, 42nd, and Ald. Sigcho-Lopez, 25th, passed a Short-term Migrant Solution (SMS) paper recognizing that there are many abandoned buildings that should be able to be used for the sake of housing migrants. The passed paper also recognizes workers that are needed to support the migrant shelters and acknowledges the necessity of providing proper funding. </p>



<p> &#8220;There are many school buildings that are abandoned which are in perfectly working condition but haven&#8217;t been used,&#8221; Ald. Lee, one of the ordinance sponsors, said. &#8220;We need to clean up, turn on the heating and air, etc. We hope to turn them into temporary shelters for migrants and homeless people in our city.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;Similarly there are other people in working on public safety and municipal marketing,&#8221; Ald. Lee said. &#8220;Essentially, our council is able to do as many topics as we wish. I believe multitasking and combining the paper is working well for our committee.&#8221; </p>



<p>Even though this paper has passed, the council is now working on another paper similar to the first but mainly focused on topic 3, municipal marketing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Liveblog (Historical)</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/friday-liveblog-historical/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael McCarthy, Deputy USG for Media]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Liveblog (Present Day)</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/friday-liveblog-present-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael McCarthy, Deputy USG for Media]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
