<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>United Nations Security Council (Present Day) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/unsc/feed/?simply_static_page=1145" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:24:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Food scarcity and the &#8220;Root of All Evil&#8221;</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/food-scarcity-and-the-root-of-all-evil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ella Cho, Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 03:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (Present Day)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tensions rose between the U.S. and Russia while the UNSC discussed the global food scarcity crisis. Russia’s invasion of Ukraine has only served to worsen]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Tensions rose between the U.S. and Russia while the UNSC discussed the global food scarcity crisis. </p>



<p>Russia’s invasion of Ukraine has only served to worsen the global food crisis. Much of the world is reliant on Ukrainian grain and the war has severely impacted Ukraine’s ability to export goods. </p>



<p>The representative from the U.S. feels strongly that food security cannot be achieved until the war in Russia and Ukraine is resolved. The representative even went as far as to claim Russia’s invasion of Ukraine is “the root of all evil” and “the direct cause” of the global food crisis. Russia, on the other hand, holds an opposing stance. </p>



<p>“Food security is not possible until western encroachment ends,” the representative of Russia stated. </p>



<p>When asked if the U.S. will continue to provide military aid to Ukraine knowing this information, the representative of the U.S. answered yes. The U.S. feels passionately that they and NATO have an obligation to protect the freedom of Ukrainian people. </p>



<p>When questioned about Russia’s involvement in the world hunger crisis, the Russian representative said, “the root of this crisis is NATO encroachment and western imperialism.”</p>



<p>Russia feels that until western forces stop intruding on Russia’s sovereignty, the international food security issue will be incredibly difficult to solve. Russia, in fact, finds the U.S.’s involvement in the Ukrainian-Russian conflict, “deeply concerning” and claims they are only exacerbating the already dire conditions. Who is truly to blame for the ongoing food crisis is unclear, what is incredibly clear though is that millions of lives are continuing to be lost due to starvation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Food insecurity takes over globally, where can migrants go?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/food-insecurity-takes-over-globally-where-can-migrants-go/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mira Polyakov, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (Present Day)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Russian invasion began on February 24, 2022, instigating the largest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II. Both Russia and Ukraine account for]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Russian invasion began on February 24, 2022, instigating the largest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II. Both Russia and Ukraine account for a large proportion of global exports of wheat and grain and limiting those exports caused severe implications for countries around the world, inducing a refugee crisis. Now, food insecurity struggles have been made prominent in the present UNSC committee, presenting insight from several dominant countries. Refugees face the struggle for a safe place to go, luckily, the United Kingdom, United States, and Japan have come to the rescue.</p>



<p>“The U.S. will gratefully help any misplaced person, regardless of background,” said the representative of the United States. </p>



<p>Migrants have a safe land to rely on when they are escaping the upheaval of food insecurity and war in Ukraine. Through a detailed interview, the representative mentioned that the care provided for the new migrants depends on where they go, and the local governments but are generally protected under American rights. However, they made it clear that although anybody will be welcomed, precautions will be taken with Russian migrants or refugees who actively participated in the Russian military. </p>



<p>“The U.S. can safely take in around 10,000 immigrants and refugees.” said the representative. </p>



<p>Minding the carrying capacity and a strong hatred of the Russian empire, the United States wishes to protect its citizens and offer a new haven for people wishing to escape to a new place they’ll call home.<br>The United Kingdom offers an innovative approach with the idea of sponsors. </p>



<p>“U.K. residents can apply to be sponsors and receive 350 pounds every month to house the refugees that are coming, and we’ve taken over about 115,000 refugees in this manner,” said the representative from the United Kingdom. </p>



<p>Over the years, the United Kingdom has donated 150 million pounds; about 181 million dollars to these refugee services, allowing a new way of life. Reliance on imports directly from the Russian-Ukrainian trade is not particularly important in the United Kingdoms, yet, a total of 9.7 million adults have fallen to food insecurity. With solutions to improve this globally, a confident statement that refugees will be well-supported stands true, opening their arms to migrants.</p>



<p>The flow of refugees is inevitable, yet it can be reduced. Safety and management are key to a growing population, but will this flow ever stop?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Correction on the UNSC Efforts in the Russia-Ukraine Conflict</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/correction-on-the-unsc-efforts-in-the-russia-ukraine-conflict/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 21:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (Present Day)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1096</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Due to an error in reporting there was a misquote on behalf of the United States of America, they are not in fact working on]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="699" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-8-1024x699.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1103" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-8-1024x699.png 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-8-300x205.png 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-8-768x524.png 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-8.png 1460w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Russian influence on Ukrainian Ports</figcaption></figure>



<p>Due to an error in reporting there was a misquote on behalf of the United States of America, they are not in fact working on closing the ports, but rather opening the ports. The U.S. has worked tirelessly to protect and support Ukraine during these troubling times and Le Monde takes all responsibility for the error. The U.S. is handling the situation in a responsible, well-timed manner. One of the most impactful things a nation can do to support a nation in crisis is to bolster its economy. In the directive the USA is working on, the U.S. is opening Ukrainian ports to export critical goods like grain not only supporting their economy but also their agricultural industry.</p>



<p>One of the epidemics the globe is facing is the catastrophe of world hunger, thousands of Tunisians, Libyans, and Pakistanis are starving because of the suffocation of the Ukrainian economy. By opening the ports Ukraine can begin to rebuild its GDP. Furthermore, opening Ukrainian ports is a soft offensive move towards Russia, the U.S. leading the stride to show Russia the world is watching them, and will not the attacks against Ukraine go without action. The security council is trying to reduce tensions in Eastern Europe, working tirelessly to create solutions to the Russia-Ukraine war.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UN Security Council Finds Solutions to Ukraine-Russia Conflict</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/un-security-council-finds-solutions-to-ukraine-russia-conflict/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 18:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (Present Day)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1005</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United Nations Security Council is navigating the conflict between Russia and Ukraine, and debating on how to preserve and support Ukraine while treating Russia]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="blob:https://press.cimun.org/fd145130-5cb4-473f-9b6e-eb90b69f0584" alt=""/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">UN Security Council 2023</figcaption></figure>



<p>The United Nations Security Council is navigating the conflict between Russia and Ukraine, and debating on how to preserve and support Ukraine while treating Russia with continuous care. Currently, the UNSC has no clear plan, however noting that they have several ideas, yet nothing is secure. The crisis in Eastern Europe is causing U.S. gas prices to rise, causing inflation and unreliability in the American Economy. Russia is one of the main oil exporters, however, with the sanctions currently placed on them, Russian oil exports are at an all-time low.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Council has decided to focus on economic issues second and prioritize the food crisis resulting from the war in Ukraine. Ukraine is one of the largest producers of agriculture, mainly grain, resulting in the people of Tunisia, Libya, and Pakistan going hungry. The Council is tackling current emergency issues before looking to the future. The USA states that &#8220;If we provide a short-term solution Ukraine will be strengthened.&#8221; Since the conflict and post-pandemic society, the number of severely food insecure people doubled from 135 million pre-pandemic to 276 million.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russia is currently blocking Ukrainian exports not allowing the nation to send out food, not only deterring their economy but directly contributing to global starvation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Security Council is working on a resolution paper to &#8220;strongly advise Ukraine to close its ports&#8221; according to the USA. Ukraine closing their ports seized by Russia is a strong defence of Ukrainian sovereignty, whilst not putting the committee on the offence to Russia.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kenya in a Food Crisis</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/kenya-in-a-food-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ella Cho, Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (Present Day)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=826</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kenya, along with the majority of other African countries, is experiencing one of the worst food crises in decades. The food crisis is a result]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Kenya, along with the majority of other African countries, is experiencing one of the worst food crises in decades. The food crisis is a result of numerous factors: Kenya’s extreme droughts, the COVID-19 pandemic, and the ongoing war between Ukraine and Russia, which combined account for more than 40% of Africa’s grain supply. The effects of food insecurity are devastating. “3.5 million Kenyans are experiencing extreme hunger. Roughly one person, in Kenya, Ethiopia, or Somalia, will die of starvation every 48 seconds”, the representative from Kenya said. Malnutrition poses as an even greater threat to already vulnerable populations and nearly one million children under five years of age and pregnant or breastfeeding women are experiencing malnutrition, said the World Food Programme.</p>



<p> Death isn’t the only side effect of food scarcity. According to the International Federation of Red Cross, also known as the IFRC, the hunger crisis in Kenya has caused, “higher rates of child marriage, increased school drop outs and escalating conflicts as people try to cope and access precious resources”. Food scarcity has massive ripple effects across the country and will continue to wreak havoc in Kenya as a result. The food crisis only appears to be getting worse as the number of Kenyans in need of urgent food assistance increased five-fold between August of 2020 and June of 2022 the World Food Programme reported. </p>



<p>Ultimately, the hunger crisis in Kenya, and other African countries, is a dire issue which can no longer go ignored. This situation must become a priority for the UNSC before millions of lives are lost to starvation. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
