<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cabinet of the Russian Federation &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/archive/2021/category/cabinet-of-the-russian-federation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 01:37:01 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>Nukes &#038; Charli D&#8217;Amelio: Interviews with Iran and Israel</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/nukes-charli-damelio-interviews-with-iran-and-israel/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Justin Wytmar, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 19:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=365</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Sunday, the Iranian Ambassador to Russia released a statement to the New York Times stating that they had finally reached a deal with the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On Sunday, the Iranian Ambassador to Russia released a statement to the New York Times stating that they had finally reached a deal with the Russian Federation. In exchange for admission into the Collective Security Treaty Organization (CSTO), the Iranians will make a number of concessions to the Russian Federation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Iranian and Russian militaries will begin joint military exercises along Iran&#8217;s Western border, the two nations will deploy their navies to the Strait of Hormuz, and seven percent of the Russian Air Force will be sent to support Iran. Additionally, Russia will be obliged to defend Iran if it is attacked militarily. This gives Iran significant backing if they were roped into a conflict with Western powers.</p>



<p>However, the Iranian cabinet is not waiting to be dragged into a nuclear war. They are ready to start a war themselves. In a statement released to the New York Times, an Iranian minister stated that Iran, &#8220;will be nuking Florida out of spite.&#8221; The Iranians also seem to want to enter the North Korean conflict. The Iranian Minister stated that Iran might nuke Korea because, &#8220;we want girlboss Kim Yo Jung to win.&#8221;</p>



<p>In a recent directive shared with the Times, the Iranians expressed a desire to &#8220;upload the Ayatollah&#8217;s consciousness to a computer,&#8221; and &#8220;enslave Charli D&#8217;Amelio &#8211; to be used as a defense mechanism in the Strait of Hormuz.&#8221; The New York Times was granted an exclusive interview with the Israeli Cabinet to discuss the Iran situation. The Israeli ministers dismissed the Iranian plans, stating that enslaving Charli D&#8217;Amelio was &#8220;not plausible,&#8221; and that they could simply &#8220;unplug&#8221; the computer version of Ayatollah Khamenei. &nbsp;</p>



<p>In conclusion, as the world enters a nuclear war, the New York Times is grateful for its readership, and wishes its readers the best during the coming nuclear apocalypse. Good luck everyone.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">365</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia and Iran come Together. Attack in Saudi Arabia a Possibility</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/russia-and-iran-come-together-attack-in-saudi-arabia-a-possibility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Saudi Arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Irani Cabinet came into agreement with Russia, creating a new partnership to respond to alleged Saudi Arabian Attacks. The Israeli cabinet held a successful]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:13px"><strong>The Irani Cabinet came into agreement with Russia, creating a new partnership to respond to alleged Saudi Arabian Attacks.</strong></p>



<p>The Israeli cabinet held a successful meeting with the Russian Cabinet regarding humanitarian aid and nuclear resources . During the discussions after this agreement it was mentioned several times the possible killing or Attack in Saudi Arabian Soil. The King and main oil refineries are among the targets of the Irani cabinet, as well as possible . The following statement was passed by the Cabinet:&nbsp;</p>



<p>To the people of Iran, we as a Cabinet have recently voted unanimously to join the CSTO with the Russian Federation. The Islamic Republic of Iran now considers the Russian Federation a strong nuclear superpower that we call a friend. Russia has recently protected our sovereign nation from a Saudi Arabian attack on our nuclear program. In response to this attack on our nation, the Cabinet of the Islamic Republic of Iran has decided to respond to the Saudi Arabian attack by attacking oil refineries in Saudi Arabia and ports on the Strait of Hormuz. We have also decided as a Cabinet to increase naval presence on the Strait of Hormuz. Any military action that will be taken in the new future are in response to the aggression of the imperialist west.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iran also showed full support to the Chinese government after the attacks in South Korea, and it&#8217;s happy for “non-imperialist”&nbsp; adversity presented to the United States of America. This alliance with Russia could bring more stability to their situation in the Middle East, but it could also mean a more catastrophic war between G5 nations. The BBC will keep you informed of any new updates.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">346</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States backs off in Belarus</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/united-states-backs-off-in-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After reports stating the CIA involvement with the conflict in Belarus and growing international pressure, the United States seems to be pulling back within Belarus.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After reports stating the CIA involvement with the conflict in Belarus and growing international pressure, the United States seems to be pulling back within Belarus. The Russian Federation and the United States were at a nuclear standoff due to the mounting violence in Bealrus yesterday, but overnight the tensions have calmed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The negative international reaction to the United States’ war-mongering tactics and aid has seemed to cause their cold feet” Sukhoi-TMC Ministry Deputy McDonald said.</p>



<p>The mounting conflict in Belarus began when President Alexander Lukashenko was shot by an opposition leader, now believed by some of the ministry to “be working for the Americans&#8221;. The military leader Victor Khrenin became the new President of Belarus due to his high ranking in the government by Lukashenko. The CIA aided in cutting power, networks, and internet service for three hours in order to put Pro-Democracy Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya in power. The United States’ action disregarded the elections by the Belarusean people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vladimir Putin has spoken to the ministry discussing the importance of ensuring peace and safety in Belarus and “keeping the United States and their corruption out”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The ministry will continue working to protect the security and safety of the Belarusean people,” Deputy Alian said. “The blatant imperialism of the Americans should not be tolerated and the sovereignty of other nations should be respected.” </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">344</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OPINION: The corruption of the US Government must be internationally condemned</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/opinion-the-corruption-of-the-us-government-must-be-internationally-condemned/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Defense]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States actions in regime change around the world, most recently in Belarus, should not go unchallenged. The corruption and lack of democracy within]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The United States actions in regime change around the world, most recently in Belarus, should not go unchallenged. The corruption and lack of democracy within the United States has been showcased through the actions of the Department of Defense (DOD) and the CIA and their intrusion into the affairs of Belarus. American imperialism and war-mongering disturbs the peace and safety of citizens and solely promotes the American agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The CIA’s actions resulted in causing a three hour blackout within the capital of Belarus and implementing Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya as President. The people of Belarus began protesting against Sviatlana’s governance and her unethical actions that put her in power. The United State’s actions in aiding the government change show that there is no regard for international law and no importance in recognizing the sovereignty of other countries. Therefore, the United States government and NATO need to pull out of Belarus and face punishment from the international community for their actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What happened in Belarus was a tragedy and it almost led to a new war and threats of a nuclear attack. The international community should join the Russian Federation and President Vladimir Putin in condemning the US government and Biden administration for their mistakes and lack of respect for the people in Belarus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The corruption and lack of knowledge of these attacks by the Biden administration illustrates the failing of the American superpower and their lack of morals. In order to ensure safety and peace in the East and in other nations hurt by the United States, the international community needs to hold the United States accountable for their horrendous actions.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Evidence of CIA involvement in Belarus: report</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/evidence-of-cia-involvement-in-belarus-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 01:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Sukhoi-TCM Ministry has discovered evidence of CIA involvement in Belarus that directly led to the presidency of Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya. The Joint TMC-Sukhoi ministry released]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Sukhoi-TCM Ministry has discovered evidence of CIA involvement in Belarus that directly led to the presidency of Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya. The Joint TMC-Sukhoi ministry released a statement to Russia Today, detailing their reaction and condemning the United States.</p>



<p>“The Joint TMC-Sukhoi taskforce, on behalf of the Russian Federation, would like to condemn the CIA and its affiliates for their manipulation and destabilization of the Belarusian region that has led to countless atrocities. We have well grounded evidence that they have taken these actions. Now is the time for the world to take a definitive stance in order to hold NATO accountable for their unethical actions. For far too long, the United States and their affiliates have undermined the sovereignty of developing and unstable countries and unjustly accused truthful nations of heinous acts. They have caused chaos and destruction. They have toppled governments and taken the lives of innocent bystanders. They have created opportunities for themselves by creating conflicts and disregarding the path of destruction they have left. The Joint TMC-Sukhoi taskforce is taking a stand against the tyranny of the West. We call our fellow nations in the East to stand with us as we condemn these perpetrators of countless meaningless wars.<br>With discontent,<br>Joint TMC-Sukhoi Taskforce of the Russian Federation”</p>



<p>The ministry has been outraged by the CIA involvement but they “are not surprised” according to Deputy McMahan, due to the past actions of American imperialism. The ministry is springing to action bringing forth directives for Putin to call on the U.N. to condemn the United States, calling for Sviatlana’s resignation, greater surveillance to protect against further unethical U.S. involvement, and mobilization of forces to ensure the security and safety of the Russian and Belarusian people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">310</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fingers Off!</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/fingers-off/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Justin Wytmar, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the classic eighties film War Games, the movie ends when a near-sentient computer avoids a global nuclear war when it learns the vital lesson]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the classic eighties film <em>War Games</em>, the movie ends when a near-sentient computer avoids a global nuclear war when it learns the vital lesson that, just like Tic-Tac-Toe, nobody wins in a nuclear war. Unlike Tic-Tac-Toe (where every game ends in a cat&#8217;s game), a thermonuclear war ends with everyone dead (a far bleaker outcome). Nevertheless, Iran and Israel seem to have their fingers on the button.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the New York Times (and other outlets) already reported, an Israeli delegate stated that, &#8220;Our nuclear weapons also will stand at the ready as time continues onward, and God bless us all.&#8221; In an interview, an Iranian ambassador told the New York Times that, &#8220;To the question &#8216;will Iran deploy nukes if invaded?&#8217; I respond with this: &#8216;Would India use its nukes if it was invaded? Would the US? Would Israel?&#8217; Of course. Do not demonize Iran! We have our nukes so that we may never have to use them, you see?&#8221;</p>



<p>It should frighten the world that two nations are this close to detonating nuclear weapons. If Israel launched a preemptive nuclear strike, Iran will no doubt respond, which will no doubt provoke the United States, which will no doubt provoke China and Russia. Alternatively, if Iran launches a nuclear strike, Israel will no doubt respond, which will no doubt provoke Russia and China, which will no doubt provoke the United States. No matter the situation, everyone loses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This precept isn&#8217;t revolutionary, the idea of Mutually Assured Destruction (or M.A.D. for short) originated in the Cold War. But for some reason, global leaders seem anxious to put their finger on the proverbial big, red button. Why is this the case? Maybe the Ayatollah wants to seem like a strong leader for his people, maybe Israel wants to stay vigilant as a tiny nation surrounded by self-proclaimed enemies. Whatever the reason, it&#8217;s time for the Israelis and the Iranians to rematch War Games, or even just listen to some common sense. To the leaders of Iran and Israel, on behalf of the global community, fingers off!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">285</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Lobbying</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/the-importance-of-lobbying/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 23:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=269</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OPINION The election of President Joe Biden in the United States has brought forth the discussion on whether there should be greater regulations on lobbying]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h6>OPINION</h6>



<p>The election of President Joe Biden in the United States has brought forth the discussion on whether there should be greater regulations on lobbying within their Congress. One of Biden’s earliest actions, an executive order aimed at curbing the revolving door between corporations and the government, which came shortly after former President Donald Trump, revoked a similar pledge.</p>



<p>Lobbyists are not happy to see the return of restrictions on their service in the executive branch. In the new administration there is a push to further deplete the role of lobbyists in the government. Furthermore, the radical left in the United States claims that lobbying by big corporations is detrimental to the political process, yet this is not true. Lobbyists’ job is to educate the Congress on matters of national and international significance, on which many of the congresspeople lack knowledge. Without lobbyists, there would be a lack of education and pressure on the Congress to further the needs of the nation and increase economic growth.</p>



<p>Lobbying allows for companies, the average citizen, and other nations to ensure that Congress is educated and able to create the best policy. With Trump gone, Russia should invest in creating a well-oiled foreign lobbying campaign in the United States to improve the relationship between the two.</p>



<p>American foreign policy is very malleable and responsive to foreign lobbying. Nations like Israel, Saudi Arabia, and even the small island country of Bermuda have long realized this reality and set a precedent for Russia to follow. Such countries have invested millions into lobbying machines that advance their interests in the United States, and in doing so, have seen their investments pay off in the form of favorable policies.</p>



<p>There is a correlation between the amount a country spends on lobbying in the United States and the relationship the United States has with that particular country. To increase the benefits in the Russian-American relationship, Russian corporations should work to lobby in the United States and gain support from their government and their people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">269</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian government nationalizes Sukhoi and Tactical Missile Corporation</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/russian-government-nationalizes-sukhoi-and-tactical-missile-corporation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 23:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After the chaos in Belarus at the hand of the United States, Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin announced the formation of a new joint ministry]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After the chaos in Belarus at the hand of the United States, Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin announced the formation of a new joint ministry made up of the Sukhoi and Tactical Missile Corporation. The corporations are now nationalized and are under the direction of Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Deputy of Public Relations released a statement discussing the excitement of both corporations to now be a “part of the [Russian] national economic system”. The statement is as follows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The T.M.C. and J.S.C. Sukhoi is excited to announce that we are now national corporations,” the statement reads. “As national companies, we are now owned by the government. In our case, the Russian Government is part of the national economic system. The Russian Government is now in charge of both companies, with President Putin overseeing this new ministry’s operations. The previous C.E.O.s are now ministers in the Russian Government and all former executives are deputies. We would like to make it explicitly clear that both deputies and ministers will maintain their roles as vice presidents and consultants to the national company. The future of our companies are looking optimistic as there are a multitude of possibilities and improvements to be made.”</p>



<p>In addition, the new nationalized Joint Ministry commented on the growing violence in Bealrus and the United States involvement. In a second press release to Russia Today, the Joint Ministry condemned the U.S. actions and called for the America and NATO forces to withdraw.</p>



<p>“The new national company has learned that there is likely a presence of NATO or American forces stationed in Belarus. It deeply concerns the Russian Government and its people to see such a blatant disregard for Belarusian independence. The Russian Federation condemns all forms of western intervention and demands that American and NATO forces immediately withdraw from the country. Further Western involvement will only continue to destabilize the country and force the Russian Federation to take action. The Russian government will be left no other choice to pursue sanctions should western forces choose to not notify the Russian government of their intention to withdraw from Belarus as soon as possible upon receiving this press release.”</p>



<p>The Ministry is “not afraid to take action” Minister Freeman said to ensure the protection and security of the Russian people.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">261</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are we witnessing Russia’s decline?</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/are-we-witnessing-russias-decline/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexander Calabrese, The Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As Belarus quickly moves towards democracy following the assassination of President Alexander Lukashenko, particular attention has been paid to the response of the Russian Federation…]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As Belarus quickly moves towards democracy following the assassination of President Alexander Lukashenko, particular attention has been paid to the response of the Russian Federation… or lack thereof.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite a tumultuous period following the assassination, which involved protests, bombings, and shootings, the pro-democracy group has rather suddenly declared victory. “Democracy has won,” says newly declared Belarusian President Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya “it is a bright new day for the Belarusian people.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>For years, Belarus has been firmly under the sphere of influence of Russia and its authoritarian President, Vladimir Putin. The new government, however, is democratic and fundamentally opposed to Russia. So far, it appears that Russia has allowed Western companies to waltz right into Minsk and support the newborn Belarusian democracy. Reports suggest that US government organizations are prepared to offer direct support to the new government, if they have not already. Russia is silent. There have even been talks of entering a treaty alliance with the United States or NATO. Russia, for their part, is yet to intervene.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why would Russia allow a Western democracy to spring up in a country merely 451 kilometers away from the city of Moscow? This lack of an active military response is a stark contrast to the former Soviet Union, which built up several layers of puppet buffer states as part of the “Iron Wall&#8221; to protect the Russian homeland. One of the only possible explanations for this lack of action is that we are witnessing the decline of Russia’s power; perhaps, Russia is incapable of maintaining a large sphere of influence, and perhaps it may lose even more influence over Europe to the West and to NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Belarus’ democracy is young and fragile. Should it seek to survive, it will face many challenges in the very near future, but the Russian threat from the near east could prove less fatal than it first appeared.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">234</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia Obtains Sukhoi and Tactical Missiles Corporation</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/russia-obtains-sukhoi-and-tactical-missiles-corporation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A temporary merger between Sukhoi and the Tactical Missiles Corporation has evolved, with the Russian Federation taking control of the two corporations. Sukhoi and TMC]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A temporary merger between Sukhoi and the Tactical Missiles Corporation has evolved, with the Russian Federation taking control of the two corporations. Sukhoi and TMC will now work to execute the will of the Russian government, specifically moving in relation to the ongoing crisis in Belarus. Russian President Vladimir Putin, in a statement to the employees of the two companies, directed executives to take whatever action necessary to remove American presence in Belarus, saying that “anything and everything is on the table.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russian executives presented suspicion that Belarus is making moves towards NATO, with Minister Boris Obnosov stating that the presence of NATO troops in Belarus is “all but certain.” The disruption and crippling of the fragile new Belarusian government was encouraged by Putin, with his suggestions including cyberattacks and the bribery of officials. Putin urged the two companies to avoid military force, but to take any other steps to interfere with the presence of U.S. and other NATO officials within Belarus. At this time, multiple directives are being considered to take action on this front, but no concrete steps have been taken.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">221</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
