<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Quinn Riordan, Russia Today &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/2021/author/qriordan/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 01:37:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>Tony Soprano becomes new CEO of Sukhoi-TMC Task Force</title>
		<link>/2021/tony-soprano-becomes-new-ceo-of-sukhoi-tmc-task-force/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Boeing Company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With former CEO of Tactical Missile Corporation Boris Obnosov appointed the new President of Belarus, the largest shareholder of the corporation, Tony Soprano (Big Tony),]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With former CEO of Tactical Missile Corporation Boris Obnosov appointed the new President of Belarus, the largest shareholder of the corporation, Tony Soprano (Big Tony), was named the new CEO. The Italian mafia gained control of Sukhoi-TMC and now hope for  “the Russians to start becoming Italians” Soprano said. The corporation hopes to restore the glory of the mafia. </p>



<p>“In order to reclaim the Italian heritage, we must end the reign of Domino’s,” Smaller Tony said. The ministry is discussing the response to Boeing’s creation of a lightsaber business.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The new mafia-led ministry hopes to “start a civil war between Domino’s and Papa John’s and turn New Jersey into an empire” Soprano said. The ministry is joining the Boeing Corporation and repeating the mantra “HEY IM WALKING HERE” over and over to “assert their dominance,” Mafia Joe said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">359</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States backs off in Belarus</title>
		<link>/2021/united-states-backs-off-in-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After reports stating the CIA involvement with the conflict in Belarus and growing international pressure, the United States seems to be pulling back within Belarus.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After reports stating the CIA involvement with the conflict in Belarus and growing international pressure, the United States seems to be pulling back within Belarus. The Russian Federation and the United States were at a nuclear standoff due to the mounting violence in Bealrus yesterday, but overnight the tensions have calmed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The negative international reaction to the United States’ war-mongering tactics and aid has seemed to cause their cold feet” Sukhoi-TMC Ministry Deputy McDonald said.</p>



<p>The mounting conflict in Belarus began when President Alexander Lukashenko was shot by an opposition leader, now believed by some of the ministry to “be working for the Americans&#8221;. The military leader Victor Khrenin became the new President of Belarus due to his high ranking in the government by Lukashenko. The CIA aided in cutting power, networks, and internet service for three hours in order to put Pro-Democracy Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya in power. The United States’ action disregarded the elections by the Belarusean people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vladimir Putin has spoken to the ministry discussing the importance of ensuring peace and safety in Belarus and “keeping the United States and their corruption out”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The ministry will continue working to protect the security and safety of the Belarusean people,” Deputy Alian said. “The blatant imperialism of the Americans should not be tolerated and the sovereignty of other nations should be respected.” </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">344</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OPINION: The corruption of the US Government must be internationally condemned</title>
		<link>/2021/opinion-the-corruption-of-the-us-government-must-be-internationally-condemned/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Defense]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States actions in regime change around the world, most recently in Belarus, should not go unchallenged. The corruption and lack of democracy within]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The United States actions in regime change around the world, most recently in Belarus, should not go unchallenged. The corruption and lack of democracy within the United States has been showcased through the actions of the Department of Defense (DOD) and the CIA and their intrusion into the affairs of Belarus. American imperialism and war-mongering disturbs the peace and safety of citizens and solely promotes the American agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The CIA’s actions resulted in causing a three hour blackout within the capital of Belarus and implementing Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya as President. The people of Belarus began protesting against Sviatlana’s governance and her unethical actions that put her in power. The United State’s actions in aiding the government change show that there is no regard for international law and no importance in recognizing the sovereignty of other countries. Therefore, the United States government and NATO need to pull out of Belarus and face punishment from the international community for their actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What happened in Belarus was a tragedy and it almost led to a new war and threats of a nuclear attack. The international community should join the Russian Federation and President Vladimir Putin in condemning the US government and Biden administration for their mistakes and lack of respect for the people in Belarus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The corruption and lack of knowledge of these attacks by the Biden administration illustrates the failing of the American superpower and their lack of morals. In order to ensure safety and peace in the East and in other nations hurt by the United States, the international community needs to hold the United States accountable for their horrendous actions.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Evidence of CIA involvement in Belarus: report</title>
		<link>/2021/evidence-of-cia-involvement-in-belarus-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 01:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Sukhoi-TCM Ministry has discovered evidence of CIA involvement in Belarus that directly led to the presidency of Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya. The Joint TMC-Sukhoi ministry released]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Sukhoi-TCM Ministry has discovered evidence of CIA involvement in Belarus that directly led to the presidency of Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya. The Joint TMC-Sukhoi ministry released a statement to Russia Today, detailing their reaction and condemning the United States.</p>



<p>“The Joint TMC-Sukhoi taskforce, on behalf of the Russian Federation, would like to condemn the CIA and its affiliates for their manipulation and destabilization of the Belarusian region that has led to countless atrocities. We have well grounded evidence that they have taken these actions. Now is the time for the world to take a definitive stance in order to hold NATO accountable for their unethical actions. For far too long, the United States and their affiliates have undermined the sovereignty of developing and unstable countries and unjustly accused truthful nations of heinous acts. They have caused chaos and destruction. They have toppled governments and taken the lives of innocent bystanders. They have created opportunities for themselves by creating conflicts and disregarding the path of destruction they have left. The Joint TMC-Sukhoi taskforce is taking a stand against the tyranny of the West. We call our fellow nations in the East to stand with us as we condemn these perpetrators of countless meaningless wars.<br>With discontent,<br>Joint TMC-Sukhoi Taskforce of the Russian Federation”</p>



<p>The ministry has been outraged by the CIA involvement but they “are not surprised” according to Deputy McMahan, due to the past actions of American imperialism. The ministry is springing to action bringing forth directives for Putin to call on the U.N. to condemn the United States, calling for Sviatlana’s resignation, greater surveillance to protect against further unethical U.S. involvement, and mobilization of forces to ensure the security and safety of the Russian and Belarusian people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">310</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stock declines for US companies due to COVID-19</title>
		<link>/2021/stock-declines-for-us-companies-due-to-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin Corporation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northrop Grumman Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The New York Stock Exchange closed yesterday and the stocks of Lockheed Martin Stock and Northrop Grumman are down about 30 points and they have]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The New York Stock Exchange closed yesterday and the stocks of Lockheed Martin Stock and Northrop Grumman are down about 30 points and they have no revenue left after the economic downturn due the Covid-19 pandemic. However, Sukhoi-TCM has almost ample capital available with about 457 million dollars of cash on hand to develop infrastructure, technology and ensure the security and safety of the Russian Federation and economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The economy has stalled in many parts of the world, with unemployment rising and many companies close to bankruptcy, yet the Russian Sukhoi-TCM is economically strong and planning for a “prosperous future” Deputy Edmonds said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I am proud of the economic prosperity that Russia has,” Edmonds said. “In response to the lack of funds of US companies this shows America’s dwindling lack of influence. This clearly shows how American hegemony has been lost and the world is tired of their over policing and control.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States’ economic recession and failure to maintain the success of their business illustrates the fall of the United States as the global superpower. Vice-Minister Raymond states that the “failed economic status of the United States and its industrial military complex” will allow the growth of Russian companies and power around the world. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CIA and the DOJ plans to meet in a Summit, further intervention in Belarus</title>
		<link>/2021/cia-and-the-doj-plans-to-meet-in-a-summit-further-intervention-in-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:05:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=276</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Joint Ministry Sukhoi-TCM received knowledge of a summit of the CIA and the United States Department of Justice (DOJ) to discuss the current conflict]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Joint Ministry Sukhoi-TCM received knowledge of a summit of the CIA and the United States Department of Justice (DOJ) to discuss the current conflict in Belarus. The CIA and United States have aided in the regime change that resulted in the Presidency of Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya despite her loss in the 2020 election.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ministry believes that the United States’ action within Belarus is “war-mongering” and their plots “of war on sovereign nations should be condemned,” Deputy McDonald said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Americans enrollment in eastern politics is an outrage, quite frankly it&#8217;s hypocritical. They created documents such as the Monroe Doctrine to prevent outside influences in their regimes, yet they impose on eastern world politics&#8221; Deputy Alien said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>An insurrection movement has begun against Tsikhanouskaya for abusing utility and technology and her suppression of technology in Belarus. Tsihanouskaya utilised US aid to cause a three hour blackout of all power and media and put herself in power, and the people of Belarus believe that her actions were unethical and corrupt. The citizens participating in the insurrection are considered “courageous” by the ministry Deputy Edmond said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The ministry is discussing how to advise President Vladimir Putin on the course of action and ensure the protection of Russian citizens and keep peace.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I believe Russia should denonce Belarus and its administration, remove all influences of them, for Russia to hear the people of Belarus, inspire them to revolt, let them choose and create an alliance with Russia,” Deputy Alien said “ its nation’s economic salvation can be the Sukhoi-TCM.”</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">276</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Lobbying</title>
		<link>/2021/the-importance-of-lobbying/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 23:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=269</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OPINION The election of President Joe Biden in the United States has brought forth the discussion on whether there should be greater regulations on lobbying]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h6>OPINION</h6>



<p>The election of President Joe Biden in the United States has brought forth the discussion on whether there should be greater regulations on lobbying within their Congress. One of Biden’s earliest actions, an executive order aimed at curbing the revolving door between corporations and the government, which came shortly after former President Donald Trump, revoked a similar pledge.</p>



<p>Lobbyists are not happy to see the return of restrictions on their service in the executive branch. In the new administration there is a push to further deplete the role of lobbyists in the government. Furthermore, the radical left in the United States claims that lobbying by big corporations is detrimental to the political process, yet this is not true. Lobbyists’ job is to educate the Congress on matters of national and international significance, on which many of the congresspeople lack knowledge. Without lobbyists, there would be a lack of education and pressure on the Congress to further the needs of the nation and increase economic growth.</p>



<p>Lobbying allows for companies, the average citizen, and other nations to ensure that Congress is educated and able to create the best policy. With Trump gone, Russia should invest in creating a well-oiled foreign lobbying campaign in the United States to improve the relationship between the two.</p>



<p>American foreign policy is very malleable and responsive to foreign lobbying. Nations like Israel, Saudi Arabia, and even the small island country of Bermuda have long realized this reality and set a precedent for Russia to follow. Such countries have invested millions into lobbying machines that advance their interests in the United States, and in doing so, have seen their investments pay off in the form of favorable policies.</p>



<p>There is a correlation between the amount a country spends on lobbying in the United States and the relationship the United States has with that particular country. To increase the benefits in the Russian-American relationship, Russian corporations should work to lobby in the United States and gain support from their government and their people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">269</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian government nationalizes Sukhoi and Tactical Missile Corporation</title>
		<link>/2021/russian-government-nationalizes-sukhoi-and-tactical-missile-corporation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 23:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After the chaos in Belarus at the hand of the United States, Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin announced the formation of a new joint ministry]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After the chaos in Belarus at the hand of the United States, Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin announced the formation of a new joint ministry made up of the Sukhoi and Tactical Missile Corporation. The corporations are now nationalized and are under the direction of Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Deputy of Public Relations released a statement discussing the excitement of both corporations to now be a “part of the [Russian] national economic system”. The statement is as follows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The T.M.C. and J.S.C. Sukhoi is excited to announce that we are now national corporations,” the statement reads. “As national companies, we are now owned by the government. In our case, the Russian Government is part of the national economic system. The Russian Government is now in charge of both companies, with President Putin overseeing this new ministry’s operations. The previous C.E.O.s are now ministers in the Russian Government and all former executives are deputies. We would like to make it explicitly clear that both deputies and ministers will maintain their roles as vice presidents and consultants to the national company. The future of our companies are looking optimistic as there are a multitude of possibilities and improvements to be made.”</p>



<p>In addition, the new nationalized Joint Ministry commented on the growing violence in Bealrus and the United States involvement. In a second press release to Russia Today, the Joint Ministry condemned the U.S. actions and called for the America and NATO forces to withdraw.</p>



<p>“The new national company has learned that there is likely a presence of NATO or American forces stationed in Belarus. It deeply concerns the Russian Government and its people to see such a blatant disregard for Belarusian independence. The Russian Federation condemns all forms of western intervention and demands that American and NATO forces immediately withdraw from the country. Further Western involvement will only continue to destabilize the country and force the Russian Federation to take action. The Russian government will be left no other choice to pursue sanctions should western forces choose to not notify the Russian government of their intention to withdraw from Belarus as soon as possible upon receiving this press release.”</p>



<p>The Ministry is “not afraid to take action” Minister Freeman said to ensure the protection and security of the Russian people.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">261</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sukhoi Executives Respond to Anti-Russia Claims</title>
		<link>/2021/sukhoi-executives-respond-to-anti-russia-claims/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While working with the Tactical Missile Corporation (TMC) to protect and ensure security for the Bealrusean people, Sukhoi was accused of “working with the Americans]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>While working with the Tactical Missile Corporation (TMC) to protect and ensure security for the Bealrusean people, Sukhoi was accused of “working with the Americans and being Anti-Russian”, by TMC CEO Boris Obnosov.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The actors who made this claim have not been identified and there has been no evidence found that corroborates this accusation. The Sukhoi Executives wanted to reassure the Russian Federation of their loyalty. The Sukhoi VP of Public Relations released a statement in response.</p>



<p>“In response to the heinous and baseless assertions made, claiming JSC Sukhoi is maintaining an “Anti-Russian” sentiment, the board first and foremost would like to say that we are appalled. The assertion that JSC Sukhoi, a historic and vital portion of Russia’s history, could turn against the motherland is absolutely absurd. Throughout our company&#8217;s history, we have done nothing but aid and support the motherland’s intentions. This statement is obviously an attempt to deface our company’s historic standing as an industry giant. To the group that made this statement, you do not hold any credibility. Your shallow attempt to destroy our companies standing is nothing but a feeble and shameful attempt to taint a respected Russian company. Your claim is baseless yet speaks volumes regarding your intentions. Our company never foresaw the day when we would have to reestablish our allegiance to the very government that created us, yet here we are. да здравствует родина Board of JSC Sukhoi”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sukhoi has seemed to regain and maintain support by the Russian Federation with a new nationalization of their corporation by the Russian government. Sukhoi and the Tactical Missile Corporation have been merged and nationalized by President Vladimir Putin, after the US intervention in Belarus and the mounting conflict.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">211</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OPINION: Why the West needs to stop interfering in other nations’ affairs</title>
		<link>/2021/opinion-why-the-west-needs-to-stop-interfering-in-other-nations-affairs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 20:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As tensions rise in Belarus, with fifteen protesters just shot and killed, with violence increasing, the United States and CIA aid to the opposition is]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As tensions rise in Belarus, with fifteen protesters just shot and killed, with violence increasing, the United States and CIA aid to the opposition is only creating more conflict. At noon, electricity, cell service, and internet service all went out for exactly three hours. As soon as utilities returned, a televised broadcast was beamed to all television in the country. This message consisted of the newly named President Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, who addressed the nation, stating that “Democracy has won”. Directly following, armed security forces have locked down the city and arrested prominent pro-Russia figures.</p>



<p>This is following an election and polls where the legitimate government of Belarus and leader Viktor Khrenin has been supported by the majority of the Belarusean citizens. The Russian government has immediately blamed the United States for the cyber-attack and arrests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“This is a blatant act of American imperialism, and if this can happen in Belarus this can happen anywhere,” President Vladimir Putin said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In reaction to the American intervention, the Tactical Missile Corporation and Sukhoi were merged and nationalized under the Russian Federation to form a new ministry to ensure security and protect the Russian Federation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Belarus is close to an all out war, due to the intervention of the United States. The United States has a history of involvement in regime change, that lead to ousting of the elected and supported governments, and in turn years of war, genocides and conflict. The United States and the West needs to stop interfering with other nations affairs under the ruse of protecting people, Belarusean people identify with the Russian Federation and should not be subject to conflict at the hand of the United States. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">206</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
