<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Arab League &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/2021/category/arab-league/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:12:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>Chaos Erupts Between Iran and the World After Successful Nuclear Bomb Test</title>
		<link>/2021/chaos-erupts-between-iran-and-the-world-after-successful-nuclear-bomb-test/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 23:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arab League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a summit held between Iranian officials and many other international officials, controversy and anger caused the room to explode–similarly to Iran’s nuclear bombs. BREAKING:]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:13px">After a summit held between Iranian officials and many other international officials, controversy and anger caused the room to explode–similarly to Iran’s nuclear bombs.</p>



<p>BREAKING: Iranian warships sighted to be positioned in the Strait of Hormuz blocking traffic, and has led to the dissemination of shocking information–Iran is speculated to be two weeks away from producing a bomb, sending the world into panicked and tense debate following this act of aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Arab League began to discuss rumors of uranium enrichment occurring within Iran, stating that if they were to follow historical events, it was highly likely for this to be happening. Many representatives wanted to wait for complete and concrete evidence before jumping to conclusions or taking actions, and denounced the sightings of warships to simply be a western plot to sow seeds of disinformation and instability. The representative of Kuwait stated, “Yes, there were sightings of Iranian ships around straits blocking traffic. It is NOT confirmed if these ships are troops yet, however. It is a very delicate solution, but many countries see it as an opportunity for Westerners to divide the Middle East and others believe these reports are an Iranian calculated move.” In agreement, the representative of Palestine told the committee to “look at every word that comes out of a westerner’s mouth with a reasonable amount of doubt”.</p>



<p>While these discussions continued, and tensions only rose, news broke out of a successful Iranian nuclear bomb test, leading to the formation of a summit between many of the parties involved–including members of the US cabinet, Saudi Arabian cabinet, Iranian cabinet, and Israeli cabinet. Despite many efforts to keep the press and international community in the dark, reporters were able to enter this summit and get live news coverage. Other parties that were not represented at the summit, such as the Russian Federation, sent someone to speak on behalf of their cabinet. The Minister of Defense told the press that As the Minister of Defense, I have been watching the tensions and movements in the Middle East carefully. Western Aggression makes me fear for the sovereignty of Iran, especially with recent troop movements. I hope that all affiliated countries are willing to work together to find a peaceful solution, and avoid bloodshed.”</p>



<p>Now, the summit that the press attended seemed to contradict this wish for peace entirely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Upon entering the room, the discussion seemed to place a heavy focus on supervision of nuclear programs as to ensure that nuclear weaponry isn’t being created, and that Iran is true to its word on its comments of simply using nuclear power as energy to benefit its people. The Ayatollah of Iran and the Israeli Minister of Infrastructure were engaged in heated debate, trying to push for a negotiation to allow their respective nations the ability to supervise the other’s nuclear programs to ensure stability. The US Secretary of Transportation told the committee that actions taken by previous leadership–the Trump Administration–do not reflect the current opinion of the US cabinet, and they wish to come to a peaceful conclusion of the summit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Soon, things took a turn for the absolute WORST. A member of the summit made a public comment on the presence of the press in the room, causing multiple people to express discontentment and confusion as to why the press was even in the room. To this, the Ayatollah responded: “I invited the press: time and time again, the international community hasn’t allowed true transparency. It’s time for that to happen.” Debate continued as per usual, until a member of the press asked the members of the summit if they were aware of the recent nuclear bomb test perpetrated by Iran. This caused the entire room to fall into chaos and dismay, a large uproar occurring at the Ayatollah’s only response: “The west will finally learn the true power of Iran. Let’s go,” and sudden departure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The press heard several desperate and angered cries, “the Ayatollah is a lying dog!” “The Kingdom of Saudi Arabia will not stand for this!” “The US will seek immediate action!” And the representative of Israel: “We are prepared to enter Iran with our troops, nuclear weapons will stand. God bless us all.”</p>



<p>Nuclear war on the horizon? Fear bubbling up within our committee rooms? Can we ever find peace? The US cabinet left the press with a final, chilling message:&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Operation Ohio, then?”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">253</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will Iran Face Punishment for NPT Violations</title>
		<link>/2021/will-iran-face-punishment-for-npt-violations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 22:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arab League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Security Council and Arab League’s opinions heavily overlap during discussions of possible punishments or actions to be taken against Iran, the idea of sanctions]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:13px">The Security Council and Arab League’s opinions heavily overlap during discussions of possible punishments or actions to be taken against Iran, the idea of sanctions cause heavy controversy.</p>



<p>After exciting and taxing discussion and passage of a paper on the transfer of power after the death of Kim Jong Un, the Security Council transitioned into a new conversation on how to take action against Iran due to violations of the NPT as leaked in previous articles from Fox. Many cabinets and committee rooms have been simply talking about how they must take quick and dutiful action, but the Security Council has been extremely attentive to holding Iran accountable while ensuring the safety of the public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many interesting sentiments were thrown around by representatives, including a heavy focus on either the reinstatement of the JCPOA or the recreation of a similar plan. The Security Council hopes to take note of the downfalls of the JCPOA and change them for the better, and improve upon the parts that worked exemplary until various withdrawals. Another focus has also been placed on whether or not sanctions would be in order, or do more harm than good–a similar conversation to that of the Arab League. Members such as the representative of Germany stated that punishment and sanctions have the ability to be helpful in many cases, but they fear that Iran will not wish to rejoin the JCPOA or join any future plans if sanctions are too overbearing and harm the economy too much–“The delegation of Germany is greatly concerned by Iran’s nuclear activities and thinks it is important that we act immediately. To elaborate, we view the JCPOA played a vital role in suppressing Iran’s nuclear capabilities, and hopes to work with other countries to create a new version of that deal. Germany understands the U.S and Israel&#8217;s conflict with Iran, but our main priority is de-escalating the situation and maintaining peace.”</p>



<p>The Security Council seemed to want to express the prominence of the people in whatever solution that comes forth during committee, many representatives warning against further economic sanctions to avoid plunging the Iranian people into more suffering–almost completely echoing sentiments expressed throughout the Arab League committee, showing that perhaps our world isn’t so divided after all. Ideas for the creation of a new nuclear deal floated around, entailing the support of Iran’s nuclear energy development–yet condemning the development of nuclear weapons, such as “intercontinental ballistic missiles,” as quoted from the representative of South Africa. The bloc working on these ideas told the committee that it was very important to allow Iran a method of redemption through peaceful means, and allowing them to be able to express their viewpoints on the matter as to come to a peaceful solution. The Security Council urges the cabinet of Iran to bring a representative into this committee as to try for peace talks and negotiation, and expresses its discontentment for all efforts to infringe upon Iran’s national sovereignty.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The delegation of Russia’s representatives told the press that “it’s a very delicate situation–we must exercise our power with great restraint to accomplish our mission.” It is of utmost importance and international interest that the world can recognize the major security threat that a new nuclear state can bring.</p>



<p>The Press was able to venture into the Arab League after hearing rumors of propaganda plans, in order to “foster patriotism” within “the new age of the Arab League”. Stay tuned for a further in-depth analysis as information comes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">240</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proposed Propaganda Campaigns &#8211; How the Arab League Plans to Tackle the Iran Crisis</title>
		<link>/2021/proposed-propaganda-campaigns-how-the-arab-league-plans-to-tackle-the-iran-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arab League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Arab League continues discussion of the Iranian crisis, leaking concerning information surrounding possible propaganda campaigns and other Middle Eastern countries developing nuclear weapons–following in]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:12px">The Arab League continues discussion of the Iranian crisis, leaking concerning information surrounding possible propaganda campaigns and other Middle Eastern countries developing nuclear weapons–following in Iran’s dangerous footsteps</p>



<p></p>



<p>The Arab League is up in arms about the extreme power imbalance within the Middle East, verbalizing their worries of economic instability within countries such as Lebanon and Iran! Many representatives are firmly against any plans of foreign–specifically western–involvement due to their “past of manipulation”, and an overall fear of major powers taking advantage of the salient resources found within the Middle East. Countries such as Iraq made their opinions clear that they do not wish to work with the United States, stating that “they are not afraid to bomb us,” and that the only way to stop Iran’s nuclear weapons development plans would be to remove these weapons–which is not a feasible solution, in many eyes. During discussions, representatives began to echo each other&#8217;s ideas and came to a common consensus: one nation should not be able to have total power over the Arab League. Comments from the representative of Libya bring a pressing issue to the table: should all of the members of the Arab League “have the ability to have nuclear [power/weapons]”?</p>



<p>As alluded to in a previous article written by Fox News, we were able to listen in on the discussion when a representative mentioned “the new Arab age”–as the press listened in further, the representative of Libya was happy to privately elaborate, sending a warning to the Iranian government: “The new Arab Ages is here! We must unite as one country fostering the great Arab Ideals. We understand the Iranian threat is large and thus we, the Arab League, have decided to keep a close inspection on the Iranian Nuclear Plan. If they do not meet our standard, we will cut diplomatic ties. With a united Arab League, we will come together as one to promote our corporation together. Conflict and tension will decrease severely and we will come together as a whole!”</p>



<p>Fox News reporters were sadly unable to listen into the entire conversations revolving various plans, but once we entered the room, we were able to hear a representative mention the usage of a possible propaganda campaign. The representative of Libya stated that “even if [they] don’t use propaganda, we need to [show and foster] patriotism&#8230;Many people here are against each other and we need to combine them.” The Arab League seems to be very focused at the moment on uniting in ideology and forming a unified body to fight against conflicts threatening the Arab world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, the mention of propaganda concerned the press–but Fox News is dedicated to avoiding biased information and jumping to conclusions, and reached out to members of the committee to expand on what exactly was meant by this comment. Luckily, we were able to get a few words from the representative of Palestine, who told Fox News that the plan mentioned was “essentially utilizing social media, chat rooms, and messaging boards to disseminate pro-Arab League and pro-Iranian viewpoints. Many citizens of foreign countries view the Arab League as breeding grounds for radicals and terrorists, and do not understand the plight of Arabs or the true state of politics in the Middle East. This plan would try to spread pro-Iranian views, such that both citizens and government figures of foreign nations are sympathetic to Iran, and understand the actions of the Arab League.”</p>



<p>Is this simply a tactic to foster patriotism within the Middle East and Arab community, and ensure that the viewpoints of these groups are heard–or is this a scheme to spread harmful propaganda and rhetoric to allow for Iran and the Middle East to gain support in their nuclear weapons development programs? A hopeful unification project, or an anti-western ploy to advance nuclear power?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fox News is dedicated to continuing listening into these conversations to ensure safety and security. Stay Tuned.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">219</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can The Middle East Work Toward Peace?</title>
		<link>/2021/can-the-middle-east-work-toward-peace/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 18:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arab League]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An in-depth look into the Arab League’s response to Iran’s violation of the Non-Proliferation Treaty and whether or not they will lift sanctions based on]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">An in-depth look into the Arab League’s response to Iran’s violation of the Non-Proliferation Treaty and whether or not they will lift sanctions based on the answer–nuclear war on the horizon?</p>



<p>During its time searching for a broader reach of perspectives on the current Iranian nuclear crisis, Fox News was able to get an inside look into the discussions of the Arab League. After being able to interview members of the Iranian cabinet, Fox News was surprised at the lack of information dissemination that was occurring within the Arab League.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The representative of Iraq from the Arab League asked the committee what acts that Iran was being punished for, “[these] nuclear issues are purely speculation”, and implored for the committee room to lift sanctions on Iran out of concern for its citizens. While the Iranian cabinet very openly discussed its plans for nuclear development and hopes to become a new worldwide nuclear power, the nations represented in the Arab League seemed in the dark on these topics, referring to Iran’s nuclear plans as “merely speculation”, and rumors–despite the Iranian Ayatollah stating that they “will lead Iran into nuclear power”. Fox hopes that this dissemination of new information publicly will help further discussions from committees tackling these dire conflicts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A big topic of interest during the Arab League’s conversation on how it plans to deal with Iran and its violation of the Non-Proliferation Treaty (NPT) was the involvement of western and first-world countries. Representatives of countries such as Palestine and Kuwait voiced concerns about western countries, specifically on how they feared that the United States only wishes to manipulate Middle Eastern countries to their advantage and push the region into further economic instability. However, members of committees such as the representative of Somalia countered these concerns by proposing that the Arab League <em>needed </em>to have “first-world countries involved”, due to the fact that many nations involved within these conflicts simply do not have the money or resources to adequately combat the issues discussed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The representatives of the Arab League also discussed sanctions on Iran, and whether they should increase them, decrease them, or keep them at the exact level that they remain currently. Representatives have made the stances clear–Iraq, Palestine, Libya, and Kuwait are adamantly against sanctions in any way shape or form against Iran, worrying of bringing harm upon the citizens rather than the intended target: the Iranian government. “Many countries in the arab league are [considered] important trading partners with Iran, and we can’t risk economic instability due to a vendetta the US has against them,” the representative of Kuwait said. The debate seemed to reach a common consensus at its conclusion: Sanctions against Iran are far too harmful to the public, and defeat its purpose of punishment toward the government. Despite this, a few representatives, such as the delegate from Libya wish to continue economic sanctions due to violation of the NPT. We hope that this kind of violation does not go unnoticed within this committee</p>



<p>The representative from Palestine left Fox News with a message condemning the actions perpetrated by the United States and western nations, pledging allegiance to Iran during this conflict: “We believe that Iran is being punished with economic sanctions for doing what the United States does on a regular basis. The United States has thousands of nuclear weapons, so many that it could destroy the entirety of the Middle East without suffering a major loss in their nuclear stock. Iran’s response, building a nuclear weapon, is simply the act of a nation desperate for survival in the face of an overwhelming foe. The committee is currently split on how to tackle the Iranian nuclear affair, a majority wishes to side against Iran. However, a smaller minority including myself, Iraq, and Mauritania wish to back Iran against the forces of America and Israel.”</p>



<p>Fox News will remain actively seized in the matter, and will continue to provide up-to-date information based off of incoming debate, and is looking forward to an insider interview with the representative of Lebanon. Stay Tuned.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">155</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tehran Tremors</title>
		<link>/2021/tehran-tremors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Justin Wytmar, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:14:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arab League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=121</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Despite the upcoming Iranian Presidential Election, Iran&#8217;s ministers seem laser-focused on a completely different issue: Nuclearization. In recent weeks, rumors began to circulate about the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Despite the upcoming Iranian Presidential Election, Iran&#8217;s ministers seem laser-focused on a completely different issue: Nuclearization. In recent weeks, rumors began to circulate about the possibility of the Iranians reaching nuclear capabilities. This Friday, those rumors have become reality.</p>



<p>  Ayatollah Ali Khamenei, the supreme leader of Iran, reported the recent beheading of the Iranian Minister of Energy. Wasting no time in appointing a replacement, Ayatollah Khamenei appointed the Minister of Science to take on the role of heading the Ministry of Energy this Friday. Ayatollah Khamenei expressed hopes that the new head of the Energy department would, &#8220;lead Iran to nuclear power.&#8221; </p>



<p>The Iranian government, which has historically been extremely secretive about its nuclear program, is openly discussing plans for nuclearization in governmental meetings. In a session that admitted a New York Times delegate, The Iranian Chief of Staff noted that &#8220;the western media is well aware of our intentions,&#8221; showing that the Iranians fully understand that they&#8217;re nuclear ambitions are no longer a state secret.</p>



<p>Some Iranian delegates seemed incredibly optimistic about their prospects, making bold claims about Iran&#8217;s geopolitical rivals. Iranian Major General Mohammad Bagheri even went so far as to say that &#8220;The U.S. President Joe Biden can be easily manipulated.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>President Biden and his administration seem to have no intention of being duped. Before entering a closed session, The United States cabinet debated the merits of a summit with the Iranians to address the nuclear situation. Many cabinet members were optimistic about the prospects of negotiating with the Iranians, hoping to deescalate the situation through diplomacy. However, some cabinet members, like Secretary of State Anthony Blinken, expressed reservations about the Iranian&#8217;s willingness to meet face to face. In the open session, Secretary Blinken cited Iran&#8217;s historical unwillingness to engage in diplomacy as a reason to seek a better alternative for addressing the situation.</p>



<p>As the Iranian nuclear situation develops, the global media will no doubt be watching Iran, its allies, and its rivals. The next few days will no doubt be headlined by major developments as Iran&#8217;s new Minister of Energy begins to carry out the Supreme Leader&#8217;s wishes, and as the global superpowers prepare to address those developments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">121</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tensions arise in Middle East after Iran allegedly resumes uranium enrichment</title>
		<link>/2021/tensions-arise-in-middle-east-after-iran-allegedly-resumes-uranium-enrichment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 02:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arab League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=88</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The uranium is suspected to be used as a weapons-grade fissile material by mid- to late February, The Arab league confirms.&#160; On Jan. 4, Iran]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>The uranium is suspected to be used as a weapons-grade fissile material by mid- to late February, The Arab league confirms.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>On Jan. 4, Iran announced that they would resume enriching their uranium to 20 percent purity, the most significant acceleration since the 2015 nuclear deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Uranium can be used to create weapons of mass destruction at 90% purity.</p>



<p>The threat of a nuclear breakout in Iran severely affects the security inside the MIddle East as well as on a global scale.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Even though Iran has previously stated their nuclear program is peaceful, the diplomacy between the country and the Arab League has never been more important.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>How did other countries react?</h4>



<p>“It is well known Iran and Oman have always maintained a non-conflict relationship”, said the representative of Oman to the Arab League. “Oman&#8217;s foreign policy has as main goals to have a peaceful relationship with Arab and non-Arab countries&#8221; she stated.</p>



<h4>What was the 2015 agreement?&nbsp;</h4>



<p>In 2015, Iran agreed to a long term nuclear power deal after tension arose because of their intention to pursue nuclear weapons. Even though the country has stated their nuclear research is peaceful, the new unconfirmed leaks have made Iran a subject of global attention.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">88</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
