<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Josie Barnes, The Times (South Africa) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/author/jbarnes/feed/?simply_static_page=1386" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:41:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>China and U.S. Joint Meeting</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/china-and-u-s-joint-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josie Barnes, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 20:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ministries of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a shocking press conference over the discussion of The Directive to Strengthen International Trade between China and the U.S. cabinets, the deal fell through.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After a shocking press conference over the discussion of The Directive to Strengthen International Trade between China and the U.S. cabinets, the deal fell through. This deal was supposed to accomplish many things, including increasing imports from the U.S. by twenty-five percent, replacing twenty-five percent of oil exchange initially from Russia, and handing over that trade to the U.S. The deal was also going to lift the embargo the U.S. had placed on semiconductors.</p>



<p>The U.S. stated, &#8220;We can not entertain a deal with China if they are also going to continue to entertain an oil deal or anything of the like with Russia.&#8221; After learning of the China and Russia conversations, the U.S. could no longer be apart. Then the cabinet stated, &#8220;That is ultimately what we have come to the table to present, and we have been as upfront as possible, and we do not want to negotiate with people we do not trust.&#8221;</p>



<p>China had a comment about this remark and ultimately stated, &#8220;I believe it is disgraceful for a diplomatic country such as the U.S. to pull out of a deal that the People&#8217;s Republic of China has already fulfilled their part of&#8221;.</p>



<p>At the end of the conference, no consensus was made. The Cabinet of the U.S. walked out to their national anthem the star-spangled banner, and the Cabinet of China soon followed. After no deal/signing as of yesterday, we wonder if China and the U.S. will try again and make a deal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>House of Commons Update</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/house-of-commons-update/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josie Barnes, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 01:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The House of Commons is getting loud! Plenty of commotion on the floor. If you pass the Monroe room, you will hear hissing, cheering, talking,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/house-of-commons-chamber-1986-1.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-1209" width="355" height="299" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/house-of-commons-chamber-1986-1.webp 1000w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/house-of-commons-chamber-1986-1-300x253.webp 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/house-of-commons-chamber-1986-1-768x648.webp 768w" sizes="(max-width: 355px) 100vw, 355px" /></figure>



<p>The House of Commons is getting loud! Plenty of commotion on the floor. If you pass the Monroe room, you will hear hissing, cheering, talking, clapping, etc. You will also hear the sound of multiple working papers in progress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With around five working papers on the floor, they hope to address the domestic economic crisis and secure the homeland against external threats. Currently, a significant paper on the floor is the M.A.R.G.A.R.E.T (the act of making additional reforms, gains, and amends to revitalize the economic transformation act). The paper highlights the hopes to bring the parliament together in nonpartisan ways and recognize the need for British people and all included, especially given the ongoing recession and unstable job market. With multiple more papers on the floor, we are excited to see what is to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNEA on energy resources</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/unea-on-energy-resources/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josie Barnes, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 19:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Times (South Africa) had the opportunity to visit the U.N. Environmental Assembly. We choose to ask additional questions after listening to the conversation on]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Times (South Africa) had the opportunity to visit the U.N. Environmental Assembly. We choose to ask additional questions after listening to the conversation on energy, biodiversity, and climate change.</p>



<p><strong>How does your country contribute to renewable energy?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Mexico: “</strong>Mexico aims to make a thirty-two percent reduction in fossil fuel emissions by twenty-thirty. We are committed to ending the use of fossil fuels, even though a large portion of our country still does use them”.</p>



<p><strong>Nepal: “</strong>We don&#8217;t have a lot of renewable energy right now. We are an underdeveloped nation attempting to address that, but we require more funding and resources and hope to eventually contribute”.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Kenya: “</strong>The bulk of the energy used in our nation is renewable. Geothermal, wind, and solar energy account for around eight-one percent”.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Does your country believe renewable energy can replace fossil fuels, and are you working on anything to do that?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Mexico: “</strong>Yes, we do think so. Renewable energy will someday be able to replace all fossil fuels. As a nation, we are now unable to completely eliminate the use of fossil fuels. Due of the lack of resources and the several other issues we are trying to address, it will take time”.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Nepal: “</strong>Yes. We are currently attempting to persuade more developed nations to act more, as they have the means and capacity to do so. We are hoping for a clean future even if it will take time”.</p>



<p><strong>Kenya: “</strong>We are certain that it can. Our nation is currently working to forge alliances that will enable us to extend that transfer. While the transition may take time, once it is complete, economies will be able to grow without the need for fossil fuels or oil”.</p>



<p><strong>What do you hope to accomplish so far in powering the energy transformation?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><strong>Mexico: “</strong>We hope that we can gradually phase out fossil fuels. Because our nation cannot uphold strict restrictions, we do not want to pass resolutions that impose them”.</p>



<p><strong>Nepal: </strong>​​”We expect action from developed nations. We hope that they resolve their problem and make use of their resources to assist other developing nations”.</p>



<p><strong>Kenya:</strong> “We aim to accomplish a goal for the amount of renewable energy it produces annually worldwide. Whatever that goal is, we want to work with other countries and make it happen”.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
