<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ExxonMobil (XOM) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/exxonmobil-xom/feed/?simply_static_page=1205" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>ExxonMobil is making a playlist for Reception Tonight?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/exxonmobil-is-making-a-playlist-for-reception-tonight/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 21:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MTV just listened to ExxonMobil Board of Directors was asked to add some songs to a playlist for our Reception tonight, and boy it&#8217;s a]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>MTV just listened to ExxonMobil Board of Directors was asked to add some songs to a playlist for our Reception tonight, and boy it&#8217;s a good one!  The reason why MTV was invited was that the CEO of ExxonMobil told MTV, “We are all on fire. It is time to turn this ship around.” </p>



<p>Here is the Link to all of the Songs &#8211; <a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/5i110Ukju6zKUmHy7CKrFf?si=EWdn6qcKTU6Fsw5tsTI4IA">https://open.spotify.com/playlist/5i110Ukju6zKUmHy7CKrFf?si=EWdn6qcKTU6Fsw5tsTI4IA</a></p>



<p>The first song brought up was <strong>Eraser by Ed Sheeran.</strong> This song had absolutely no explanation and no significance, it failed 2 to 4. </p>



<p>The next song that was brought up was <strong>Mo Bamba by Sheck West</strong> But, alas, they choose to use the clean one. Their reason was for giggles because it doesn&#8217;t sound like the original. Hence, why it passed Unanimously! </p>



<p>Calling all Swifties! The next song is <strong>You Belong with Me by the Queen of Pop, T-Swift</strong>! This song was suggested by the VP of Corporate Strategic Planning. “The citizens on the tanker belong in our hearts.”</p>



<p>This next song was the biggest Party song (Pun intended) in the 2010s. <strong>Party in the U.S.A by Miley Cyrus. </strong>There was no exact reason why it was mentioned but none the matter. It passed unanimously.</p>



<p>This next song is very controversial, but nonetheless, it was mentioned. The song is <strong>Touch the Sky by Kanye West</strong>. The Board of Directors did a one-for and one-against debate for this song. The Director for this song was the VP of Public and Government Affairs. &#8220;It&#8217;s Musical genius! It’s just one song, it&#8217;s insane!” The director that was against the song was the VP of Corporate Strategic Planning. He said that &#8220;With everything going on with Kayne, do we want our public image to show we support Kayne? With everything against him, this could affect our image. This is your (VP of Public and Government Affairs) job and your reputation on the line.&#8221; Despite the VP of Public and Government Affairs speaking for this song, it failed unanimously. </p>



<p>This next song did the opposite of the Kayne song, it passed unanimously! This song is <strong>Runaway Baby by Bruno Mars</strong>. They also didn&#8217;t give me a reason why but it is a good song though!</p>



<p>The final song that was voted on failed. With 2 votes for and 4 votes against, was the song <strong>Butter by BTS</strong>. Even though they&#8217;re being enlisted into the army, they still are loved in people&#8217;s hearts. The now-former VP of Public and Government Affairs&#8217; explanation was butter equals oil in cooking, and ExxonMobil stands for oil. </p>



<p>The Board is very excited about the reception and can&#8217;t wait for the participants to hear the tunes playlist. If you have any suggestions for songs to add to the list, click the link below to add songs to the potential list!</p>



<p><a href="https://forms.gle/eu9nyhPhXTn4QeBx5">https://forms.gle/eu9nyhPhXTn4QeBx5</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exxon Mobil&#8217;s plan to resolve their detained tanker</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/exxon-mobils-plan-to-resolve-their-detained-tanker/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 08:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With this late-night crisis in full swing. The Exxon Mobile Board of Directors are hard at work creating solutions to get their tanker ship back]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With this late-night crisis in full swing. The Exxon Mobile Board of Directors are hard at work creating solutions to get their tanker ship back into their control. </p>



<p>For some background on the issue, Russia has taken captive one of their tanker ships, filled with precious oil as well as Exxon Employees.</p>



<p>Currently, their main priority is the safety of the hostages and getting their ship back. Some solutions may include but are not limited to. Tracing the ship, since it&#8217;s filled with technology, there got to be a way to trace it! Contact tracing, we did it during the COVID-19 pandemic, how hard could it be? They would just be using the route they have, and see where the ship was when they last had contact with it. </p>



<p>As for the future, they plan on making sure this never happens again. One way to avoid it is to avoid Russian Territories. The only reason why they are in this mess is that they were in Russian territory. </p>



<p>At this moment, their main priority is getting the people taken hostage home safely. Our thoughts and prayers are going to Exxon Mobile. </p>



<p></p>



<p>Good Night and see you all when the sun shines. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exxon Mobile Board of Directors are Alive!</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/exxon-mobile-board-of-directors-are-alive/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 01:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The last committee session for Exxon Mobile was a closed session, but they are now open to the public in the latest session. MTV was]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-audio"><audio controls src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/20230203_190257.mp3"></audio></figure>



<p>The last committee session for Exxon Mobile was a closed session, but they are now open to the public in the latest session. MTV was fortunate enough to talk with Exxon Mobil&#8217;s President, Tom Gibbs, you may listen to the interview above.</p>



<p>Gibbs stated that they are currently working hard on their directives and once they are finished, they will change the world, one step at a time. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>US and Exxon Mobil expanding horizons for competitive yet sustainable energy</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/us-and-exxon-mobil-expanding-horizons-for-competitive-yet-sustainable-energy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Marquez, Der Speigel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 19:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1002</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The US Cabinet recently held a meeting with key Exxon Mobil executives to discuss the details of deal between the two bodies. This deal holds]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The US Cabinet recently held a meeting with key Exxon Mobil executives to discuss the details of deal between the two bodies. This deal holds great promise for a future built on the foundations of affordable and competitive renewable energy sources available to the masses. </p>



<p>In their meeting earlier today, the US cabinet proposed a groundbreaking $1.5 billion in subsidies to be dispersed to the oil giant over the next 5 years. This sum of money will ensure that Exxon has adequate funding to research and develop renewable energy sources and lower the price of oil to be more competitive with foreign nations’ prices. Exxon Mobil has already pledged $500 million of their own to research and develop biofuel, EVs, and carbon captures and plans to review their progress every six months to ensure they are “getting their money’s worth,” according to the company’s press secretary, with a possibility of renewing or increasing funding at the end of the review period. </p>



<p>Everyone involved in the meeting appeared to be quite thrilled to be negotiating a deal with the other party, with the US Secretary of the Treasury proudly remarking “There’s nothing more attractive than oil!” Perhaps another reason for everyone’s joyful demeanors lies in the fact that The US government will be providing subsidies to decrease the price of oil per barrel from approximately $74 per barrel, according to Markets Insider at the time of publication, to below Russia’s cost of $71 per barrel and then slowly decrease to a goal of $65 per barrel over the five-year period. This deal allows Exxon to expand its presence into numerous other European markets, and even China, at a more affordable price than Russian oil which many nations are still forced to purchase over American oil due to its higher price and accomplishes the US’s goal of cutting Russia out of the global economy and lowering the price of oil and gasoline domestically. </p>



<p>This is all great news, for Americans, not so much Russians and their secret allies, however, one member of the US cabinet made it clear that the deal’s emphasis isn’t on sustainability but won’t harm sustainability either, a confusing statement considering where the US government is planning Exxon to employ their subsidies, leaving room to wonder if there will be alternative machinations planned between Exxon and the US government.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>US, Chinese Leaders Conflict on Relationships Between Free Media and Oil </title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/us-chinese-leaders-conflict-on-relationships-between-free-media-and-oil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 19:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 3, the United States Cabinet and the ExxonMobil Board of Directors held an open door meeting to discuss expansion of oil drilling to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On February 3, the United States Cabinet and the ExxonMobil Board of Directors held an open door meeting to discuss expansion of oil drilling to global markets. At the same time, Chinese leaders discussed dealing with their oil crisis caused by the Russo-Ukrainian War. However, the nations’ approaches to dealing with opposition have starkly differed.</p>



<p>An ExxonMobil executive who wished to remain anonymous acknowledged that protests over the private deal may erupt. “We can’t stop protests from happening,” said the executive. “So we need to address the volatility of them by working with their demands.” American secretaries have also discussed how they will address protests. “We do not want to create a monopoly with our deal,” said the CIA Director. “So if protests erupt, we’ll need to address that.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>While Chinese leaders have openly welcomed protests, they have explained mass arrests of protestors. “We have no knowledge of unjust detaining,” said Finance Minister Liu Kun. “The only reason protestors were arrested was for sedition and treason, and we want to speak to the leaders directly.” Culture and Tourism Minister Hu Heping also outlined her concern with free press reporting on the protests. “There is a massive security issue with private press,” she said. “Government owned does not mean unfree.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>ExxonMobil secretaries admitted their frustration with protests nonetheless. “Protestors don’t know what they want from ExxonMobil,” said the anonymous secretary. “We know what we want.” Various Cabinet members discussed how ExxonMobil will expand drilling in untapped markets with a goal of making American markets more competitive than Russian and Chinese markets. The executive further discussed his wishes to achieve what the public desires, a sentiment echoed by executive LD DuCharme. “We want to also invest into biofuels,” she said.</p>



<p>In the meeting between the US government and ExxonMobil, the Treasury Secretary specifically mentioned ExxonMobil’s commitment to sustainability as the reason for working with them. “We need to keep competition up,” said the Secretary. “If Exxon violates our deal or US laws, the deal is over.”</p>



<p>Chinese officials have remained mum on expanding oil drilling amongst mass protests in the country. Finance minister Liu Kun explained his hesitancy on action. “We want to keep our neutrality,” he explained. “So it’s difficult to say where our oil will come from.” However, the United States Treasury Secretary was clear. “Nothing is more valuable to the US than oil,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ExxonMobil to discuss future of fossil fuels</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/exxonmobil-to-discuss-future-of-fossil-fuels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, O Globo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 16:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ExxonMobil finds itself in a position to determine the company&#8217;s post-oil future, and the board is planning to create a renewable energy future, as we]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="300" height="168" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Picture1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-792"/></figure>



<p>ExxonMobil finds itself in a position to determine the company&#8217;s post-oil future, and the board is planning to create a renewable energy future, as we see them on track to do so. ExxonMobli is set to at least talk about ways to create sustainable solutions to meet our societies evolving needs, But have also been seen to doubt the power of consumers. </p>



<p>The president of ExxonMobil is quoted saying that people, “pay a high price.” We see they have goals of being pro net zero, as stated in the ExxonMobil Climate Solutions Plans. </p>



<p>ExxonMobil’s motto is previously stated as, “[being] committed towards providing clean and safe energy for everyone, wherever they live and wherever they need to go.” ExxonMobil is claiming to meet expectations of consumers by decreasing carbon emissions, but also saying that they still want to count on oil and natural gasses in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As gas and oil prices increase, the call for affordable clean energy rises. In a CNBC interview with the CEO of ExxonMobil, Darren Woods, says he fully predicts ExxonMobil will continue to use current energy methods for their company, and will continue to use oil and gas in the future. The ExxonMobil Board is on track to plan the future of ExxonMobil along with their future climate change contributions, which will undoubtedly influence the future of the company in these uncertain times.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
