<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cabinet of the United States of America &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2021/category/cabinet-of-the-united-states-of-america/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:45:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>US-Russia standoff amidst internal scandal</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/us-russia-standoff-amidst-internal-scandal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexander Calabrese, The Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two global superpowers, the United States of America and Russia, may be on the brink of potential military conflict in the small landlocked Eastern European]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Two global superpowers, the United States of America and Russia, may be on the brink of potential military conflict in the small landlocked Eastern European nation of Belarus. Since the assassination of Belarusian dictator Alexander Lukashenko a few days ago, a U.S.-backed democratic opposition government has come to power led by Svetlana Tikhanovskaya, but the state is still very much unstable. Russia has been conspicuously quiet on the matter in recent days but it believed to be preparing for war, albeit much more covertly. The U.S. is believed to be directly supplying the new government, and are also believed to be using modern tactics involving social media and internet memes to influence public opinion amongst the Belarusian people.</p>



<p>Reports early this morning suggest that the Department of Defense has acted in Belarus without the approval of the White House and Commander-in-Chief. A CIA insider reported that “the DOD lied about the presidential approval” which raises serious concerns regarding co-operation within the government. In a CIA memo revealed yesterday, the Agency called the Department of Defense “dysfunctional” and questioned their decision-making. Though the Department of Defense is yet to make any sort of public response to the allegations, sources in the Department described the CIA as “a tough batch”.</p>



<p>Will internal struggles between different institutions in the U.S. government prevent America from coordinating a viable and consistent response to a conflict on NATO’s doorstep? If the trends of recent hours continue, that may well be the case.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">349</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States backs off in Belarus</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/united-states-backs-off-in-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:30:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=344</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After reports stating the CIA involvement with the conflict in Belarus and growing international pressure, the United States seems to be pulling back within Belarus.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After reports stating the CIA involvement with the conflict in Belarus and growing international pressure, the United States seems to be pulling back within Belarus. The Russian Federation and the United States were at a nuclear standoff due to the mounting violence in Bealrus yesterday, but overnight the tensions have calmed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The negative international reaction to the United States’ war-mongering tactics and aid has seemed to cause their cold feet” Sukhoi-TMC Ministry Deputy McDonald said.</p>



<p>The mounting conflict in Belarus began when President Alexander Lukashenko was shot by an opposition leader, now believed by some of the ministry to “be working for the Americans&#8221;. The military leader Victor Khrenin became the new President of Belarus due to his high ranking in the government by Lukashenko. The CIA aided in cutting power, networks, and internet service for three hours in order to put Pro-Democracy Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya in power. The United States’ action disregarded the elections by the Belarusean people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Vladimir Putin has spoken to the ministry discussing the importance of ensuring peace and safety in Belarus and “keeping the United States and their corruption out”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The ministry will continue working to protect the security and safety of the Belarusean people,” Deputy Alian said. “The blatant imperialism of the Americans should not be tolerated and the sovereignty of other nations should be respected.” </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">344</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OPINION: The corruption of the US Government must be internationally condemned</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/opinion-the-corruption-of-the-us-government-must-be-internationally-condemned/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:19:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Defense]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=333</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States actions in regime change around the world, most recently in Belarus, should not go unchallenged. The corruption and lack of democracy within]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The United States actions in regime change around the world, most recently in Belarus, should not go unchallenged. The corruption and lack of democracy within the United States has been showcased through the actions of the Department of Defense (DOD) and the CIA and their intrusion into the affairs of Belarus. American imperialism and war-mongering disturbs the peace and safety of citizens and solely promotes the American agenda.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The CIA’s actions resulted in causing a three hour blackout within the capital of Belarus and implementing Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya as President. The people of Belarus began protesting against Sviatlana’s governance and her unethical actions that put her in power. The United State’s actions in aiding the government change show that there is no regard for international law and no importance in recognizing the sovereignty of other countries. Therefore, the United States government and NATO need to pull out of Belarus and face punishment from the international community for their actions.&nbsp;</p>



<p>What happened in Belarus was a tragedy and it almost led to a new war and threats of a nuclear attack. The international community should join the Russian Federation and President Vladimir Putin in condemning the US government and Biden administration for their mistakes and lack of respect for the people in Belarus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The corruption and lack of knowledge of these attacks by the Biden administration illustrates the failing of the American superpower and their lack of morals. In order to ensure safety and peace in the East and in other nations hurt by the United States, the international community needs to hold the United States accountable for their horrendous actions.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">333</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The US declares war on China. Here is what we know.</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/the-us-declares-war-on-china-here-is-what-we-know/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the last session of the day, members of the United States Cabinet have reportedly declared war to China. Sources confirmed the Feb. 6 attack]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>In the last session of the day, members of the United States Cabinet have reportedly declared war to China.</strong></p>



<p>Sources confirmed the Feb. 6 attack by Chinese forces in South Korean territory, leaving many wounded and severely injured. In a press release sent by the Cabinet of the United States, they clearly stated their discomfort of this attack, as well as condemning the attack on South Korea forces. “This strike characterizes an uncalled for escalation of violence in an already unstable region that is both immoral and irresponsible”, they said.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Later that day, They classified this attack as “A direct attack to our ally South Korea” witch would be followed by these statements regarding the conflict:</p>



<p>A: Declare war on China. They attacked one of the United States&#8217; most important allies.<br>B: Send in aircraft of our own to fire on Chinese soldiers.<br>C: Continue our support in a more covert fashion. We can&#8217;t get ourselves directly involved.<br>D: Choose your own, or a combination of these options.</p>



<p>The new Biden administration has found themselves in two wars already, and the reputation of the United States seems to be going back into violence and war. The BBC will keep covering this topic closely, and report any new updates.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">331</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Israel is like Simba,” from the Disney classic, Lion King</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/israel-is-like-simba-from-the-disney-classic-lion-king/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 02:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Israeli cabinet officials make comical statements comparing the Iranian conflict to the events from a Disney movie during a press conference, Security Council and Arab]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">Israeli cabinet officials make comical statements comparing the Iranian conflict to the events from a Disney movie during a press conference, Security Council and Arab League come to major decisions</p>



<p>The United Nations Security Council has found itself scattered and unsure of which topic it should handle first, while the Iranian conflict and Korean Peninsula Conflict begin to reach a climax of sorts. The committee is pretty evenly split, with representatives from countries such as the United Kingdom and South Africa pushing for a focus on North Korea, commenting on concerns over a civil war with the involvement of nuclear weaponry, similar to the situation being seen on an international scale involving Iran. Other representatives feared the growth of Iranian nuclear weaponry, particularly the representative of Russia expressing their belief to the committee that Iran deserves to have “an olive branch” extended to them, saying that they are acting out of fear of the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The representative of the United States then put their foot down, stating that their stance is firm: providing barriers in the case of an increasing aggression from the likes of Iran is insanely important during this crisis, and the US would be forced to take more severe action if Iran refuses to stop nuclearization efforts.</p>



<p>At this point, the Security Council barred the committee from all press, effectively silencing Fox News and keeping the public in the dark from future proceedings. Luckily, reporters have had the great opportunity to speak with an insider representative who wishes to be kept anonymous. They informed us that the Security Council passed a resolution that entailed the removal of U.N. sanctions and trade embargos–however, “all U.S. sanctions against Iran related to alleged human rights abuses, missiles, and support for terrorism are not affected by the agreement and will remain in place.” On top of this, the Security Council pledges to not interfere with the upcoming Iranian election.</p>



<p>After gaining this information, reporters ventured to listen in on the debate happening in the Arab League, while they also discussed the passing of two working papers on the table. It seems that the room is split into two blocs, one that gives prominence to demolishing western influence, spreading information into Asia that “glorifies Iran and islamic nations” and “demonizes Israel”, and the unification of Arabic states–the other wishing to work alongside the United States and Israel in possible peace negotiations (a possible rejoining of the JCPOA on Iran and the United States’ part), helping Iran continue a civilian nuclear program while condemning the development of nuclear weapons, and limiting the activities of Iranian nuclear activities (bimonthly surprise inspections of nuclear power plants, limiting uranium enrichment, dismantlement of excess centrifuges). The representative of Palestine went as far as to compare Israel to the “creation of the devil”. Anonymous sources leaked that a resolution paper passed, that of the bloc focusing on the dissemination of propaganda and demonizing Israel.</p>



<p>Fox News worries of upcoming updates regarding this plan, and hopes that this does not go unnoticed. The anonymous source also voices their displeasure with the fact that the paper passed “gives money to terrorists in our countries.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, reporters had the great pleasure of being able to attend a press conference held by the Cabinet of Israel, in which they gave the press important messages to share with its allies and Iran. “Israel has tried to negotiate with Iran, Iran has threatened us numerous times. We will not tolerate these threats,” they told us. Members of the cabinet went on to compare the Ayatollah of Iran to the infamous Disney villain, Scar–from the Lion King–and pointed out similarities between the nation of Israel and the character of Simba the lion. This person proceeded to say that they will team up with a respective “Timon and Pumba”, that being the United States and Saudi Arabia, in preparing defenses against Iran if they were to strike first. “Though we hope there will be no war, we are prepared for one. We have exhausted all of our diplomatic solutions, we have a fear that the Iranian government might strike us,” members of the cabinet warned, and told the press that they want to make sure that the Security Council is aware that Israel will see any “progressive moves from Iran” as inciting violence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">317</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Operation Ohio”. Newest US plan regarding Iran&#8217;s nuclear threat</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/operation-ohio-newest-us-plan-regarding-irans-nuclear-threat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is ready to execute after Iran&#8217;s successful nuclear test, Israel and Arabia to be involved again. The Military Plan was supposedly only]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:13px">The United States is ready to execute after Iran&#8217;s successful nuclear test, Israel and Arabia to be involved again.</p>



<p>The Military Plan was supposedly only being used if Iran showed aggression and endangered the principle of world peace. In a summit held by the Cabinet of the United States of America, peace was greatly disturbed by Iran’s nuclear activity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The plan consists of preparing ships from the US 5th Fleet to block Iran from leaving the strait of Hormuz. The ships will remain on standby on Saudi bases near the area, and we currently don’t know the location of the ships at the moment. The United States also made it very clear that “We will be able to beat the Iranian ships easily and prevent them from leaving the straight”, the new leak confirms.</p>



<p>The military will also investigate any safe ways to destroy or disable their nuclear weapons using whatever resources necessary, but would prefer doing it in the same way possible. Air Force will be used until further notice.</p>



<p>Nuclear Forces seem to be available for both Iran and the United States, and we don’t know until what extent they are willing to use this mass destruction armory. Tension has escalated in the Middle East, and a war is more viable now than any other time, and diplomacy seems to be losing this battle. There is still no response from Iran regarding the summit, but&nbsp; The BBC will keep you informed of any news regarding the topic.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">299</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Importance of Lobbying</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/the-importance-of-lobbying/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 23:55:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=269</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OPINION The election of President Joe Biden in the United States has brought forth the discussion on whether there should be greater regulations on lobbying]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h6>OPINION</h6>



<p>The election of President Joe Biden in the United States has brought forth the discussion on whether there should be greater regulations on lobbying within their Congress. One of Biden’s earliest actions, an executive order aimed at curbing the revolving door between corporations and the government, which came shortly after former President Donald Trump, revoked a similar pledge.</p>



<p>Lobbyists are not happy to see the return of restrictions on their service in the executive branch. In the new administration there is a push to further deplete the role of lobbyists in the government. Furthermore, the radical left in the United States claims that lobbying by big corporations is detrimental to the political process, yet this is not true. Lobbyists’ job is to educate the Congress on matters of national and international significance, on which many of the congresspeople lack knowledge. Without lobbyists, there would be a lack of education and pressure on the Congress to further the needs of the nation and increase economic growth.</p>



<p>Lobbying allows for companies, the average citizen, and other nations to ensure that Congress is educated and able to create the best policy. With Trump gone, Russia should invest in creating a well-oiled foreign lobbying campaign in the United States to improve the relationship between the two.</p>



<p>American foreign policy is very malleable and responsive to foreign lobbying. Nations like Israel, Saudi Arabia, and even the small island country of Bermuda have long realized this reality and set a precedent for Russia to follow. Such countries have invested millions into lobbying machines that advance their interests in the United States, and in doing so, have seen their investments pay off in the form of favorable policies.</p>



<p>There is a correlation between the amount a country spends on lobbying in the United States and the relationship the United States has with that particular country. To increase the benefits in the Russian-American relationship, Russian corporations should work to lobby in the United States and gain support from their government and their people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">269</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Why Iran Really Matters</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/why-iran-really-matters/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Justin Wytmar, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 22:15:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=243</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[OPINION Over the past few days, the media has been frantically covering developments in Iran. The product of this media frenzy has been honed into]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h6>OPINION</h6>



<p>Over the past few days, the media has been frantically covering developments in Iran. The product of this media frenzy has been honed into nuclear development, which is undoubtedly important. However, Iran has been on the center of the world stage ever since the days of Alexander the Great, long before the advent of nuclear technology. So why does Iran <em>really </em>matter? What&#8217;s so important about it that has led global superpowers to squabble over it for time immemorial.</p>



<p>There are a few reasons. In modern times, one of the major reasons has been oil. Iranian oil was discovered in 1908, and only a year later, the British had established the Anglo-Persian Oil Company (APOC). By the advent of the first World War, Britain had bought up the majority of shares in the APOC and had effectively nationalized the Iranian Oil Industry. In the early 1950s, the Iranian people democratically elected Mohammad Mossadegh, a socialist who tried to nationalize the oil industry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Americans and British, who benefitted from the oil, forced a coup, replacing the democratically-elected Mossadegh with a brutal, dictatorial regime. The reaction to that dictatorship brought us to the theocratic revolution that led to Iran&#8217;s current government.</p>



<p>But oil, which is almost cliche to mention in an article like this, is not the only reason that Iran matters. Iran sits at the crossroads between Asia and the rest of the Middle East. It has the potential to serve the Chinese and Russians as an avenue into the Arab World. But it could also serve as a Western bulwark, keeping Putin and Xi Jinping from dominating the Middle East.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iran&#8217;s strategic location, in addition to its oil and nuclear capabilities, is the reason that Iran matters. It is the reason that Xi Jinping&#8217;s Belt and Road initiative stretches towards Iran, the reason Russia has been trying so hard to impose a deal with the Iranians, and the reason that the United States has launched &#8220;Operation Porcupine&#8221; to meddle in Iran&#8217;s affairs. So, as you, the careful reader, explore the media landscape in an attempt to contextualize Iran, don&#8217;t forget that Iran&#8217;s global importance only begins at the nuclear arsenal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">243</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Are we witnessing Russia’s decline?</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/are-we-witnessing-russias-decline/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexander Calabrese, The Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:54:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=234</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As Belarus quickly moves towards democracy following the assassination of President Alexander Lukashenko, particular attention has been paid to the response of the Russian Federation…]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As Belarus quickly moves towards democracy following the assassination of President Alexander Lukashenko, particular attention has been paid to the response of the Russian Federation… or lack thereof.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite a tumultuous period following the assassination, which involved protests, bombings, and shootings, the pro-democracy group has rather suddenly declared victory. “Democracy has won,” says newly declared Belarusian President Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya “it is a bright new day for the Belarusian people.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>For years, Belarus has been firmly under the sphere of influence of Russia and its authoritarian President, Vladimir Putin. The new government, however, is democratic and fundamentally opposed to Russia. So far, it appears that Russia has allowed Western companies to waltz right into Minsk and support the newborn Belarusian democracy. Reports suggest that US government organizations are prepared to offer direct support to the new government, if they have not already. Russia is silent. There have even been talks of entering a treaty alliance with the United States or NATO. Russia, for their part, is yet to intervene.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Why would Russia allow a Western democracy to spring up in a country merely 451 kilometers away from the city of Moscow? This lack of an active military response is a stark contrast to the former Soviet Union, which built up several layers of puppet buffer states as part of the “Iron Wall&#8221; to protect the Russian homeland. One of the only possible explanations for this lack of action is that we are witnessing the decline of Russia’s power; perhaps, Russia is incapable of maintaining a large sphere of influence, and perhaps it may lose even more influence over Europe to the West and to NATO.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Belarus’ democracy is young and fragile. Should it seek to survive, it will face many challenges in the very near future, but the Russian threat from the near east could prove less fatal than it first appeared.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">234</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>OPINION: Why the West needs to stop interfering in other nations’ affairs</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/opinion-why-the-west-needs-to-stop-interfering-in-other-nations-affairs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 20:56:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As tensions rise in Belarus, with fifteen protesters just shot and killed, with violence increasing, the United States and CIA aid to the opposition is]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As tensions rise in Belarus, with fifteen protesters just shot and killed, with violence increasing, the United States and CIA aid to the opposition is only creating more conflict. At noon, electricity, cell service, and internet service all went out for exactly three hours. As soon as utilities returned, a televised broadcast was beamed to all television in the country. This message consisted of the newly named President Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, who addressed the nation, stating that “Democracy has won”. Directly following, armed security forces have locked down the city and arrested prominent pro-Russia figures.</p>



<p>This is following an election and polls where the legitimate government of Belarus and leader Viktor Khrenin has been supported by the majority of the Belarusean citizens. The Russian government has immediately blamed the United States for the cyber-attack and arrests.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“This is a blatant act of American imperialism, and if this can happen in Belarus this can happen anywhere,” President Vladimir Putin said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In reaction to the American intervention, the Tactical Missile Corporation and Sukhoi were merged and nationalized under the Russian Federation to form a new ministry to ensure security and protect the Russian Federation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Belarus is close to an all out war, due to the intervention of the United States. The United States has a history of involvement in regime change, that lead to ousting of the elected and supported governments, and in turn years of war, genocides and conflict. The United States and the West needs to stop interfering with other nations affairs under the ruse of protecting people, Belarusean people identify with the Russian Federation and should not be subject to conflict at the hand of the United States. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">206</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
