<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/council-of-ministers-of-the-russian-federation/feed/?simply_static_page=1196" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:22:30 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. cabinet finds success in meeting with Russia</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/u-s-cabinet-finds-success-in-meeting-with-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juliana Gunvalsen, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1692</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shortly after 3 p.m., the U.S. concluded discussions with the Russian cabinet in order to secure the ship carrying oil to China as well as]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Shortly after 3 p.m., the U.S. concluded discussions with the Russian cabinet in order to secure the ship carrying oil to China as well as the American nationals. </p>



<p>In terms of exchanges, the U.S. negotiation involved swapping two Russian nationals for every American national returned safely to the United States. While this was discussed as potentially being an unfair exchange, the cabinet assures the press that this will foster relations between both nations, as well as China. This swap also comes after the Biden administration initiated a prisoner swap with American W.N.B.A. player Brittney Griner and Russian Arms Dealer Vadim Krasikov, which was met with both ridicule and celebration within American borders. </p>



<p>In terms of the ship carrying oil, the cabinet ensured that it will be completing its trip to China as quickly as possible. Furthermore, the CIA Director shared that the Turkish Intelligence Agency will be investigating the contents on the ship to ensure the integrity of the delivery. This will continue previous relationships between the U.S. and Turkey, especially with having Turkey as a mediator. </p>



<p>The United States&#8217; cabinet emphasized the importance of keeping lines of communication open throughout all recovery efforts. Their priorities throughout negotians were the safety of all nationals as well as Ukrainian citizens as well as gaining control of the ship. When asked if this will give an upperhand to the U.S. delegation, it was clear that this does give the United States a certain edege. This leverage would especially become relevant if the United States were to intervene in the war in Ukraine. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A house divided</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/a-house-divided/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hongtao Hu, The Sun]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 07:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of Iraq (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran-Iraq War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Sun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the Iran-Iraq war continuing for over a year, Iran, Iraq, and Russia are divided &#8212; not only against each other, but among themselves. However,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="819" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-1024x819.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-1359" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-1024x819.jpeg 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-300x240.jpeg 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-768x615.jpeg 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D.jpeg 1431w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>With the Iran-Iraq war continuing for over a year, Iran, Iraq, and Russia are divided &#8212; not only against each other, but among themselves.</p>



<p>However, one faction has joined forces: the USSR and Iraq.</p>



<p>While notorious for secrecy, The Sun has received an anonymous report about a meeting between the USSR and Iraq, where a member of the USSR cabinet was reportedly heard saying to Iraq: “our house is your house.” </p>



<p>However, the USSR is burdened with the loss of a member of its cabinet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this meeting, the USSR stated that the recently deceased Finance Minister of the USSR was discovered to be colluding with members of the Iranian cabinet.</p>



<p>Could the USSR have “disappeared” the Minister of Finance for political purposes? Is the USSR providing nuclear resources to Iraq? Only time will tell.</p>



<p>In other news, Iraq is experiencing internal turmoil along its southern border, incited by Ayatollah Khomeini’s words: “to our brothers in Iraq especially, I turn to you now. You know in your hearts that the mongrel demon-spawn of the greater Satan Saddam Hussein will never care for you…now it is time for you to be freed of your oppressor in accordance with the wishes of the Muslim people, and the true Sharia!”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Such words have invoked the “righteous” fervor of Iraqi citizens and have led to several civilian arrests in Iraq.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In response, the Ambassador to the United Nations for Iraq offered a “sneak peek” of a future directive to The Sun, hinting at creating literacy programs and actions to reduce hunger in the population.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Iran, after discovering the news of a collaboration between the deceased Finance Minister of the USSR and a member of their cabinet, accusations went flying about a possible “traitor” in their midst.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With the Iran-Iraq war in the midst of its first year, both sides of the conflict are experiencing similar troubles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia expels journalists as Ukrainians killed</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/russia-expels-journalists-as-ukrainians-killed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 02:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Russian Federation has refused to open the door to journalists who attempt to report on their politics, with the president personally intimidating journalists who]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Russian Federation has refused to open the door to journalists who attempt to report on their politics, with the president personally intimidating journalists who challenge his politics. When Moscow Times reporters attempted to enter what was an Open Meeting, they were immediately arrested and threatened by the guards.</p>



<p>Some of the reporters attempted to challenge the president. “I am the President,” he responded back. “I do what I want.”</p>



<p>The Russian President specifically cited the Moscow Times’ stance against the Russian invasion of Ukraine, an action the president repeatedly referred to as a “righteous cause.” However, more than 7,000 civilians have been killed in the war in Ukraine, all while Russia’s GDP has decreased by 0.5 percent.</p>



<p>Freedoms for journalists and the media have greatly diminished according to watchdog group Freedom House, while 12 journalists have been killed in Ukraine since the start of the war. Furthermore, Russian actions have been financially assisted by a variety of companies and countries.</p>



<p>ExxonMobil has spent up to 16 billion dollars on Russia since 2005, and left about 4 billion dollars in assets when they pulled back in 2022. When questioned about their assistance in Russia’s war, ExxonMobil’s Board of Directors were unable to provide clear responses. “Check the 10K,” said the President. “I don’t know the complete answer.”</p>



<p>ExxonMobil has aimed to uphold national and international law. President of Technology and Engineering LD DuCharme stated that “we are mainly focused on sustainability.” However, many executives also joked about the lack of consequences for violating the U.S. deal. “When you’re rich, you don’t lose time,” said the ExxonMobil President. “You lose money instead.”</p>



<p>Additionally, according to the US Treasury Secretary, China had made an offer to Russia to undercut the US-ExxonMobil deal at a cheaper rate. Chinese officials admitted the offer, but said that they had not entertained the deal. “We have no plans to further negotiate with Russia,” said the Chinese Finance Minister.</p>



<p>However, China still sends billions of dollars to Russia. “We have always been cooperating with them,” said the Finance Minister. “Nothing is new.”</p>



<p>However, Russia’s war has been bolstered by continuous funding. As one of the Moscow Times evicted journalists stated, “they pay for war, and receive its profits to shut down the press.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia violates nuclear arms treaty</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/russia-violates-nuclear-arms-treaty/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dia Murali, Buenos Aires Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:46:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=834</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The see-saw dynamic of Russia and Ukraine continues to teeter back and forth, gradually increasing speed until the violent rocking becomes a constant concern. One]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The see-saw dynamic of Russia and Ukraine continues to teeter back and forth, gradually increasing speed until the violent rocking becomes a constant concern. One of the most turbulent factors is the threat of nuclear attack from Russia’s front. </p>



<p>Russian President Vladimir Putin has consistently admitted to Russia’s willingness to utilize such significant weaponry if deemed necessary. This looming threat has begun to draw closer with new conflicts arising within the realm of arms control.</p>



<p><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="377" height="251" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/HRnic5-ulKy6gKoSo8YWTDljhw90xig_2AonpOTJ9lgtfCHpAU_MB1vgpQHbgMZxg0vcjdAudK4rcGoReI3CXt0N1iDZHJrZqCM8cRDyK0qW5YwyRnmXi072YiMA3_8ZsGIV-R1YPWxHkPMlT2Ml31g"></p>



<p>Trust between nations is incredibly crucial in times of high tension. The Strategic Arms Reduction Treaty II (START II) establishes a nation’s obligation to consent to inspection by foreign authorities.  Despite having agreed to the treaty, Russia refuses to comply with regulations and is actively prohibiting U.S. officials from conducting inspections on Russian nuclear weaponry. The significance of this rebuff has not gone unnoticed by the global community. Communication between these countries in regards to an issue so volatile is essential in order to avoid further escalation and conflict. </p>



<p>“[the United States] is committed to ensuring the safety and security of our allied countries and citizens,&#8221; the White House press secretary said. &#8220;Our dedication to maintaining peace on our globe requires us to verify that foreign states are complying with the international standards of arms control.”</p>



<p>The potential for nuclear catastrophe becomes increasingly serious as the Russia/Ukraine conflict continues to grow. With the violation of the START treaty, the almost 6,000 nuclear warheads that Russia possesses become a huge liability. To restore peace of mind to all, U.S. officials are pushing for Russia to simply comply with foreign inspection activities.</p>



<p>“[Russia’s] nuclear power serves as a very necessary deterrent to those that may wish us ill, Russia&#8217;s FSB director said. &#8220;The safety and future of our country depends on our strength; we will continue to defend our priorities and assets as necessary.” </p>



<p>The futures of the U.S. and Russia are not the only ones threatened by this conflict. The future of global arms control could be seriously affected. The disregard that has been displayed for the START implies that this treaty could be endangered in the future. As the only current regulation in relation to the arsenals of the U.S. and Russia, the conflict regarding the START must be quickly terminated to prevent further nuclear proliferation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where should Ukrainian refugees go?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/where-should-ukrainian-refugees-go/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mira Polyakov, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=816</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The wave of migrants and refugees has persisted due to the crisis between Russia and Ukraine, and the upheaval of food insecurity in Africa. The]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The wave of migrants and refugees has persisted due to the crisis between Russia and Ukraine, and the upheaval of food insecurity in Africa.  The international community will discuss the question: where should they go? The refugee crisis in Europe began in late February 2022, when the majority of 8 million refugees fled Ukraine to Poland. As this war continues, residents in both Russia and Ukraine will be forced to migrate globally for security. Each country has an obligation to provide asylum for someone escaping persecution, with concern for their economy and safety.</p>



<p>The African Union promotes their notion of an “integrated, prosperous and peaceful Africa, driven by its citizens and representing a dynamic force in the global arena,” where immigrants and refugees purpose this intent. However, Africa’s DRC and Congo face the struggle of food insecurity impacting a third of the country&#8217;s population, and creating a surge of internally displaced persons or IDPs. Luckily, the African countries of Gabon and Ghana open their arms to those who struggle and welcome many IDPs.</p>



<p>“For migration, we believe that it is necessary for a country to grow, however, safety is always in consideration,” said the representative of Ghana to the African Union.</p>



<p>Acceptance of migrants, refugees, and IDPs will support a growing population benefiting the country’s economy and GDP, they said.</p>



<p>With this in mind, the safety of the people is kept in consideration, as these immigrants bring new insight to the country. </p>



<p>“When it comes to the issue of immigration and asylum seekers, Gabon&#8217;s initial approach has always been to find the means to accommodate refugees while still ensuring the safety and security of official residents,” the representative from Gabon said.</p>



<p>Importance of understanding who is entering the country and for what reasons assures the safety<br>and security of the people living in it. As for the IDPs and refugees eluding hunger and war, they intend to improve their way of life. Every human being is entitled to a safe environment to live a secure lifestyle, and with the acceptance from countries for migrants, refugees, and IDPs, this lifestyle will be achieved.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
