<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Present Day &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/present-day/feed/?simply_static_page=1312" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:43:11 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. cabinet finds success in meeting with Russia</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/u-s-cabinet-finds-success-in-meeting-with-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juliana Gunvalsen, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1692</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shortly after 3 p.m., the U.S. concluded discussions with the Russian cabinet in order to secure the ship carrying oil to China as well as]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Shortly after 3 p.m., the U.S. concluded discussions with the Russian cabinet in order to secure the ship carrying oil to China as well as the American nationals. </p>



<p>In terms of exchanges, the U.S. negotiation involved swapping two Russian nationals for every American national returned safely to the United States. While this was discussed as potentially being an unfair exchange, the cabinet assures the press that this will foster relations between both nations, as well as China. This swap also comes after the Biden administration initiated a prisoner swap with American W.N.B.A. player Brittney Griner and Russian Arms Dealer Vadim Krasikov, which was met with both ridicule and celebration within American borders. </p>



<p>In terms of the ship carrying oil, the cabinet ensured that it will be completing its trip to China as quickly as possible. Furthermore, the CIA Director shared that the Turkish Intelligence Agency will be investigating the contents on the ship to ensure the integrity of the delivery. This will continue previous relationships between the U.S. and Turkey, especially with having Turkey as a mediator. </p>



<p>The United States&#8217; cabinet emphasized the importance of keeping lines of communication open throughout all recovery efforts. Their priorities throughout negotians were the safety of all nationals as well as Ukrainian citizens as well as gaining control of the ship. When asked if this will give an upperhand to the U.S. delegation, it was clear that this does give the United States a certain edege. This leverage would especially become relevant if the United States were to intervene in the war in Ukraine. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese finance minister announces plan to become sole Taiwanese ruler</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/chinese-finance-minister-announces-plan-to-become-sole-taiwanese-ruler/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ministries of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The People’s Republic of China’s finance minister laid out his plans to become the sole ruler of Taiwan in an exclusive interview with the Moscow]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The People’s Republic of China’s finance minister laid out his plans to become the sole ruler of Taiwan in an exclusive interview with the Moscow Times. The Minister explained his goals and his desire for the Taiwanese people.</p>



<p>Claiming that Taiwan was rightfully Chinese land, the minister explained why he felt the obligation to want the island. </p>



<p>“The citizens of Taiwan want a minister who is in accordance with the people,” he said. “I am that person.” </p>



<p>The Chinese finance minister also reiterated that he is the only person he believes the Taiwanese people want ruling over them. </p>



<p>“I have experience as a finance minister, and I know how money runs a country,” he explained. He also elaborated that China taking over Taiwan would complete China’s adherence to the one country, two systems policy.</p>



<p>The minister of finance remained mum on how he would implement his plans to take over the island. “I haven’t decided on anything specific,” he said, in regard to how he would invade the island. “But when the time is right, Taiwan joining us will be inevitable.”</p>



<p>He also laid out the Communist system that he would impose in Taiwan. “The Taiwanese people do not want a democracy,” he stated. “They want a system of government similar to what rules mainland China.” According to a recent poll conducted through Taipei’s National Chengchi University, only 6.5 percent of Taiwanese citizens support reunification and rule under the People’s Republic of China.</p>



<p>“I want to see Taiwan under new management,” the finance minister explained. When asked how he would deal with potential opposition from current Taiwanese citizens, he was blunt. “We need reeducation rather than suppression of the press,” he said. “The only way the world will learn to understand our Communist government is if we re-educate them through increased media and literature.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corrections to Moscow Times-Al Jazeera Articles</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/corrections-to-moscow-times-al-jazeera-articles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Al Jazeera Editorial Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Moscow Times would like to sincerely apologize for errors in the press that have been reported in two recent articles about Al Jazeera. Firstly,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Moscow Times would like to sincerely apologize for errors in the press that have been reported in two recent articles about Al Jazeera. Firstly, the Moscow Times incorrectly transcribed a quote from the Minister of Technology calling upon a “hostage takeover.” In reality, the Minister of Technology called upon a “hostile takeover.” Additionally, in the opinion piece, “No objective news will come out of Al Jazeera until it cuts off Qatar,” the Minister of Technology’s assertion was repeated more accurately but he was misidentified as the Minister of Transportation. The Minister of Technology made the statement. The Moscow Times would also like to clarify a comment about the journalistic standards, this was made in regard to a working paper where the Balkans Director was questioning how to improve journalistic standards, and should not be taken to mean that Al Jazeera currently has none. That said, the Moscow Times stands by all other assertions made in both articles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNEA looks ahead to climate resiliency</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/unea-looks-ahead-to-climate-resiliency/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juliana Gunvalsen, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 21:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Having finished their first topic, the UNEA is well underway with their next concern in debate: empowering climate resilience. Yesterday, the RRECO bloc was one]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Having finished their first topic, the UNEA is well underway with their next concern in debate: empowering climate resilience. Yesterday, the RRECO bloc was one of the three papers voted on, though it did not pass.</p>



<p>“I think that our paper RRECO was realistic and people could not handle that fact,&#8221; a representative from the bloc stated. &#8220;There was a certain piece of western bias… We just thought it was logical to have big developed countries and a few small countries so we really wanted to express the stress in the realistic portion.”</p>



<p>Despite these events, many of the same countries resumed their work together this morning in order to tackle the new issues at hand. Countries such as Mauritania, Venezuela, Syria, China, Iran, and Russia. </p>



<p>Collectively they “came together to start working on this one solution really because we knew that our countries get along, have similar policies, and things that definitely affect each other.” Syria stated, “For instance, droughts can really cause floods, that can be the main contributor, and Syria suffers from droughts. We feel like at this point we are probably the farthest along bloc, it&#8217;s the most comprehensive paper.”</p>



<p>Other delegates, such as Indonesia and Uruguay, were simply glad to see a display of diplomacy in the cabinet. Indonesia feels that “it was absolutely wonderful that this paper got passed and got passed unilaterally in various countries who had various different interests. I initially came out on the opposition but when I saw the paper and examined it more closely I realized we shared a common goal, so I ended up supporting it very strongly.”</p>



<p>Uruguay, a sponsor on the Net Green paper that was passed, shared a similar sentiment. The delegate said, “I&#8217;m just really happy I could be apart of the sponsors for this amazing paper. It was really really fun just to work out these differences between countries, talking to different blocs trying to make it so we can get our paper passed and it&#8217;s just amazing to see the world take a step in the right direction. It&#8217;s the first time I&#8217;ve ever seen this many countries come together to do something and not say something, but objectively do something.”</p>



<p>The committee is working relentlessly to solve the current issues and anticipates the presentation of working papers at some point during today’s session.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>No objective news will come out of Al Jazeera until it cuts off Qatar</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/no-objective-news-will-come-out-of-al-jazeera-until-it-cuts-off-qatar/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 16:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Al Jazeera Editorial Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the minutes after the Qatari minister of transportation threatened to cut off Al Jazeera and hold its journalists accountable, the network began discussing new]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the minutes after the Qatari minister of transportation threatened to cut off Al Jazeera and hold its journalists accountable, the network began discussing new plans to please the Qatari government. In the SLAY working paper, Al Jazeera discussed plans to change their coverage and portray Qatar in a more positive light.</p>



<p>One of the clauses in the paper involves Al Jazeera hiring an economist from the greater Middle East to speak about why Qatar is an ideal nation to move to because of its strong resources. They also hope to create a project to tell stories and traditions from Qatar to ensure its history is portrayed in the best light possible.</p>



<p>All after the government threatened to fire the Board of Directors and hold them hostage.</p>



<p>The editorial opinion of the Moscow Times is that when dictatorships begin threatening the well-being of journalists, the journalists’ lives take precedence over adherence to the truth. Al Jazeera has implemented some workarounds to ensure journalistic integrity, such as company-wide surveys to identify points of reform in stories, such as impartiality and bias. However, these workarounds are anonymous and could easily be manipulated by the Qatari government. Furthermore, describing investment opportunities in Qatar may enrich the government to further suppress the views of journalists.</p>



<p>In another working paper, titled “We Address Takeover Evacuation” (We ATE), Al Jazeera has laid out plans to leave the country in case the government attempts to falsely imprison or harm the journalists. However, the Moscow Times believes that this must be the action taken if Qatar’s money continues to suppress the voice of journalists. Censorship naturally degrades reporting; the Balkans Director even questioned, “have we defined journalistic standards for hiring?” If Al Jazeera hopes to maintain serious coverage and be considered a voice of the Arab World, it must have the courage to leave Qatar and establish its own independence as a network.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Biden&#8217;s cabinet contradictions</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/bidens-cabinet-contradictions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Molly Robson, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 16:03:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1475</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Yesterday, an impromptu press conference was held by the U.S. Cabinet in which the press had many questions for Biden and his administration. Biden described]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-17.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1496" width="418" height="474"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">President Biden speaks at a press conference yesterday afternoon</figcaption></figure>



<p>Yesterday, an impromptu press conference was held by the U.S. Cabinet in which the press had many questions for Biden and his administration. </p>



<p>Biden described yesterday&#8217;s events as a &#8220;farce&#8221;, expressing his disappointment with both the other cabinets and his own. However, perhaps the real disappointment should be levied on Biden, as his ability to veer off-topic was incredibly apparent in his answers to the press. </p>



<p>When asked about the Ukrainian power plant, President Biden strangely said, &#8220;why do we give plants so much power?&#8221;, a question that is neither relevant nor useful. This comes in direct contradiction to the president&#8217;s hard stance against Russia, making Fox News wonder: which president does Biden want to be? The one who goes on irrelevant tangents? Or the one who takes a stand against the enemy?</p>



<p>When asked about Russia, Biden stated &#8220;we [the cabinet] refuse to communicate with Russia&#8221;. While this is a valiant effort to ice out the opposing force, a halt on Russian-U.S. communication could do more harm than good. </p>



<p>Though the treasury secretary stated that the U.S. &#8220;cannot risk American lives&#8221;, those lives may be at risk simply because Biden&#8217;s government refuses to communicate with the Russians. Why would the administration not try its hand at diplomacy? </p>



<p>Putin&#8217;s war has raged for nearly a year, causing a flood of Ukrainian refugees to other countries, including the United States. The Biden administration cannot continue to flip and flop between openness and isolation, it needs to make a choice. If this indecision continues, when and how will Russia react?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Qatari technology minister threatens to hold Al Jazeera members hostage</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/qatari-technology-minister-threatens-to-hold-al-jazeera-members-hostage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 15:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Al Jazeera Editorial Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1487</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After Al Jazeera’s recent actions to create a TikTok network and expand their news scope, the Qatari government still expressed its anger with the network’s]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After Al Jazeera’s recent actions to create a TikTok network and expand their news scope, the Qatari government still expressed its anger with the network’s progress. The government specifically cited “flailing international reporting” as the cause of its ire.</p>



<p>&nbsp;“We had high hopes for the nascent network, and were determined to share many opinions,” said the Minister of Technology. “But by the recent callousness of reporting, we will have no choice but to hold Al Jazeera journalists hostage.”</p>



<p>Al Jazeera’s journalists believe that the Qatari government’s anger is veiled criticism of the network’s opinions. “We embrace journalism and journalistic ethics,” said the Mubasher Director. “So when the government threatens us, it means they’re imposing their opinions over the truth we report.”</p>



<p>Other Al Jazeera Board of Directors members addressed a need to appease the Qatari government. </p>



<p>“We need the funding from the government,” said the Balkans Director. “It’s not ideal, but we may have to appease the Qatari government in order to survive.” </p>



<p>However, the Balkans Director clarified that he does not want to take orders directly from Qatar.  “We still need to focus on internal efforts, and report on issues where we’re independent, but still reporting on issues Qatar wants us to report on,” he said.</p>



<p>However, Al Jazeera’s journalists have affirmed that their top priority is currently maintaining journalistic integrity, and hope to report even if they are held hostage or are evicted from Qatar. “The government may seize our property at any time,” said the Mubasher Director. “So we need to make sure we can safely be evacuated.”</p>



<p>The Mubasher Director pleaded for international support to help the journalists against the Qatari government, whose Energy Minister recently advocated a “forgive and forget” attitude towards Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. “The world needs to know where Qatar is putting their resources,” the Mubasher Director said. </p>



<p>The Arabic Director expanded on this. “We need international aid to make sure we can wean off government support and maintain our independence,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sustainability! What are it’s goals?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/sustainability-what-are-its-goals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mira Polyakov, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 15:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After making a visit to the UNEA, Iran, Tunisia, and India introduced their resolution about a more sustainable world. Green economies make a green world]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After making a visit to the UNEA, Iran, Tunisia, and India introduced their resolution about a more sustainable world. Green economies make a green world right? These economies can provide a low-carbon, resource-efficient, and socially inclusive economy preventing the loss of biodiversity and ecosystem services. </p>



<p>Soon a switch will be made, superseding the irreplaceable non-renewable resources, to more valuable renewable resources. Renewable sources may include wind and solar power, biomass, and bioenergy which would strongly promote sustainability.  Following those, everything hydro comes into play, with hydro-energy, and hydro-thermal energy. But questions remain such as what body of water they plan to use, and what areas are deep enough underground?</p>



<p>With nuclear power our economy can be pushed 3 steps forward, the disposal of nuclear waste, the expansion of the power, and intense research for nuclear facilities all can help rid the atmosphere of harmful byproducts emitted by fossil fuels and significantly contribute to both the economic and environmental dimensions of sustainability. </p>



<p>The world is in good hands, let&#8217;s just hope this is not too good to be true.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exxon Mobil&#8217;s plan to resolve their detained tanker</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/exxon-mobils-plan-to-resolve-their-detained-tanker/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 08:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With this late-night crisis in full swing. The Exxon Mobile Board of Directors are hard at work creating solutions to get their tanker ship back]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With this late-night crisis in full swing. The Exxon Mobile Board of Directors are hard at work creating solutions to get their tanker ship back into their control. </p>



<p>For some background on the issue, Russia has taken captive one of their tanker ships, filled with precious oil as well as Exxon Employees.</p>



<p>Currently, their main priority is the safety of the hostages and getting their ship back. Some solutions may include but are not limited to. Tracing the ship, since it&#8217;s filled with technology, there got to be a way to trace it! Contact tracing, we did it during the COVID-19 pandemic, how hard could it be? They would just be using the route they have, and see where the ship was when they last had contact with it. </p>



<p>As for the future, they plan on making sure this never happens again. One way to avoid it is to avoid Russian Territories. The only reason why they are in this mess is that they were in Russian territory. </p>



<p>At this moment, their main priority is getting the people taken hostage home safely. Our thoughts and prayers are going to Exxon Mobile. </p>



<p></p>



<p>Good Night and see you all when the sun shines. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Janes aim social media campaign to grow movement</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/janes-aim-social-media-campaign-to-grow-movement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 03:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Janes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Janes, a nonprofit group that aims to promote equitable access to abortion, have been organizing a social media campaign to protect women’s right to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Janes, a nonprofit group that aims to promote equitable access to abortion, have been organizing a social media campaign to protect women’s right to choose. Citing concerns over repression of reproductive rights in an era where abortion is not protected federally, the Janes have been working to make sure that right is given.</p>



<p>The founder of the Janes explained her concerns with the government’s lack of progress in expanding abortion access. “The U.S. has failed to protect women’s rights,” she said. “That’s why we’re doing all that we can to protect abortion access.”</p>



<p>The organization is beginning with establishing social media accounts and leading assemblies and community events. “We’d like to use any form of social media,” said the Founder. “TikTok, Instagram, maybe even LinkedIn to recruit nurses and gynecologists.”</p>



<p>TikTok in particular has elicited support amongst Janes. Because Gen Z is statistically the most active cohort on TikTok, many of the leaders believe raising awareness on the platform will educate teens. “As an adult, I’ve spent 13 hours on TikTok sometimes,” said co-founder Kendra Winter. “So if we make videos targeted at kids, we’ll be able to reach them efficiently.”</p>



<p>For the founder, expanding access to abortion through social media is not a pipe dream, it is an integral part of American democracy. “The best way to reform democracy is to work within it,” she said. “Through social media, we can encourage citizens to vote and take action to make sure their rights are protected.”</p>



<p>The Janes have also explored connecting with local press and other organizations to raise awareness of abortion rights. </p>



<p>“While we aim to use social media to build a national platform, we want to stay local to Chicago on the ground for now,” the founder explained. The Director of Community Relations also cited Gen Z for Change as a potential organization to collaborate with.</p>



<p>The Janes chair admits her lofty goals, stating that “it’s going to be hard to organize a benefit concert or get Taylor Swift to speak out.” However, the group, which currently has under 100 volunteers and workers but over 20,000 followers, aims to grow on social media even more. “We can use hashtags like #WeAreJane,” said the director of communications. “That way, we’ll expand our reach to women nationwide.</p>



<p>The founder is confident that using social media will maintain American democratic values. “The government is doing what it can,” she said. “But if we use social media to build a movement, we’ll actually be a bigger part of the government and expand the people’s will.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
