<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Alejandro Moreno, BBC News &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/2021/author/amoreno/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 01:37:55 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>BREAKING NEWS: Iran Leaked Nuke Plan</title>
		<link>/2021/breaking-news-iran-leaked-nuke-plan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:46:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=351</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Have a covid party at Fox News headquarters Breathes really hard on Vladimir Putin in the hopes that he will get COVID Nukes the US]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p></p>



<ol><li>Have a covid party at Fox News headquarters</li><li>Breathes really hard on Vladimir Putin in the hopes that he will get COVID</li><li>Nukes the US<ol><li>Florida, specifically the super bowl</li><li>The Capitol</li><li>The White House</li></ol></li><li>Nukes the BBC Headquarters</li><li>Nukes China</li><li>Nukes Russia (!!!!) for:<ol><li>Being spiteful</li><li>Being petty</li><li>Engaging in fan behavior tbh!</li></ol></li><li>Procures snacks for the Iranian Cabinet;</li><li>Uploads the Ayatollah’s consciousness to a computer so he may reign forever from the cyberworld;</li><li>Puts the honorable Ayatollahs face on the nukes&lt;3;</li><li>&nbsp;Nukes literally anywhere in Korea that will help #girlboss Kim Yo Jung</li><li>Nukes 4512 Johnson Avenue &#8212; for personal reasons;&nbsp;</li><li>Nukes the moon &#8212; which is a known imperial force;<ol><li>Inspired by the dreams of Gru&lt;3 from Despicable Me</li></ol></li><li>Nuke the homes of Kim Kardashian and Logan Paul</li><li>Enslave Charli D’Amelio &#8211; To be utilized as a defense mechanism in the Strait of Hormuz</li><li>Sets up a shrine for the Ayatollah&lt;3 at all of the aforementioned nuke sites</li><li>Jail anyone who is an Aries (they toxic) (except Fox News and the Ayatollah)<ol><li>Unless they’re a pisces or libra ;(</li></ol></li><li>Stream all four seasons of rick and morty</li></ol>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">351</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia and Iran come Together. Attack in Saudi Arabia a Possibility</title>
		<link>/2021/russia-and-iran-come-together-attack-in-saudi-arabia-a-possibility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Saudi Arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Irani Cabinet came into agreement with Russia, creating a new partnership to respond to alleged Saudi Arabian Attacks. The Israeli cabinet held a successful]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:13px"><strong>The Irani Cabinet came into agreement with Russia, creating a new partnership to respond to alleged Saudi Arabian Attacks.</strong></p>



<p>The Israeli cabinet held a successful meeting with the Russian Cabinet regarding humanitarian aid and nuclear resources . During the discussions after this agreement it was mentioned several times the possible killing or Attack in Saudi Arabian Soil. The King and main oil refineries are among the targets of the Irani cabinet, as well as possible . The following statement was passed by the Cabinet:&nbsp;</p>



<p>To the people of Iran, we as a Cabinet have recently voted unanimously to join the CSTO with the Russian Federation. The Islamic Republic of Iran now considers the Russian Federation a strong nuclear superpower that we call a friend. Russia has recently protected our sovereign nation from a Saudi Arabian attack on our nuclear program. In response to this attack on our nation, the Cabinet of the Islamic Republic of Iran has decided to respond to the Saudi Arabian attack by attacking oil refineries in Saudi Arabia and ports on the Strait of Hormuz. We have also decided as a Cabinet to increase naval presence on the Strait of Hormuz. Any military action that will be taken in the new future are in response to the aggression of the imperialist west.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iran also showed full support to the Chinese government after the attacks in South Korea, and it&#8217;s happy for “non-imperialist”&nbsp; adversity presented to the United States of America. This alliance with Russia could bring more stability to their situation in the Middle East, but it could also mean a more catastrophic war between G5 nations. The BBC will keep you informed of any new updates.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">346</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The US declares war on China. Here is what we know.</title>
		<link>/2021/the-us-declares-war-on-china-here-is-what-we-know/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the last session of the day, members of the United States Cabinet have reportedly declared war to China. Sources confirmed the Feb. 6 attack]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>In the last session of the day, members of the United States Cabinet have reportedly declared war to China.</strong></p>



<p>Sources confirmed the Feb. 6 attack by Chinese forces in South Korean territory, leaving many wounded and severely injured. In a press release sent by the Cabinet of the United States, they clearly stated their discomfort of this attack, as well as condemning the attack on South Korea forces. “This strike characterizes an uncalled for escalation of violence in an already unstable region that is both immoral and irresponsible”, they said.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Later that day, They classified this attack as “A direct attack to our ally South Korea” witch would be followed by these statements regarding the conflict:</p>



<p>A: Declare war on China. They attacked one of the United States&#8217; most important allies.<br>B: Send in aircraft of our own to fire on Chinese soldiers.<br>C: Continue our support in a more covert fashion. We can&#8217;t get ourselves directly involved.<br>D: Choose your own, or a combination of these options.</p>



<p>The new Biden administration has found themselves in two wars already, and the reputation of the United States seems to be going back into violence and war. The BBC will keep covering this topic closely, and report any new updates.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">331</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Operation Ohio”. Newest US plan regarding Iran&#8217;s nuclear threat</title>
		<link>/2021/operation-ohio-newest-us-plan-regarding-irans-nuclear-threat/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:52:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States is ready to execute after Iran&#8217;s successful nuclear test, Israel and Arabia to be involved again. The Military Plan was supposedly only]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:13px">The United States is ready to execute after Iran&#8217;s successful nuclear test, Israel and Arabia to be involved again.</p>



<p>The Military Plan was supposedly only being used if Iran showed aggression and endangered the principle of world peace. In a summit held by the Cabinet of the United States of America, peace was greatly disturbed by Iran’s nuclear activity.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The plan consists of preparing ships from the US 5th Fleet to block Iran from leaving the strait of Hormuz. The ships will remain on standby on Saudi bases near the area, and we currently don’t know the location of the ships at the moment. The United States also made it very clear that “We will be able to beat the Iranian ships easily and prevent them from leaving the straight”, the new leak confirms.</p>



<p>The military will also investigate any safe ways to destroy or disable their nuclear weapons using whatever resources necessary, but would prefer doing it in the same way possible. Air Force will be used until further notice.</p>



<p>Nuclear Forces seem to be available for both Iran and the United States, and we don’t know until what extent they are willing to use this mass destruction armory. Tension has escalated in the Middle East, and a war is more viable now than any other time, and diplomacy seems to be losing this battle. There is still no response from Iran regarding the summit, but&nbsp; The BBC will keep you informed of any news regarding the topic.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">299</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran taking strong precautions regarding possible international militarization on Iranian soil</title>
		<link>/2021/iran-taking-strong-precautions-regarding-possible-international-militarization-on-iranian-soil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:25:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=214</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Iranian Armed Forces, the Islamic Revolutionary Guards, and any cyber operations resources will be utilized in case of attack in Iranian soil, new leak]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>The Iranian Armed Forces, the Islamic Revolutionary Guards, and any cyber operations resources will be utilized in case of attack in Iranian soil, new leak confirms</strong></p>



<p>Iran is not holding back on the preparation of a possible military encounter with foreign countries. New anonymous leaks reveal that Iran is secretly arming the Iranian Military in case of an impending attack. They are also reaching out with various international spies to learn about how well other countries are armed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Iranian are also continuing to divert resources and funds directed towards the Iranian nuclear weapon program and other nuclear production systems, sources say. The islamic Revolutionary Guard Corps is yet to be deployed across the nation to place explosives that can be remotely detonated only in case of an invasion. It is very clear that the Irani government is taking all the precautions possible in case of another Middle East war.</p>



<p>China has also been linked as a possible military backup to Iranian forces. Iran will utilize the 2016 China Agreement in order to request military assistance and stability, COVID-19 aid, and humanitarian aid and relief funds. The chinese will also have a 25% discount on all Iranian oil exports, imports and international tariffs.</p>



<p>The rapid increase in militarization is what&#8217;s keeping the tension in the Middle East escalating at a fast pace. There is still no evidence of the Iranian Cabinet&#8217;s possible peaceful approach regarding the nuclearization process in their nation. BBC News will be working with the topic closely, as we still wait for updates on how this conflict develops. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">214</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Operation Porcupine”. Secret military operations in Iran to be taking place by the US government.</title>
		<link>/2021/operation-porcupine-secret-military-operations-in-iran-to-be-taking-place-by-the-us-government/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 20:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Department of Defense]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=200</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New leaked information from the U.S cabinet confirms that their actions regarding Iran’s recent nuclear program goes far beyond diplomacy and support. The cabinet of]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>New leaked information from the U.S cabinet confirms that their actions regarding Iran’s recent nuclear program goes far beyond diplomacy and support.</strong></p>



<p>The cabinet of the United States of America is planning on taking strong military action if needed in the Middle East regarding Iran’s nuclearization. In a classified directive written on February 5, 2021, the Cabinet clearly states that they will be prioritizing intelligence operations conducted by the Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), in order to keep constant surveillance on the Irani suspected nuclear sites. This operation has been named “Operation Porcupine”, and is being conducted in cooperation with Israel and Saudi Arabia.</p>



<p>The United States also stated that they will be ready in case of conflict, announcing that the Chairman of the Joint Chiefs of Staff will be coordinating with top generals in secret on creating possible plans of attack. The Joint Chiefs of Staff will also coordinate with regional commanders to ensure that American troops are ready in case of conflict. Some of the discussed actions were; to increase training frequency, testing for missile system effectiveness, requesting reports from generals on the United States’ capability to defend against nuclear attacks, and to work with local militaries to increase cooperation.</p>



<p>Israel and Saudi Arabia have also&nbsp; been alerted of the current situation, and were asked through a series of letters to not engage in any military action regarding the situation in Iran yet. Allies all over the world have also been warned of possible aggressions and actions by the Irani cabinet, and to be ready against any situation.</p>



<p>The United States of America is also prioritizing peaceful talks with Iran through a summit, wanting to remain as transparent and pacific with news media chanis around the world. In case of this not working, the world should be prepared for military action and violence. President Biden and the new administration&#8217;s approach to conflict like this is still in doubt, but the possibility of a new Middle East war is increasing every minute.  BBC News will be following the topic very closely throughout the next couple of days.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">200</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran to Move Forward with Nuclear Weaponry Project</title>
		<link>/2021/iran-to-move-forward-with-nuclear-weaponry-project/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:30:06 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=141</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[New leaks confirm that Iran will continue to work and develop their nuclear research sources.&#160; The Iranian Cabinet is discussing the economic and social damage]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>New leaks confirm that Iran will continue to work and develop their nuclear research sources.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The Iranian Cabinet is discussing the economic and social damage that immoral and imperialist international sanctions have caused to the Iranian people.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Iranian government also stated that &#8220;Iran seeks to further its military cooperation with Russia, specifically by joining CSTO &#8212; the defense pact which Russia administers.&nbsp; Such a move would be mutually beneficial to our two states.&nbsp; Because of Russia&#8217;s nuclear arsenal and the fact of Mutually Assured Destruction (MAD)”.</p>



<p>There is still no response from either the United States nor Israel regarding the topic and how they are planning on moving forward.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Meanwhile The Arab League has shown divided opinions on Iran´s possible nuclear threat. Even though there is still no new information regarding Iran continuing their nuclear program, there are certain questions regarding first world countries as well as western countries involvement in the situation.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iraq and Palestine are among a few delegations which consider that Israel and western involvement is the real security and nuclear threat to the Middle East&nbsp; “Iran’s possible nuclear threat needs to be followed closely, but we can’t move forward until we are 100% sure”, they said. Other nations have been strongly suggesting the involvement of&nbsp; first world countries to protect Arab Nations from Iran&#8217;s nuclear threats. The committee has also been discussing possible Economic Sanctions to Iran, something that Iraq strongly disagrees with.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The BBC will keep a close coverage on what these nations have to say about the topic.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">141</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tensions arise in Middle East after Iran allegedly resumes uranium enrichment</title>
		<link>/2021/tensions-arise-in-middle-east-after-iran-allegedly-resumes-uranium-enrichment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 02:49:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arab League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=88</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The uranium is suspected to be used as a weapons-grade fissile material by mid- to late February, The Arab league confirms.&#160; On Jan. 4, Iran]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>The uranium is suspected to be used as a weapons-grade fissile material by mid- to late February, The Arab league confirms.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>On Jan. 4, Iran announced that they would resume enriching their uranium to 20 percent purity, the most significant acceleration since the 2015 nuclear deal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Uranium can be used to create weapons of mass destruction at 90% purity.</p>



<p>The threat of a nuclear breakout in Iran severely affects the security inside the MIddle East as well as on a global scale.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Even though Iran has previously stated their nuclear program is peaceful, the diplomacy between the country and the Arab League has never been more important.&nbsp;</p>



<h4>How did other countries react?</h4>



<p>“It is well known Iran and Oman have always maintained a non-conflict relationship”, said the representative of Oman to the Arab League. “Oman&#8217;s foreign policy has as main goals to have a peaceful relationship with Arab and non-Arab countries&#8221; she stated.</p>



<h4>What was the 2015 agreement?&nbsp;</h4>



<p>In 2015, Iran agreed to a long term nuclear power deal after tension arose because of their intention to pursue nuclear weapons. Even though the country has stated their nuclear research is peaceful, the new unconfirmed leaks have made Iran a subject of global attention.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">88</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
