<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 05:58:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>UN will not allocate military or humanitarian resources to India</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/13/un-will-not-allocate-military-or-humanitarian-resources-to-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 04:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=648</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amidst the unbelievable drama surrounding the Sino-Indian conflict, everyone is left wondering what will happen next. Following a visit to the United Nations Security Council,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Amidst the unbelievable drama surrounding the Sino-Indian conflict, everyone is left wondering what will happen next. Following a visit to the United Nations Security Council, a vote among all members resulted in only one representative voting to give military resources to India while all 10 others voted no. Consequentially, a nearly unanimous vote to send humanitarian aid to India has been vetoed by the Republic of China, resulting in the U.N. not reserving any resources to the Indian Council. </p>



<p>The Republic of China, independent from the People&#8217;s Republic of China and which does not have U.N. representation, accepted an interview where they shared some important information about how the cabinet has been acting on the issue. Both nations China and India continue to be shocked by each other&#8217;s actions with their militaries and hatred towards both sides is building up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The U.S. Senate: Senator William Proxmire Sepaks on Behalf of the Senate</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/10/the-u-s-senate-senator-william-proxmire-sepaks-on-behalf-of-the-senate-ready-for-edit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 16:04:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the most recent press conference, Sen. Proxmire represented the U.S. Senate and started with his condolences for the loss of Eleanor Roosevelt. He continued]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the most recent press conference, Sen. Proxmire represented the U.S. Senate and started with his condolences for the loss of Eleanor Roosevelt. He continued to express that as they dealt with the Cuban Missile Crisis, they felt that it was important to discuss the civil rights issue within the nation, specifically women’s rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>In an interview with Senator Proxmire, he stated many things not only on behalf of himself, but speaking overall for the U.S. Senate.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The Cuban missile crisis has impacted many and caused chaos, and the U.S. Senate reassures their unity and doing “not only what is in our best interest, but in the best interest of the American people.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Senate attempted solutions to help de-escalate the situation in Cuba, and at the same time protect the U.S. and its public as a whole, ensuring the safety of all Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the topic of the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women, Sen. Proxmire said, “we understand women’s rights and civil rights are an issue that requires prioritization, and they are the most important thing to the Senate. Currently, we are working on solutions to try and implement more education, as well as other social reforms which are in the process.” </p>



<p><strong>“As a senator that wants every American to know the truth, I wish all of you to know that we are trying to do the best for all American people, and I acknowledge the discontent with us, but rest assured we are using our power to ensure the happiness and great state of the U.S.A.”</strong></p>



<p>Overall not only as a senator, but a representative of our government, Sen. Proxmire and the rest of the U.S. Senate want the American people to rest assured knowing they are working on solutions to help with women’s rights, civil rights, and the overall safety of the nation, which will further unveil as debates and bills continue to develop. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PCSW Appeals to US Cabinet and Senate in Interest of Advocating for Women</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/pcsw-appeals-to-us-cabinet-and-senate-in-interest-of-advocating-for-women/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Swadha Garnaik, BBC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 23:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the aftermath of the intense discussions with the U.S. Senate and Cabinet, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) convened to reflect]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the aftermath of the intense discussions with the U.S. Senate and Cabinet, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) convened to reflect on the progress made and the challenges ahead. The post-Senate meeting interview with Jessica Weis and Dr. Henry David shed light on the Senate&#8217;s acknowledgment of their concerns, particularly regarding Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson&#8217;s letter. Weis added her perspective, saying, &#8220;The questions that they posed were very good. And I&#8217;m very happy that they mentioned that they passed a bill that brought up women and protections for them.&#8221; Despite the challenges, there seems to be a newfound dialogue between the PCSW and the Senate, hinting at the possibility of improved collaboration. The committee members expressed satisfaction with the Senate&#8217;s responsiveness and hoped for improved communication on resolutions and bills.</p>



<p>Following the cabinet meeting, Marguerite Rawalt and Honorable John Macy, Jr. highlighted the positive strides made in addressing issues related to women&#8217;s roles in the military and workforce. They emphasized the importance of promoting women&#8217;s contributions, especially in times of crisis such as the Cuban Missile Crisis. The committee members remained professional, advocating for women&#8217;s relevance to national security without succumbing to individual anger.</p>



<p>However, the committee&#8217;s optimism was tempered by a press conference where U.S. Cabinet representative John McCone claimed that the status of women was a low priority amid the pressing matters facing the government. The official asserted, &#8220;As we have a lot going right now, the status of women is at a low priority at the moment.&#8221; This disappointing declaration underscored the uphill battle the PCSW faces in securing recognition for women&#8217;s issues in the current political climate. The committee questions how America could be a powerhouse if women were marginalized and thus immobilized. This blow marks the second occasion where the U.S. government seemingly disregarded the PCSW.</p>



<p>The Presidential Committee on the Status of Women has released a press statement in response to the blatant disrespect of the Cabinet. &#8220;The Presidential Commission on the Status of Women condemns the actions of the US Cabinet and the statement made by the Director of the CIA. Director John McCone outwardly expressed the Cabinet’s disinterest in the rights of American women. During a press conference with the PCSW and US Senate, McCone stated that on the list of their priorities, our directives were very low. These directives detailed plans for empowering women in regards to the current state of our nation given the Cuban Missile Crisis. The PCSW would like to express their disappointment in our US Cabinet for not giving their support for half of the US population.&#8221;</p>



<p>The PCSW remains determined to uphold Eleanor Roosevelt&#8217;s legacy, urging the government to recognize and prioritize the contributions of women to the nation&#8217;s well-being.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LATEST FROM THE POST: Southern Democratic Senators Double Down on Their Stance and Address the Nation</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/latest-from-the-post-southern-democratic-senators-double-down-on-their-stance-and-address-the-nation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=659</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an exclusive interview with the Washington Post, Democratic Senator Olin D. Johnston and his colleauges wished to provide us with a message for the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In an exclusive interview with the Washington Post, Democratic Senator Olin D. Johnston and his colleauges wished to provide us with a message for the nation. The address reads as follows: </p>



<p>&#8220;Today I, Senator Olin D. Johnston, stand before members of the Press to address a very important matter. John Locke contended that if the government the people created in the state of nature violated the rights of the citizens and the set laws of the land, the right of revolution would entitle the people to use force to punish that government and depose its rulers. Today, In light of the drastic motions and efforts of the United States Federal Government related to the infringement of state’s rights, it is time that YOU, the people take initiative today, putting the power back in your hands.&nbsp;In accordance with the Second Southern Manifesto, and the Federal Government’s complete disregard of the statements within that document, the people must adhere to those same words of John Locke and impose the &#8216;right of revolution&#8217;. Align yourselves, and make your voices heard by marching to THE CAPITOL. If the United States Government isn’t willing to listen to the representatives of the people, let them hear from the people themselves. “</p>



<p>The colleagues supporting this address are senators Allen J. Ellender, Richard Russell Jr., Harry F. Byrd, Robert Byrd, and Herman Talmadge</p>



<p>The implications of this incitement of revolt are yet to be seen, and the Washington Post advises all Americans to stay alert as the situation develops.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. cabinet: cry for action</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/u-s-cabinet-cry-for-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=651</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for pressuring China with the situation in Taiwan, and the proposal of possible sanctions which the UNSC is open to was discussed. </p>



<p>The U.S. cabinet currently already has ships in Japan for a diplomatic presence in the region, moving forward with sanctions they feel will be the most effective way Additionally, they feel that these harder sanctions will pressure China about their wrongdoings and have more international pressure about correcting their wrongs. </p>



<p>The representative from the UNSC had advised that there is a firm reason for these sanctions on China, and that the body does whatever they can in significance with their cause, supporting Taiwan. </p>



<p>Later on, in the press conference, the United States cabinet, madam Press Secretary had explained that the United States was shocked by China’s reaction to the call for a revote. The U.S. has time and time again reached out to the PRC yet has received no response, but the PRC was reported to barge into the U.S. cabinet&#8217;s closed session when it was “most convenient for them.” China’s sudden aggression within Taiwan now gives the U.S. reason to believe that there is heavy Chinese involvement, as their own social media platform, Tencent has also been explicitly spreading disinformation that directly influenced the results of the election. </p>



<p>The cabinet has also called upon the UNSC to help with the current issues within Taiwan, specifically the corruption seen within the election and the democracy impeded from within it. Additionally, they have coordinated asking for how the UNSC will choose to move forward with China’s actions as the U.S. government specifically will no longer be contacting the Chinese government due to the “disrespect of sanctity diplomacy.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>An intercepted source has also let us know that China is threatening the U.S. and threatening to get rid of some things that are unknown in regard to the U.S. The U.S. economy also is thriving and has no further need for China. </p>



<p>Furthermore, in an interview with UN Ambassador Linda Thomas Greenfield, “The U.S. is trying their best in order to help Taiwan as the United States has empathy for all and they are heavily focused on the economy to help our citizens. Alongside this, we are arranging a meeting with the U.S. delegation from the Security Council as their input is valuable.”</p>



<p>The response from the UNSC is still being awaited and more developments will continue as debate on the next steps to be taken continue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PRESS CONFERENCE: United States is Shocked China&#8217;s Actions</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/press-conference-united-states-is-shocked-chinas-actions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between the two countries. The U.S. representative has sensed some aggression from China, also shown through how they have allowed themselves to come into meetings with no prior conversation. </p>



<p>The United States has further commentary on the fact that China has said they do not want forgiven involvement at the moment because of any possible influence on their election. Yet, the United States mentioned how the Chinese app, Tencent,  is spreading misinformation and has directly influenced China’s election. Showing that even with no current foreign relations, there are still direct influences on their election via the country’s social media app. Was it really worth it to cut connections with other countries that have not had an influence when you country has had an influence first? </p>



<p>Due to the previous actions that China has taken, the United States feels that China is rejecting any possible diplomatic offers. Furthermore, the U.S. has called upon the United Nations Security Council to help deal with these issues in China and even Taiwan as it is going to be needed to keep international peace between countries. After coordinating with the U.S. Security Council representative, the U.S. is urging the most powerful peacekeeping body in the world to help to deal with China’s actions as quickly and as effectively as possible. Now, the United States will no longer be in contact with the China government because of all the previously mentioned issues and that they have disrespected diplomacy. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Missile crisis brings positive changes for women in war-related industries</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/missile-crisis-brings-positive-changes-for-women-in-war-related-industries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Though the unfortunate crisis involving the U.S. and USSR in Cuba has raised tensions and concerns of war, there are also many American domestic concerns]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Though the unfortunate crisis involving the U.S. and USSR in Cuba has raised tensions and concerns of war, there are also many American domestic concerns that could be revolutionary in women&#8217;s rights. The war effort is supported by women which is reflected by the growing number of women in the workplace aiding in war efforts. Not only does this benefit the factory industry and war production, but also boosts the domestic economy, advancing and building the nation. As for opportunities for women, the current crisis has been evidenced in women&#8217;s abilities and aspirations. </p>



<p>The press representative for the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women commented saying, &#8220;Additionally, our commission has been working towards creating legislative reforms that focus on educational opportunities&#8230;to ensure that these women are starting off with the right skill set.&#8221; </p>



<p>Women will have opportunities to be business owners and entrepreneurs unlike ever before. This crisis has brought on the guarantee of women in the workplace and to have equal freedoms.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X is Getting Sued? What Will Happen Now?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/x-is-getting-sued-what-will-happen-now/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[X Corporation, owner of the social media platform formerly known as Twitter and currently developing X-Connect, is currently being sued by the U.S. government. They]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>X Corporation, owner of the social media platform formerly known as Twitter and currently developing X-Connect, is currently being sued by the U.S. government. They say they have nothing to hide, but, if they have nothing to hide, what is the real reason for them getting sued? The X representative said that they have not had government involvement because of the issues that are surrounded with it, but they are not involved and are having issues with that same government. </p>



<p>They say that they are still committed to the development of the X-Connect app while following regulations and focusing on innovations even after this information of them being sued. After a U.S. cabinet meeting in which an A.I. implication was brought up, the U.S. government and X each threatened to sue the other entity. So they say that they have no government relations, yet still talk to the U.S. cabinet? That is directly going against what the X representative said they were doing. How are you able to go against your own words?</p>



<p>Even though they are receiving an abundance of backlash and are in the midst of getting sued, X Corporation is still attempting to further develop their app. Which also raises the question, will that affect the amount of users that will use their X-Connect app? They have said that they are going to continue to control their app because they have trust in their own systems, and as of now have no further comment on the situation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China Expresses Discontent With an Article They say is &#8220;Unrepresentative of Our Beliefs&#8221;</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/china-expresses-discontent-with-an-article-they-say-is-unrepresentative-of-our-beliefs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the morning of Dec. 9, 2023, The Times of India published a piece on China recently using it&#8217;s veto power within the United Nations]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On the morning of Dec. 9, 2023, The Times of India published a piece on China recently using it&#8217;s veto power within the United Nations Security Council (UNSC) to vote against providing humanitarian aid for the for the Russia-Ukraine war. &#8220;This is a blatant example of poor press from the Times of India&#8221; says the Chinese delegation.</p>



<p>In interviews with both the Washington Post and Xinhua State News Agency, China explained that the delegation has every right to execute its veto powers in the UNSC whenever the state deems it necessary and that the veto was used in this instance specifically due to China believing that the Security Council should be diverting more of it&#8217;s time to the development of peace talks. In a sense, China seeks to pour more funding into preventing additional conflict between the nations, rather than simply supplying the band-aids to heal those affected by it.</p>



<p>China expressed to the Post directly that it was actually disappointed in the direction that the UNSC has been moving in and that &#8220;the lack of action from the Security Council to even issue a statement requesting peace talks is honesty a tragedy in and of itself and reflects extremely poorly upon the UNSC, especially when aid packages have already been sent before.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese cabinet member claims Indian communications representative threatened him at press conference</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/chinese-cabinet-member-claims-indian-communications-representative-threatened-him-at-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ari Ramjit, Pan African News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the latest press conference, a representative from the cabinet of the People&#8217;s Republic of China spoke out about the war still happening between China]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>During the latest press conference, a representative from the cabinet of the People&#8217;s Republic of China spoke out about the war still happening between China and India.</p>



<p>&#8220;Not that long ago, the Indian communications minster threatened me at a press conference. He said to me: &#8216;Do you want war? Do you want war? Minister you have your war,'&#8221; the representative from China said. </p>



<p>&#8220;China&#8217;s military position is strong. Our offense and defense are firm and unwavering. Despite this strong position and our previous experience with radical Indian cabinet, China will once again graciously offer the diplomatic solution.&#8221; </p>



<p>&#8220;Firstly, an immediate removal of all Indian troops from rightfully Chinese territory,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;Second, economic reparations for all the damages India has caused China. Third, India&#8217;s support for China becoming a full member of the United Nation&#8217;s General Assembly. Fourth, India returning all seized territory that are rightfully Chinese. China is choosing to fight fire with diplomacy. We want this war to end, but if India wants to worsen this conflict and let more innocent Chinese and Indian civilians die, China&#8217;s hands are tied.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
