<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>United States Senate (1962) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/historical-committees/united-states-senate-1962/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 04:47:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The U.S. Senate: Senator William Proxmire Sepaks on Behalf of the Senate</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/10/the-u-s-senate-senator-william-proxmire-sepaks-on-behalf-of-the-senate-ready-for-edit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 16:04:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the most recent press conference, Sen. Proxmire represented the U.S. Senate and started with his condolences for the loss of Eleanor Roosevelt. He continued]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the most recent press conference, Sen. Proxmire represented the U.S. Senate and started with his condolences for the loss of Eleanor Roosevelt. He continued to express that as they dealt with the Cuban Missile Crisis, they felt that it was important to discuss the civil rights issue within the nation, specifically women’s rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>In an interview with Senator Proxmire, he stated many things not only on behalf of himself, but speaking overall for the U.S. Senate.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The Cuban missile crisis has impacted many and caused chaos, and the U.S. Senate reassures their unity and doing “not only what is in our best interest, but in the best interest of the American people.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Senate attempted solutions to help de-escalate the situation in Cuba, and at the same time protect the U.S. and its public as a whole, ensuring the safety of all Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the topic of the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women, Sen. Proxmire said, “we understand women’s rights and civil rights are an issue that requires prioritization, and they are the most important thing to the Senate. Currently, we are working on solutions to try and implement more education, as well as other social reforms which are in the process.” </p>



<p><strong>“As a senator that wants every American to know the truth, I wish all of you to know that we are trying to do the best for all American people, and I acknowledge the discontent with us, but rest assured we are using our power to ensure the happiness and great state of the U.S.A.”</strong></p>



<p>Overall not only as a senator, but a representative of our government, Sen. Proxmire and the rest of the U.S. Senate want the American people to rest assured knowing they are working on solutions to help with women’s rights, civil rights, and the overall safety of the nation, which will further unveil as debates and bills continue to develop. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LATEST FROM THE POST: Southern Democratic Senators Double Down on Their Stance and Address the Nation</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/latest-from-the-post-southern-democratic-senators-double-down-on-their-stance-and-address-the-nation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=659</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an exclusive interview with the Washington Post, Democratic Senator Olin D. Johnston and his colleauges wished to provide us with a message for the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In an exclusive interview with the Washington Post, Democratic Senator Olin D. Johnston and his colleauges wished to provide us with a message for the nation. The address reads as follows: </p>



<p>&#8220;Today I, Senator Olin D. Johnston, stand before members of the Press to address a very important matter. John Locke contended that if the government the people created in the state of nature violated the rights of the citizens and the set laws of the land, the right of revolution would entitle the people to use force to punish that government and depose its rulers. Today, In light of the drastic motions and efforts of the United States Federal Government related to the infringement of state’s rights, it is time that YOU, the people take initiative today, putting the power back in your hands.&nbsp;In accordance with the Second Southern Manifesto, and the Federal Government’s complete disregard of the statements within that document, the people must adhere to those same words of John Locke and impose the &#8216;right of revolution&#8217;. Align yourselves, and make your voices heard by marching to THE CAPITOL. If the United States Government isn’t willing to listen to the representatives of the people, let them hear from the people themselves. “</p>



<p>The colleagues supporting this address are senators Allen J. Ellender, Richard Russell Jr., Harry F. Byrd, Robert Byrd, and Herman Talmadge</p>



<p>The implications of this incitement of revolt are yet to be seen, and the Washington Post advises all Americans to stay alert as the situation develops.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is the Senate being shut out, or are they separating themselves?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/is-the-senate-being-shut-out-or-are-they-separating-themselves/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 21:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Concerns have arisen as multiple senators express their displeasure with the lack of communication between branches of the United States government. Several new resolutions presented]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Concerns have arisen as multiple senators express their displeasure with the lack of communication between branches of the United States government. Several new resolutions presented before the Senate emphasize better and more frequent levels of communication between the executive and legislative branches, but also dart between numerous topics.</p>



<p>The U.S. Senate has struggled to come to conclusions on major topics as the subject of debate shifts continuously, but valuable arguments are still being made. Civil rights and checks and balances float around the room while Senators talk about what is most important for the country. However, the consensus proves to be that immediate action needs to be taken on the rights of women and all people of color. Even then, the two groups in desperate need of civil rights protections cannot seem to be agreed upon.</p>



<p>Cooperation seems to be absent and agreement is rarely occurring in any part of the debate, even though nearly all senators share the view of the vitality of the topics. The priorities of the Senate remain questionable seeing that conversations within the chamber have no majorly effective results. As stated by more than one Senator, the allocation and protection of these rights to minority groups is imperative, and it is clear that the Senate, while indecisive, is determined to create conclusions. The future of social inequality remains anticipated yet uncertain.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Sen. James Pearson expresses his disappointment</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/u-s-sen-james-pearson-expresses-his-disappointment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=556</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Senate has officially passed many resolutions regarding the Cuban Missile Crisis, including plans regarding the U.S. Presidential Cabinet.&#160; With this, one of the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. Senate has officially passed many resolutions regarding the Cuban Missile Crisis, including plans regarding the U.S. Presidential Cabinet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With this, one of the papers not passed was the RULE paper, sponsored in part by Republican Sen. James Pearson from Kansas. This paper essentially planned on making sure that the executive branch would inform Congress of any military action to keep Congress updated and they would be able to move forward or not with the actions after 30 days. Sen. Pearson was disheartened and shared his sentiments on this matter by expressing how he felt strongly regarding the resolutions passed, as well as his resolution. </p>



<p>In an interview with Sen. Pearson, he expressed how “the cabinet has not been informing the senate of practically anything that has been going on with Cuba.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Regarding the failure of his paper he has stated the reason behind this is due to “a few people who were very much like ‘this is too much bureaucracy, this is raising tensions between the executive and legislative branch.'&#8221; </p>



<p>He further explained how the reasons for not passing his paper seem hypocritical due to his fellow senators having a similar resolution where the president would be in power for no more than 30 days with the military to protect the country. </p>



<p>He finished by explaining how “this is just quite frankly ridiculous that the senate passed this because again, it just increases tensions between the executive and legislative branch” and how on day 31 of a conflict, “we are out of luck.”  Even after coming up with solutions, they do not seem to be solving the issue at hand, but rather creating possible internal resentment within the senate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BREAKING NEWS: Classified US Government Documents released to the Public</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/breaking-news-classified-us-government-documents-released-to-the-public/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To our fellow Americans,&#160; This letter was drafted by Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson depicts the status of women in the eyes of the U.S.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To our fellow Americans,&nbsp;</p>



<p>This letter was drafted by Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson depicts the status of women in the eyes of the U.S. Cabinet and Vice President. This letter was in response to the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women after they proposed multiple resolutions to address the labor standards of women, women&#8217;s civic engagement, and women’s engagement in the ongoing Missile Crisis in Cuba. To highlight some of his sentiments, he stated that the sentiments of the PCSW were not priorities, and the administration does not have the time to address any of these issues.</p>



<p>The women in America should not take elements of this letter and be content. The women in America should take this letter as an opportunity to prove to their governmental representatives that their contributions to the public sphere are still relevant to embody the capitalist values of our society.</p>



<p><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/k2LLD4vH6iG_JblqhSpS7QsFl6lsj-xA1Nq8CGOue96ary85kG9YWrti95zeUa6wg-fztL4HtSOOYSDmge2APDOfS56tYtsynR3JC_DMGzOxAPsU6RjT2FKPo9LubOa6dkEjcORgJqsKT6JUqrZ9Obi98ZavgddFmkZIYNaOczrI3aFtS7hyuom5QlUSKg" width="93" height="93"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/9NG4gKNdsHHLkjYuYZtZWGnZdQI03dXQybaSSuIXeeYcNA_usYSBVFcvxgO8NW6CVW0gGiuxV6Iz5rU8EJyVO_aVxx3I1oSQ3VPCuDLORUw8Gq6rZ6otpPz0L8FXCl-eHAi-PV-AXTsq-h1zW6OCxhm7rFB-qqWKgvvxINpdOp6-38nkewZyZdMsdC0oWQ" width="160" height="84"></p>



<p>Letter from LBJ</p>



<p>Office of President John F. Kennedy</p>



<p>Washington D.C.<br>October 1962</p>



<p>_____________________________________________________________________________</p>



<p>October 1962, Washington D.C. &#8211;</p>



<p>While your input on policy has been appreciated previously. I have the unfortunate task of informing your commission that we currently cannot pursue your policies regarding women in the workplace. They may have some potential, but because of the events occurring in Cuba, the President does not have the time to review them.</p>



<p>Your commitment to our nation is admirable, and I have nothing but respect for Mrs. Roosevelt. However, while we struggle with a response to this crisis, we cannot spare any time to review this report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Office of the Vice President of the United States of America</p>



<p>Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson</p>



<p>The letter, when delivered to Mrs. Roosevelt, the former first lady,&nbsp; <em>may</em> have contributed to her death, it seemed to have caused her weak heart to give out. Unfortunately, she passed away later that night, and America lost a national treasure. Now the American people are faced with a decision, will we tolerate her death? Will we let Mr. Vice President Lyndon B Johnson gets away with his disregard for women or will we stand up to him? <strong>America stands true today, and America will stand strong tomorrow, with women behind it.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Concerned American Citizen</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What, if any, Roles can Women Play in Society?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/what-if-any-roles-can-women-play-in-society/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 1962, the role of women in society is becoming more important. It is becoming more than just cooking, cleaning, and watching the children. The]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In 1962, the role of women in society is becoming more important. It is becoming more than just cooking, cleaning, and watching the children. The role that they can play in society is now more important than it has been before. </p>



<p>Hon. Orville Freeman mentions how women can play a significant role in the Cold War between America and Cuba. We have men who are standing with women to want to help them become more active in American society. Working with other powerful women and men can help everyone achieve a common goal that they want, which is for women to have more roles within society. </p>



<p>As a group, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women are working to see if they can introduce more women into the medical field, as well as the serving in the war if they so please. This would allow more empowerment within women, allowing them to be more confident to share their ideas; a critical perspective when considering the development of America. </p>



<p>Freeman also mentioned in an interview, “We believe that providing loans to women in entrepreneurship would enhance network and collaboration between women and those collaborations could be channeled into civic duties.”</p>



<p>Providing loans to allow women to be able to experience different professions will allow them to want to be more active in society. This is important because whether or not you need people to be more active in society, if they are not willing to do it, less people will want to be active in society. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is JFK Under the Threat of Impeachment?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/is-jfk-under-the-threat-of-impeachment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a majority Democratic yet visibly divided Senate, Senators are heavily struggling to reach any sort of agreement over how to take action on the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a majority Democratic yet visibly divided Senate, Senators are heavily struggling to reach any sort of agreement over how to take action on the intensifying Cuban Missile Crisis, and debates have even led to an angry proposition that President John F. Kennedy be impeached. It is no longer just party differences that are causing splits between views, as senators representing the same party express contradicting opinions on what to do about Cuba. Solutions and objectives repeatedly contradict each other while various senators give speeches to the Cabinet. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1025" src="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-519" srcset="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81.jpg 1600w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-300x192.jpg 300w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-1024x656.jpg 1024w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-768x492.jpg 768w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-1536x984.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p>After listening to the opinions of a few Democrats, it seems that de-escalation of the crisis appears to be a popular idea amongst the Democratic party. On the other hand, Republicans desire to push for greater protection of American citizens from any expansion of communism and the Cuban Missile Crisis onto American soil and to raise funds for fighting the Cold War effort.</p>



<p>According to the Democratic Senator of Wisconsin, William Proxmire, &#8220;All of the members of the Senate are trying as hard as they possibly can to regain citizens&#8217; trust and restore public faith in the Senate.&#8221; Following up on the scandals concerning the political and ideological associations of some Senators, it is clear that they strongly wish to make up for what has happened. Proxmire emphasized that he would like to call upon every Senator to do what is best for all Americans despite political beliefs, and that peace is the priority to negotiate for.</p>



<p>It has additionally been noted that amplifying involvement in the crisis would be far too costly for the United States, seeing that we, as a nation, are still recovering from some economic recessions coming back from war. Considering all this, the Senate has yet to pass anything regarding the Cuban Missile Crisis, and leaves Americans increasingly anxious over the tomorrow of the United States.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Senators are Voting Against Their Own Views</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/senators-are-voting-against-their-own-views/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many United States senators have gathered in an attempt to discuss their opposing views, similar views, and create resolutions to solve their issues that they]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Many United States senators have gathered in an attempt to discuss their opposing views, similar views, and create resolutions to solve their issues that they are combating. Senator Mike Mansfields has mentioned, “Some senators have lost sight of that given power that they have, they are working with the interest of their own minds and not the the best of the people.” Allowing yourself to stay in line and work for what is best for the people is critical in this position, which some are clearly struggling to do. </p>



<p>Senator Humphrey, who was previously the majority whip, was not present, so it was elected by the rest of the senate that Senator Johnston would be whip, to cover in his absence. The responsibility of the whip is to keep everyone in line so they are following policy, which is important information to note. “There have been some conflicts that Senator Johnston has been involved in, but in the end, some senators, like Senator Young from Ohio, have been working across the aisle with Republican minorities, instead of working with democratic Allies,” Mansfield mentioned in an interview. It is already being seen that the whip who was elected is already working with opposing parties, which sparks the question, is that someone who you want to be representing your party? </p>



<p>Mansfield has been able to work around, listening in on what others are doing and saying, and has had many resolutions to the issue at hand, an example of one of the people who are staying in line, as one should be doing. A quote from Mansfield, “I went and worked with Senator Adkin of Vermont and we wrote a paper on agriculture that just passed. Other bills we have passed, in regards to our first topic which was innovation, and industrialism and developing the American interior, all four bills passed, which they don’t directly step over each other, but they do.” Mansfield has passed many bills, further showing that he is one of the few that can stay in line, as the senate should be doing. </p>



<p>There have been resolutions passed by both the Republican and Democratic Parties, two specific ones being written in part by Senator Young, and another by a Republican senator; both passing with 27 votes. But, it was seen that opposing parties were voting with papers that were from the opposing parties, which were directly seen in this situation. This is causing conflict within the Democratic Party because it is not allowing them to vote properly because some are voting for Republic papers that have opposing views to what they are trying to pass. </p>



<p></p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LATEST FROM THE POST: Conservative Southern Democrats Make Their Voices Heard</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/latest-from-the-post-conservative-southern-democrats-make-their-voices-heard/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 03:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the past few years, the United States government has made significant pushes in the direction of improved civil rights and breaking down gender-based disparities.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Over the past few years, the United States government has made significant pushes in the direction of improved civil rights and breaking down gender-based disparities. However, Democratic Senator Olin. D. Johnston believes that in doing so, the government on several occasions has infringed the rights of individual states and their constitutional ability to create laws the reflect the views of their people. </p>



<p>This is why he, alongside other conservative democrats from the south, have drafted the Declaration on States Rights and Constitutional Principals, also known as the &#8220;Second Southern Manifesto&#8221;. This  manifesto stresses the importance of recognizing how badly state sovereignty has been disrespected within the United States. Additionally, Senator Johnston himself states that &#8220;The recent advocacy for legislation targeted towards civil rights is &#8216;Un-American&#8217; and as unwarranted as it is unconstitutional.&#8221; </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sen. Byrd apologizes for association with Nazi sympathizer, Sen. Johnston denies allegations</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/latest-from-the-post-bbc-questionable-sympathies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 01:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LATEST FROM THE POST &#38; BBC: Questionable Sympathies? The following senators have been identified as potential Nazi sympathizers via association with Nazi apologist and founder]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>LATEST FROM THE POST &amp; BBC: Questionable Sympathies?</strong></p>



<p>The following senators have been identified as potential Nazi sympathizers via association with Nazi apologist and founder of the Christian Nationalist Crusade Gerald L.K. Smith, Stuart Symington, Clinton Anderson, Olin D. Johnston, John Little McClellan, Allen J. Ellender, and Harry F. Byrd Sr.</p>



<p>Both the BBC and Washington Post were able to conduct interviews with Senators Harry F. Byrd Sr. and Olin D Johnston respectively. Senator Byrd Sr. confessed to the allegations against him stating &#8220;I apologize for saying that, that was very radical and extreme of me&#8230; I meant to say something else, more as a joke than anything.&#8221; Senator Byrd Sr.&#8217;s jokes will likely not be as comedic as he hoped as this breaking information does not seem like it could be of much benefit to his career or credibility within American politics.</p>



<p>Alternatively, Senator Johnston was baffled when approached about the allegations against him but after collecting his thoughts he was able to formulate a response. &#8220;I&#8217;ve served the US Government for a long time now, I&#8217;ve served in both the first and second World Wars, and any claims of me being associated with the Nazi is honestly just ridiculous,&#8221; said Johnston. Senator Johnston believes he&#8217;s done an insurmountable amount of work for the United States and wishes nothing but the support of the nation that he&#8217;s served so over the course of his career.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
