<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/feed/?simply_static_page=1110" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:31:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>After The Janes Press Conference Fiasco, Members Speak Out</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/after-the-janes-press-conference-fiasco-members-speak-out/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 06:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Janes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1664</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As you all have heard, something huge has happened in the Janes. During the press conference, an argument ensured between two members, and the press]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As you all have heard, something huge has happened in the Janes. During the press conference, an argument ensured between two members, and the press heard something about getting arrested. Here&#8217;s the video of the argument.</p>



<p></p>



<p>A group has split apart from the Janes. The organization has been spilt into one group of the 7 original members &#8220;The Janes&#8221; and The other three members are now a part of an unknown organization called &#8220;The Does&#8221;. </p>



<p>MTV was privileged to get a statement from two members of &#8220;The Janes&#8221;, The Director of Public Policy and the Director of Communications. </p>



<p>&#8220;We are the Janes collective. A collective is founded on togetherness. the Janes are incredibly hurt and betrayed by the treason of former Janes&#8217; member Gabriela Vasquez AKA Gabby. One of the most discussed values the Janes value is loyalty. A person seeking abortion needs to trust the abortion clinic and clinician. Thus we cannot support Gabriela, and we will be investigating the situation and plan to sue her. Following Gabriela, the Lead Activist is the Directory of Community Relations and the Founder.&#8221;</p>



<p>On the other hand, anonymous source told MTV that they do not plan to follow through with the legal actions presented by the Directors of Public Policy and Communications. </p>



<p>There was a second leak relating to the Janes partnership with ExxonMobil. ExxonMobil gave &#8220;The Janes&#8221; $500K for funds. What they don&#8217;t know is that the money is being laundered to the underground group &#8220;The Does&#8221;, and they are using this money to do more embezzlement. This is why &#8220;The Janes&#8221; was split in the first place. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran accused of misconduct in Iran-Iraq War</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/iran-accused-of-misconduct-in-iran-iraq-war/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hongtao Hu, The Sun]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 23:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of Iraq (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hot off of accusations that its ally Syria is engaging in chemical warfare, the USSR is pressuring Iran to cede the territories of Golestan, North]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="396" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/President_Ali_Khamenei_in_Iran-Iraq_War.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1709" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/President_Ali_Khamenei_in_Iran-Iraq_War.jpg 600w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/President_Ali_Khamenei_in_Iran-Iraq_War-300x198.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">President Ali Khamenei visiting soldiers during the Iran-Iraq War. (Source: Wikipedia Commons)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Hot off of accusations that its ally Syria is engaging in chemical warfare, the USSR is pressuring Iran to cede the territories of Golestan, North Khorasan, and Razavo Khorasan due to claims of civilian killings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The USSR has accused Iran of killing USSR civilians in its northeastern provinces, stating that Iran has “endangered and already killed thousands of innocent civilians” in the provinces of Golestan, North Khorasan, and Razavi Khorasan, and thus requests to occupy said provinces.</p>



<p>It is important to note that the war between Iraq and Iran is occurring along the western border of Iran, with Iraq fighting a 2-front war between Syria to the west and Iran to the east.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/8Q0ML2L8YV6PJB1ns9_ei-8aPrTmBsafGE9ML_2u1fv03Mq-BtncbE6qFcvsGDmCHG8JfOsR1kmmi_F-u5DnUN3JpT8otN5tMXuctYK7ArI4RmvZj5pQ0F_nGrYKmNkXb-zA7ZFSjZ3gY0MRhJDG6Q0" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Iran has asserted that the war is occurring nowhere close to possible USSR civilians, claiming that the USSR is threatening Iran with military action.</p>



<p>The Iranian Minister of Petroleum states that “it seems like the USSR has the worst intentions for the Middle East” and is beginning to establish a demilitarized zone within the provinces, along with seeking diplomatic negotiations with the USSR.</p>



<p>The Minister of Petroleum is also requesting the international community to take notice, stressing that “we hope the international community and especially the U.S. can recognize the severity of the USSR’s deception and their threat at this moment.”</p>



<p>Additionally, the Iraqi cabinet has accused Iran’s ally Syria of using chemical warfare and thus violating the Geneva Convention during its incursion into the western borders of Iraq.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Minister of Foreign Affairs from Iraq calls upon the Arab League to take action against Iran, stating: “There’s a great importance that the Arab League applies trade sanctions against Iran so that the Iranian and Syrian treachery can near an end.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iran states that it’s currently looking into the accusations of chemical warfare and reconsidering its relationship with Syria, however, they are still allying with them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. cabinet finds success in meeting with Russia</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/u-s-cabinet-finds-success-in-meeting-with-russia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juliana Gunvalsen, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:49:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1692</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Shortly after 3 p.m., the U.S. concluded discussions with the Russian cabinet in order to secure the ship carrying oil to China as well as]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Shortly after 3 p.m., the U.S. concluded discussions with the Russian cabinet in order to secure the ship carrying oil to China as well as the American nationals. </p>



<p>In terms of exchanges, the U.S. negotiation involved swapping two Russian nationals for every American national returned safely to the United States. While this was discussed as potentially being an unfair exchange, the cabinet assures the press that this will foster relations between both nations, as well as China. This swap also comes after the Biden administration initiated a prisoner swap with American W.N.B.A. player Brittney Griner and Russian Arms Dealer Vadim Krasikov, which was met with both ridicule and celebration within American borders. </p>



<p>In terms of the ship carrying oil, the cabinet ensured that it will be completing its trip to China as quickly as possible. Furthermore, the CIA Director shared that the Turkish Intelligence Agency will be investigating the contents on the ship to ensure the integrity of the delivery. This will continue previous relationships between the U.S. and Turkey, especially with having Turkey as a mediator. </p>



<p>The United States&#8217; cabinet emphasized the importance of keeping lines of communication open throughout all recovery efforts. Their priorities throughout negotians were the safety of all nationals as well as Ukrainian citizens as well as gaining control of the ship. When asked if this will give an upperhand to the U.S. delegation, it was clear that this does give the United States a certain edege. This leverage would especially become relevant if the United States were to intervene in the war in Ukraine. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese finance minister announces plan to become sole Taiwanese ruler</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/chinese-finance-minister-announces-plan-to-become-sole-taiwanese-ruler/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ministries of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The People’s Republic of China’s finance minister laid out his plans to become the sole ruler of Taiwan in an exclusive interview with the Moscow]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The People’s Republic of China’s finance minister laid out his plans to become the sole ruler of Taiwan in an exclusive interview with the Moscow Times. The Minister explained his goals and his desire for the Taiwanese people.</p>



<p>Claiming that Taiwan was rightfully Chinese land, the minister explained why he felt the obligation to want the island. </p>



<p>“The citizens of Taiwan want a minister who is in accordance with the people,” he said. “I am that person.” </p>



<p>The Chinese finance minister also reiterated that he is the only person he believes the Taiwanese people want ruling over them. </p>



<p>“I have experience as a finance minister, and I know how money runs a country,” he explained. He also elaborated that China taking over Taiwan would complete China’s adherence to the one country, two systems policy.</p>



<p>The minister of finance remained mum on how he would implement his plans to take over the island. “I haven’t decided on anything specific,” he said, in regard to how he would invade the island. “But when the time is right, Taiwan joining us will be inevitable.”</p>



<p>He also laid out the Communist system that he would impose in Taiwan. “The Taiwanese people do not want a democracy,” he stated. “They want a system of government similar to what rules mainland China.” According to a recent poll conducted through Taipei’s National Chengchi University, only 6.5 percent of Taiwanese citizens support reunification and rule under the People’s Republic of China.</p>



<p>“I want to see Taiwan under new management,” the finance minister explained. When asked how he would deal with potential opposition from current Taiwanese citizens, he was blunt. “We need reeducation rather than suppression of the press,” he said. “The only way the world will learn to understand our Communist government is if we re-educate them through increased media and literature.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Patrick Wall: Traitor to the UK</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/patrick-wall-traitor-to-the-uk/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The House of Commons is discussing which member of parliament has been committing treasonous acts against the UK in the Falkland Islands. The Prime Minister]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="960" height="582" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-21.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1670" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-21.png 960w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-21-300x182.png 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-21-768x466.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">House of Commons furious about the betrayl</figcaption></figure>



<p>The House of Commons is discussing which member of parliament has been committing treasonous acts against the UK in the Falkland Islands. The Prime Minister revealed to the House of Commons that there was one member of parliament that created instability in the government and risked the lives of Argentinians and British citizens in the Falkland Islands and abroad. </p>



<p>The House believes that the traitor is Patrick Wall. &#8220;Patrick Wall has been switching his own policy from the beginning,&#8221; said one anonymous member of parliament. &#8220;He made one too many compromises with the Labour party and would do anything for his bill to go through. Also, his bowler hat sucks.&#8221; Another member said he was &#8220;mentally, physically, and emotionally abused by our traitor, Patrick Wall.&#8221; </p>



<p>Prime Minister Thatcher revived the intercepted note, detailing with irrefutable proof that the traitor is Patrick Wall. Wall is now considered a traitor to the UK and will be punished accordingly. The committee is convinced that Patrick Wall is at fault, and investigating how this treason occurred, leaving everyone wondering, what on earth is going on in the House of Commons?</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corrections to Moscow Times-Al Jazeera Articles</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/corrections-to-moscow-times-al-jazeera-articles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Al Jazeera Editorial Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Moscow Times would like to sincerely apologize for errors in the press that have been reported in two recent articles about Al Jazeera. Firstly,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Moscow Times would like to sincerely apologize for errors in the press that have been reported in two recent articles about Al Jazeera. Firstly, the Moscow Times incorrectly transcribed a quote from the Minister of Technology calling upon a “hostage takeover.” In reality, the Minister of Technology called upon a “hostile takeover.” Additionally, in the opinion piece, “No objective news will come out of Al Jazeera until it cuts off Qatar,” the Minister of Technology’s assertion was repeated more accurately but he was misidentified as the Minister of Transportation. The Minister of Technology made the statement. The Moscow Times would also like to clarify a comment about the journalistic standards, this was made in regard to a working paper where the Balkans Director was questioning how to improve journalistic standards, and should not be taken to mean that Al Jazeera currently has none. That said, the Moscow Times stands by all other assertions made in both articles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK House of Commons and Cabinet Respond to Emergency Crisis</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/uk-house-of-commons-and-cabinet-respond-to-emergency-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 21:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1624</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an emergency crisis early this morning the cabinet of the UK convened to solve the Falkland islands crisis and the Soviet control of the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In an emergency crisis early this morning the cabinet of the UK convened to solve the Falkland islands crisis and the Soviet control of the Afghan government. The Cabinet reached a new and restrengthened alliance between the US and the UK in regard to the Falkland Islands. The Falkland islands are off the southern coast of South America, and due to the close proximity of the US, their CIA will supply intelligence and put diplomatic pressure on the islands, as well as impose sanctions upon Argentina.<br>The cabinet then tackled the crisis of the USSR&#8217;s presence in Afghanistan. The UK cabinet is taking anti-communist actions and is in valiant support of the Mujahadeen and stands strong against communism. With the outcome of Ronald Regan&#8217;s health still uncertain, the UK may give into the demands of the USSR. The UK is firmly against communism but lacks the action and strength to defend democracy until the last second. The UK debated the possible idea of surrendering to Afghanistan and the USSR.</p>



<p><br>When Le Monde informed the UK cabinet of the Soviet invasion of the Afghan government, the UK responded by saying that the USSR just has close ties to the Afghan government working together, but there is no infiltration of the government. Despite direct quotes from the USSR ministers, the UK was adamant about this fact.</p>



<p><br>Additionally, with the betrayal in the house of commons, the cabinet is investigating the treasonous actions of a member of parliament initiating an offensive attack into the Falkland Islands risking the lives of the British and Argentinian people living there. The House of Commons, The UK Cabinet, and Margret Thatcher are all working diligently to investigate and prosecute the offender.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNEA looks ahead to climate resiliency</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/unea-looks-ahead-to-climate-resiliency/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juliana Gunvalsen, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 21:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Having finished their first topic, the UNEA is well underway with their next concern in debate: empowering climate resilience. Yesterday, the RRECO bloc was one]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Having finished their first topic, the UNEA is well underway with their next concern in debate: empowering climate resilience. Yesterday, the RRECO bloc was one of the three papers voted on, though it did not pass.</p>



<p>“I think that our paper RRECO was realistic and people could not handle that fact,&#8221; a representative from the bloc stated. &#8220;There was a certain piece of western bias… We just thought it was logical to have big developed countries and a few small countries so we really wanted to express the stress in the realistic portion.”</p>



<p>Despite these events, many of the same countries resumed their work together this morning in order to tackle the new issues at hand. Countries such as Mauritania, Venezuela, Syria, China, Iran, and Russia. </p>



<p>Collectively they “came together to start working on this one solution really because we knew that our countries get along, have similar policies, and things that definitely affect each other.” Syria stated, “For instance, droughts can really cause floods, that can be the main contributor, and Syria suffers from droughts. We feel like at this point we are probably the farthest along bloc, it&#8217;s the most comprehensive paper.”</p>



<p>Other delegates, such as Indonesia and Uruguay, were simply glad to see a display of diplomacy in the cabinet. Indonesia feels that “it was absolutely wonderful that this paper got passed and got passed unilaterally in various countries who had various different interests. I initially came out on the opposition but when I saw the paper and examined it more closely I realized we shared a common goal, so I ended up supporting it very strongly.”</p>



<p>Uruguay, a sponsor on the Net Green paper that was passed, shared a similar sentiment. The delegate said, “I&#8217;m just really happy I could be apart of the sponsors for this amazing paper. It was really really fun just to work out these differences between countries, talking to different blocs trying to make it so we can get our paper passed and it&#8217;s just amazing to see the world take a step in the right direction. It&#8217;s the first time I&#8217;ve ever seen this many countries come together to do something and not say something, but objectively do something.”</p>



<p>The committee is working relentlessly to solve the current issues and anticipates the presentation of working papers at some point during today’s session.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ExxonMobil is making a playlist for Reception Tonight?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/exxonmobil-is-making-a-playlist-for-reception-tonight/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 21:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MTV just listened to ExxonMobil Board of Directors was asked to add some songs to a playlist for our Reception tonight, and boy it&#8217;s a]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>MTV just listened to ExxonMobil Board of Directors was asked to add some songs to a playlist for our Reception tonight, and boy it&#8217;s a good one!  The reason why MTV was invited was that the CEO of ExxonMobil told MTV, “We are all on fire. It is time to turn this ship around.” </p>



<p>Here is the Link to all of the Songs &#8211; <a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/5i110Ukju6zKUmHy7CKrFf?si=EWdn6qcKTU6Fsw5tsTI4IA">https://open.spotify.com/playlist/5i110Ukju6zKUmHy7CKrFf?si=EWdn6qcKTU6Fsw5tsTI4IA</a></p>



<p>The first song brought up was <strong>Eraser by Ed Sheeran.</strong> This song had absolutely no explanation and no significance, it failed 2 to 4. </p>



<p>The next song that was brought up was <strong>Mo Bamba by Sheck West</strong> But, alas, they choose to use the clean one. Their reason was for giggles because it doesn&#8217;t sound like the original. Hence, why it passed Unanimously! </p>



<p>Calling all Swifties! The next song is <strong>You Belong with Me by the Queen of Pop, T-Swift</strong>! This song was suggested by the VP of Corporate Strategic Planning. “The citizens on the tanker belong in our hearts.”</p>



<p>This next song was the biggest Party song (Pun intended) in the 2010s. <strong>Party in the U.S.A by Miley Cyrus. </strong>There was no exact reason why it was mentioned but none the matter. It passed unanimously.</p>



<p>This next song is very controversial, but nonetheless, it was mentioned. The song is <strong>Touch the Sky by Kanye West</strong>. The Board of Directors did a one-for and one-against debate for this song. The Director for this song was the VP of Public and Government Affairs. &#8220;It&#8217;s Musical genius! It’s just one song, it&#8217;s insane!” The director that was against the song was the VP of Corporate Strategic Planning. He said that &#8220;With everything going on with Kayne, do we want our public image to show we support Kayne? With everything against him, this could affect our image. This is your (VP of Public and Government Affairs) job and your reputation on the line.&#8221; Despite the VP of Public and Government Affairs speaking for this song, it failed unanimously. </p>



<p>This next song did the opposite of the Kayne song, it passed unanimously! This song is <strong>Runaway Baby by Bruno Mars</strong>. They also didn&#8217;t give me a reason why but it is a good song though!</p>



<p>The final song that was voted on failed. With 2 votes for and 4 votes against, was the song <strong>Butter by BTS</strong>. Even though they&#8217;re being enlisted into the army, they still are loved in people&#8217;s hearts. The now-former VP of Public and Government Affairs&#8217; explanation was butter equals oil in cooking, and ExxonMobil stands for oil. </p>



<p>The Board is very excited about the reception and can&#8217;t wait for the participants to hear the tunes playlist. If you have any suggestions for songs to add to the list, click the link below to add songs to the potential list!</p>



<p><a href="https://forms.gle/eu9nyhPhXTn4QeBx5">https://forms.gle/eu9nyhPhXTn4QeBx5</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Council of Ministers of Iraq provides statement to Le Monde</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/council-of-ministers-of-iraq-provides-statement-to-le-monde/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 20:52:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of Iraq (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1618</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-video"><video controls src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/le_monde_iraq_cab_statement.mov"></video></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
