<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ministries of the People’s Republic of China &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/ministries-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china/feed/?simply_static_page=1199" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:56:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Chinese finance minister announces plan to become sole Taiwanese ruler</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/chinese-finance-minister-announces-plan-to-become-sole-taiwanese-ruler/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ministries of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The People’s Republic of China’s finance minister laid out his plans to become the sole ruler of Taiwan in an exclusive interview with the Moscow]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The People’s Republic of China’s finance minister laid out his plans to become the sole ruler of Taiwan in an exclusive interview with the Moscow Times. The Minister explained his goals and his desire for the Taiwanese people.</p>



<p>Claiming that Taiwan was rightfully Chinese land, the minister explained why he felt the obligation to want the island. </p>



<p>“The citizens of Taiwan want a minister who is in accordance with the people,” he said. “I am that person.” </p>



<p>The Chinese finance minister also reiterated that he is the only person he believes the Taiwanese people want ruling over them. </p>



<p>“I have experience as a finance minister, and I know how money runs a country,” he explained. He also elaborated that China taking over Taiwan would complete China’s adherence to the one country, two systems policy.</p>



<p>The minister of finance remained mum on how he would implement his plans to take over the island. “I haven’t decided on anything specific,” he said, in regard to how he would invade the island. “But when the time is right, Taiwan joining us will be inevitable.”</p>



<p>He also laid out the Communist system that he would impose in Taiwan. “The Taiwanese people do not want a democracy,” he stated. “They want a system of government similar to what rules mainland China.” According to a recent poll conducted through Taipei’s National Chengchi University, only 6.5 percent of Taiwanese citizens support reunification and rule under the People’s Republic of China.</p>



<p>“I want to see Taiwan under new management,” the finance minister explained. When asked how he would deal with potential opposition from current Taiwanese citizens, he was blunt. “We need reeducation rather than suppression of the press,” he said. “The only way the world will learn to understand our Communist government is if we re-educate them through increased media and literature.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China and U.S. Joint Meeting</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/china-and-u-s-joint-meeting/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josie Barnes, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 20:05:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ministries of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a shocking press conference over the discussion of The Directive to Strengthen International Trade between China and the U.S. cabinets, the deal fell through.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After a shocking press conference over the discussion of The Directive to Strengthen International Trade between China and the U.S. cabinets, the deal fell through. This deal was supposed to accomplish many things, including increasing imports from the U.S. by twenty-five percent, replacing twenty-five percent of oil exchange initially from Russia, and handing over that trade to the U.S. The deal was also going to lift the embargo the U.S. had placed on semiconductors.</p>



<p>The U.S. stated, &#8220;We can not entertain a deal with China if they are also going to continue to entertain an oil deal or anything of the like with Russia.&#8221; After learning of the China and Russia conversations, the U.S. could no longer be apart. Then the cabinet stated, &#8220;That is ultimately what we have come to the table to present, and we have been as upfront as possible, and we do not want to negotiate with people we do not trust.&#8221;</p>



<p>China had a comment about this remark and ultimately stated, &#8220;I believe it is disgraceful for a diplomatic country such as the U.S. to pull out of a deal that the People&#8217;s Republic of China has already fulfilled their part of&#8221;.</p>



<p>At the end of the conference, no consensus was made. The Cabinet of the U.S. walked out to their national anthem the star-spangled banner, and the Cabinet of China soon followed. After no deal/signing as of yesterday, we wonder if China and the U.S. will try again and make a deal.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China cabinet looks toward negotiations</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/china-cabinet-looks-toward-negotiations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juliana Gunvalsen, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 18:54:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ministries of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1032</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China got to work quickly this morning to discuss what negotiations could look like as the delegations made aims to be more democratic in their]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>China got to work quickly this morning to discuss what negotiations could look like as the delegations made aims to be more democratic in their foreign affairs. While the delegation maintains it will hold strong values, many of their other endeavors have suffered as a result. These include gaining support for their goal to enforce their “One China policy” as well as various aspects of trade.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="624" height="346" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screen-Shot-2023-02-03-at-1.53.13-PM.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1033" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screen-Shot-2023-02-03-at-1.53.13-PM.png 624w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screen-Shot-2023-02-03-at-1.53.13-PM-300x166.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 624px) 100vw, 624px" /></figure>



<p>One suggestion offered by the cabinet was to initiate a prisoner swap with the United States in order to foster relations between the two countries. The U.S. has long condemned China for their taking of prisoners, most of whom have been determined as wrongfully detained. According to CNN, China currently has three such detainees imprisoned. While U.S. Secretary of&nbsp;State Antony Blinken was scheduled to travel to Beijing, this trip has been postponed following the discovery of a Chinese spy balloon flying over the U.S. on February 2.</p>



<p>Another aspect of discontentment that members of the cabinet acknowledged was the claim that much of Chinese technology has been stolen from the United States. The delegates reported that there were efforts to crack down on such enterprises as China now possesses the resources to make these advancements on their own.</p>



<p>Most of these ideas come in response to the United States’ embargoes on China, most of which are a result of alleged human rights violations occurring within China’s borders. The most recent of these actions occurred in December of 2022 when the US imposed sanctions on individuals and organizations tied to illegal fishing, which is commonly tied to other illicit activities.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese expansion draws US ire</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/chinese-expansion-draws-us-ire/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juliana Gunvalsen, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:33:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Ministries of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=828</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[For many years the People’s Republic of China has disputed its territory’s reach with bordering nations like India and Taiwan, however lately this has turned]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>For many years the People’s Republic of China has disputed its territory’s reach with bordering nations like India and Taiwan, however lately this has turned towards aggressive actions by the Chinese government. According to the Council on Foreign Relations, a clash between Indian and Chinese troops occurred on December 9, 2022 after China failed to observe its’ standing agreement with India that outlines the notion that the countries cannot amass troops on the border. This comes from China as an attempt to change the LAC (Line of Actual Control). While China has no such agreement with Taiwan, other countries globally have acknowledged that they will retaliate if China chooses to initiate war in Taiwan, most notably the United States. A representative from the United States said, “We think that all countries should have their national autonomy and we stand for that globally.” Just this week, Taiwan activated military systems after Chinese aggression in the form of aircraft and warships. When asked to comment, a Chinese delegate refused to comment. While the delegate may be silent, the Chinese governments’ actions speak volumes. These actions have not gone unnoticed and this past week U.S. General Mike Minihan predicts war between China and the United States over Taiwan as soon as 2025. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
