<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cabinet of the United States (1962) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/historical-committees/cabinet-of-the-united-states-1962/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:30:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>BREAKING NEWS: Classified US Government Documents released to the Public</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/breaking-news-classified-us-government-documents-released-to-the-public/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To our fellow Americans,&#160; This letter was drafted by Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson depicts the status of women in the eyes of the U.S.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To our fellow Americans,&nbsp;</p>



<p>This letter was drafted by Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson depicts the status of women in the eyes of the U.S. Cabinet and Vice President. This letter was in response to the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women after they proposed multiple resolutions to address the labor standards of women, women&#8217;s civic engagement, and women’s engagement in the ongoing Missile Crisis in Cuba. To highlight some of his sentiments, he stated that the sentiments of the PCSW were not priorities, and the administration does not have the time to address any of these issues.</p>



<p>The women in America should not take elements of this letter and be content. The women in America should take this letter as an opportunity to prove to their governmental representatives that their contributions to the public sphere are still relevant to embody the capitalist values of our society.</p>



<p><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/k2LLD4vH6iG_JblqhSpS7QsFl6lsj-xA1Nq8CGOue96ary85kG9YWrti95zeUa6wg-fztL4HtSOOYSDmge2APDOfS56tYtsynR3JC_DMGzOxAPsU6RjT2FKPo9LubOa6dkEjcORgJqsKT6JUqrZ9Obi98ZavgddFmkZIYNaOczrI3aFtS7hyuom5QlUSKg" width="93" height="93"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/9NG4gKNdsHHLkjYuYZtZWGnZdQI03dXQybaSSuIXeeYcNA_usYSBVFcvxgO8NW6CVW0gGiuxV6Iz5rU8EJyVO_aVxx3I1oSQ3VPCuDLORUw8Gq6rZ6otpPz0L8FXCl-eHAi-PV-AXTsq-h1zW6OCxhm7rFB-qqWKgvvxINpdOp6-38nkewZyZdMsdC0oWQ" width="160" height="84"></p>



<p>Letter from LBJ</p>



<p>Office of President John F. Kennedy</p>



<p>Washington D.C.<br>October 1962</p>



<p>_____________________________________________________________________________</p>



<p>October 1962, Washington D.C. &#8211;</p>



<p>While your input on policy has been appreciated previously. I have the unfortunate task of informing your commission that we currently cannot pursue your policies regarding women in the workplace. They may have some potential, but because of the events occurring in Cuba, the President does not have the time to review them.</p>



<p>Your commitment to our nation is admirable, and I have nothing but respect for Mrs. Roosevelt. However, while we struggle with a response to this crisis, we cannot spare any time to review this report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Office of the Vice President of the United States of America</p>



<p>Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson</p>



<p>The letter, when delivered to Mrs. Roosevelt, the former first lady,&nbsp; <em>may</em> have contributed to her death, it seemed to have caused her weak heart to give out. Unfortunately, she passed away later that night, and America lost a national treasure. Now the American people are faced with a decision, will we tolerate her death? Will we let Mr. Vice President Lyndon B Johnson gets away with his disregard for women or will we stand up to him? <strong>America stands true today, and America will stand strong tomorrow, with women behind it.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Concerned American Citizen</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What, if any, Roles can Women Play in Society?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/what-if-any-roles-can-women-play-in-society/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 1962, the role of women in society is becoming more important. It is becoming more than just cooking, cleaning, and watching the children. The]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In 1962, the role of women in society is becoming more important. It is becoming more than just cooking, cleaning, and watching the children. The role that they can play in society is now more important than it has been before. </p>



<p>Hon. Orville Freeman mentions how women can play a significant role in the Cold War between America and Cuba. We have men who are standing with women to want to help them become more active in American society. Working with other powerful women and men can help everyone achieve a common goal that they want, which is for women to have more roles within society. </p>



<p>As a group, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women are working to see if they can introduce more women into the medical field, as well as the serving in the war if they so please. This would allow more empowerment within women, allowing them to be more confident to share their ideas; a critical perspective when considering the development of America. </p>



<p>Freeman also mentioned in an interview, “We believe that providing loans to women in entrepreneurship would enhance network and collaboration between women and those collaborations could be channeled into civic duties.”</p>



<p>Providing loans to allow women to be able to experience different professions will allow them to want to be more active in society. This is important because whether or not you need people to be more active in society, if they are not willing to do it, less people will want to be active in society. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is JFK Under the Threat of Impeachment?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/is-jfk-under-the-threat-of-impeachment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a majority Democratic yet visibly divided Senate, Senators are heavily struggling to reach any sort of agreement over how to take action on the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a majority Democratic yet visibly divided Senate, Senators are heavily struggling to reach any sort of agreement over how to take action on the intensifying Cuban Missile Crisis, and debates have even led to an angry proposition that President John F. Kennedy be impeached. It is no longer just party differences that are causing splits between views, as senators representing the same party express contradicting opinions on what to do about Cuba. Solutions and objectives repeatedly contradict each other while various senators give speeches to the Cabinet. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1025" src="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-519" srcset="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81.jpg 1600w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-300x192.jpg 300w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-1024x656.jpg 1024w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-768x492.jpg 768w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-1536x984.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p>After listening to the opinions of a few Democrats, it seems that de-escalation of the crisis appears to be a popular idea amongst the Democratic party. On the other hand, Republicans desire to push for greater protection of American citizens from any expansion of communism and the Cuban Missile Crisis onto American soil and to raise funds for fighting the Cold War effort.</p>



<p>According to the Democratic Senator of Wisconsin, William Proxmire, &#8220;All of the members of the Senate are trying as hard as they possibly can to regain citizens&#8217; trust and restore public faith in the Senate.&#8221; Following up on the scandals concerning the political and ideological associations of some Senators, it is clear that they strongly wish to make up for what has happened. Proxmire emphasized that he would like to call upon every Senator to do what is best for all Americans despite political beliefs, and that peace is the priority to negotiate for.</p>



<p>It has additionally been noted that amplifying involvement in the crisis would be far too costly for the United States, seeing that we, as a nation, are still recovering from some economic recessions coming back from war. Considering all this, the Senate has yet to pass anything regarding the Cuban Missile Crisis, and leaves Americans increasingly anxious over the tomorrow of the United States.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Senators are Voting Against Their Own Views</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/senators-are-voting-against-their-own-views/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many United States senators have gathered in an attempt to discuss their opposing views, similar views, and create resolutions to solve their issues that they]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Many United States senators have gathered in an attempt to discuss their opposing views, similar views, and create resolutions to solve their issues that they are combating. Senator Mike Mansfields has mentioned, “Some senators have lost sight of that given power that they have, they are working with the interest of their own minds and not the the best of the people.” Allowing yourself to stay in line and work for what is best for the people is critical in this position, which some are clearly struggling to do. </p>



<p>Senator Humphrey, who was previously the majority whip, was not present, so it was elected by the rest of the senate that Senator Johnston would be whip, to cover in his absence. The responsibility of the whip is to keep everyone in line so they are following policy, which is important information to note. “There have been some conflicts that Senator Johnston has been involved in, but in the end, some senators, like Senator Young from Ohio, have been working across the aisle with Republican minorities, instead of working with democratic Allies,” Mansfield mentioned in an interview. It is already being seen that the whip who was elected is already working with opposing parties, which sparks the question, is that someone who you want to be representing your party? </p>



<p>Mansfield has been able to work around, listening in on what others are doing and saying, and has had many resolutions to the issue at hand, an example of one of the people who are staying in line, as one should be doing. A quote from Mansfield, “I went and worked with Senator Adkin of Vermont and we wrote a paper on agriculture that just passed. Other bills we have passed, in regards to our first topic which was innovation, and industrialism and developing the American interior, all four bills passed, which they don’t directly step over each other, but they do.” Mansfield has passed many bills, further showing that he is one of the few that can stay in line, as the senate should be doing. </p>



<p>There have been resolutions passed by both the Republican and Democratic Parties, two specific ones being written in part by Senator Young, and another by a Republican senator; both passing with 27 votes. But, it was seen that opposing parties were voting with papers that were from the opposing parties, which were directly seen in this situation. This is causing conflict within the Democratic Party because it is not allowing them to vote properly because some are voting for Republic papers that have opposing views to what they are trying to pass. </p>



<p></p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release from The Kennedy Administration</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-the-kennedy-administration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good afternoon esteemed members of the press, The Kennedy Administration is ecstatic to announce a huge step forward in world peace. We have had a]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Good afternoon esteemed members of the press,</p>



<p>The Kennedy Administration is ecstatic to announce a huge step forward in world peace. We have had a breakthrough in negotiations with the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics in that they have agreed to remove their nuclear missiles from Cuba in exchange for the United States removing their nuclear missiles from Turkey. Therefore we are delighted to inform the American people that they can sleep well at night with there no longer being an enemy nuclear power 103 miles away from the American mainland.<br></p>



<p>Delightfully,</p>



<p>The Kennedy Administration</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release from The Kennedy Administration Regarding the Death of Eleanor Roosevelt</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-the-kennedy-administration-regarding-the-death-of-eleanor-roosevelt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good evening fellow Americans, I am deeply saddened to announce the passing of former First Lady Eleanor Roosevelt. Through her time as the First Lady,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Good evening fellow Americans,</p>



<p>I am deeply saddened to announce the passing of former First Lady Eleanor Roosevelt. Through her time as the First Lady, she made many great strides in championing women&#8217;s rights. Her legacy will live on through the recent passing of legislation by the PCSW on the status of women&#8217;s rights in the US.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Somberly,</p>



<p>The Kennedy Administration</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. cabinet seeks to reassure Americans following Cuban missile revelations</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/u-s-cabinet-seeks-to-reassure-americans-following-cuban-missile-revelations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 00:19:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=324</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The US cabinet sought to reassure the American people concerned about Cuba and the missile crisis with a statement to the press. &#8220;[The American people]]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The US cabinet sought to reassure the American people concerned about Cuba and the missile crisis with a statement to the press. &#8220;[The American people] have nothing to worry about,&#8221; the Head of Publicity said. &#8220;They are just building them in Cuba, and we are currently working on perusing a diplomatic solution with the USSR. Which would get these nuclear weapons out of Cuba and stop the construction of these launch sites.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Kennedy Administration and cabinet acknowledge the worries and stress by the American people with the rumors at hand, but have made it clear that conflicts are under control as they actively pursue solutions with the USSR. No other comment has been made about further actions and relations with the USSR.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Castro announces nuclear capabilities, takes credit for downed U2 spy plane</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/castro-announces-nuclear-capabilities-takes-credit-for-downed-u2-spy-plane/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="CIMUN XX - A speech by Castro" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pYF3LZ5qoaU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
