<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Council of Ministers of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (1962) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/historical-committees/council-of-ministers-of-the-union-of-soviet-socialist-republics-1962/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:52:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Press Release from The Kennedy Administration</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-the-kennedy-administration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good afternoon esteemed members of the press, The Kennedy Administration is ecstatic to announce a huge step forward in world peace. We have had a]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Good afternoon esteemed members of the press,</p>



<p>The Kennedy Administration is ecstatic to announce a huge step forward in world peace. We have had a breakthrough in negotiations with the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics in that they have agreed to remove their nuclear missiles from Cuba in exchange for the United States removing their nuclear missiles from Turkey. Therefore we are delighted to inform the American people that they can sleep well at night with there no longer being an enemy nuclear power 103 miles away from the American mainland.<br></p>



<p>Delightfully,</p>



<p>The Kennedy Administration</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release from USSR</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-ussr/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Comrades, the recent escalation of actions towards Cuba with blockades has only shown theaggression of Capitalism. We have been forced to reinforce our border to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Comrades, the recent escalation of actions towards Cuba with blockades has only shown the<br>aggression of Capitalism. We have been forced to reinforce our border to protect our allies in<br>the Warsaw Pact and abroad. We would like to inform the world that these actions are not<br>meant to be aggressive, only protective. The USSR is still strong and supporting our allies<br>against possible actions of US aggression. We want to lend a humanitarian hand where the US<br>won&#8217;t. Under communism you will be supported, under communism you are free. Now is the<br>time of communism and now is the time for safety which is why the USSR is entering peaceful<br>negotiations with the US regarding nuclear weapons, to show our generosity and equality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
