<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/historical-committees/union-council-of-ministers-of-the-republic-of-india-1962/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 05:58:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>UN will not allocate military or humanitarian resources to India</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/13/un-will-not-allocate-military-or-humanitarian-resources-to-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 04:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=648</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amidst the unbelievable drama surrounding the Sino-Indian conflict, everyone is left wondering what will happen next. Following a visit to the United Nations Security Council,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Amidst the unbelievable drama surrounding the Sino-Indian conflict, everyone is left wondering what will happen next. Following a visit to the United Nations Security Council, a vote among all members resulted in only one representative voting to give military resources to India while all 10 others voted no. Consequentially, a nearly unanimous vote to send humanitarian aid to India has been vetoed by the Republic of China, resulting in the U.N. not reserving any resources to the Indian Council. </p>



<p>The Republic of China, independent from the People&#8217;s Republic of China and which does not have U.N. representation, accepted an interview where they shared some important information about how the cabinet has been acting on the issue. Both nations China and India continue to be shocked by each other&#8217;s actions with their militaries and hatred towards both sides is building up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese cabinet member claims Indian communications representative threatened him at press conference</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/chinese-cabinet-member-claims-indian-communications-representative-threatened-him-at-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ari Ramjit, Pan African News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the latest press conference, a representative from the cabinet of the People&#8217;s Republic of China spoke out about the war still happening between China]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>During the latest press conference, a representative from the cabinet of the People&#8217;s Republic of China spoke out about the war still happening between China and India.</p>



<p>&#8220;Not that long ago, the Indian communications minster threatened me at a press conference. He said to me: &#8216;Do you want war? Do you want war? Minister you have your war,'&#8221; the representative from China said. </p>



<p>&#8220;China&#8217;s military position is strong. Our offense and defense are firm and unwavering. Despite this strong position and our previous experience with radical Indian cabinet, China will once again graciously offer the diplomatic solution.&#8221; </p>



<p>&#8220;Firstly, an immediate removal of all Indian troops from rightfully Chinese territory,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;Second, economic reparations for all the damages India has caused China. Third, India&#8217;s support for China becoming a full member of the United Nation&#8217;s General Assembly. Fourth, India returning all seized territory that are rightfully Chinese. China is choosing to fight fire with diplomacy. We want this war to end, but if India wants to worsen this conflict and let more innocent Chinese and Indian civilians die, China&#8217;s hands are tied.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Foreshadowing Events to the People&#8217;s Republic of China and India Conflict</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/the-foreshadowing-events-to-the-pr-china-and-india-conflict-ready-for-edit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=368</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After the early morning crisis update of the war starting on the border, the side is at fault is still in question. The previous status]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After the early morning crisis update of the war starting on the border, the side is at fault is still in question. The previous status of peace between India and China on the border dispute seems to be a stand-still, as both parties claim contrasting perspectives. It has been on record that the two nations appeared to be coming to terms and possibly end the dispute once and for all, up until the yesterday&#8217;s press conference where a press representative for each the China cabinet and Indian Council shared the conflicting accounts of the relations.</p>



<p>Yesterday, the Indian council made it known during the press conference that they intend not to move on the border and has claimed in the past that expanding borders is not in their interests either. At a press release in the Council yesterday , the Director of Intelligence commented on the matter describing how the Chinese government have been negligent of their offers of diplomatic relations, furthermore the Chinese are the aggressors in this conflict. According to the council, China has been violent and have killed many Indian citizens on the border. </p>



<p>At the very same press conference yesterday evening, the press representative for the People&#8217;s Republic of China stated, &#8220;India, wrongly claiming Chinese territory as its own has blatantly denied every Chinese attempt at reconciliation. China does not want violence. It wants the people of China to be safe, protected, and well fed, but Nehru has refused a trade deal, reused collaboration on scientific endeavors, refused to engage on our shared ties of decolonization.&#8221; All the while, China was also occupied with internal struggles and growth as they try to recover from the tragic event of the Banqiao Dam collapsing and crude accusations of being involved in the disappearance of the beloved Dalai Lama.</p>



<p>Now with the ongoing hostilities and violence between the two it begs the question; &#8220;Who is the real aggressor?&#8221; Both parties claim war is not wanted and have the similar resolution method of communication if the other party is willing. The issue of disinformation being spread threatened the situation and rose tensions, undoubtedly leading us to where we are today in the dispute. Going forward, it seems tensions are only rising and the two Asian nations are on the brink of war. More on this ongoing conflict coming soon in the future.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guerrilla fighters at the Sino-Indian border</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/guerrilla-fighters-at-the-sino-indian-border/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In recent updates there have been news of Indian guerrilla fighters at the border with China in response to the growing India and China border]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In recent updates there have been news of Indian guerrilla fighters at the border with China in response to the growing India and China border conflict. Guerrilla fighters may include armed civilians and non-professional paramilitary groups, even children.</p>



<p>Although the council claimed that safety of their people was the biggest concern, these fighters at the high risk Indian border raise many concerns about this. This also brings into question the preparedness of the nation as the border troops are not high-ranking military but civilians who are not trained and are at high risk facing the strong Chinese army.</p>



<p>In today&#8217;s press conference, the Indian Minister of Communications responded claiming, &#8220;&#8230;in our last press conference we did mention that we were confident in winning this war and that we believed we had the military strength to really support it.&#8221; This claim seems to falsify their reinforcing statement on the safety of Indian citizens as their &#8220;military strength&#8221; is made up of untrained citizens and possibly children, and ultimately contrasts the recent developments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>India&#8217;s Plans on the Border</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/indias-plans-on-the-border/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 10:16:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=486</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After the recent update of hostilities and tensions rising between China and India at the border, it calls into question the next step taken by]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After the recent update of hostilities and tensions rising between China and India at the border, it calls into question the next step taken by India after their numerous &#8220;attempts at communication and peace.&#8221; After press observation in the Indian Council it has become clear that cabinet members are looking for strategies and a plan of action on the war front. Members have collectively agreed on contacting the United States for foreign aid. </p>



<p>When questioned about India&#8217;s economic stability and dangers of entering war at a recent press conference, the Minister of Communications and press representative seemed to be confident in India&#8217;s ability to enter war if needed and asserted that Indian citizens should not worry about funding the war. If U.S. involvement were to occur it would be on the precedent of India&#8217;s welcoming global relations and would be beneficial to the country that &#8220;only got its independence 15 years ago.&#8221; Only time will tell if India&#8217;s confidence in their economic strength holds up as they claim it will.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China invades India, citing killing of innocent civilians</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/a-message-from-the-peoples-republic-of-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ari Ramjit, Pan African News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 08:51:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=485</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following late night meetings to address tension along the Sino-Indian border, the People&#8217;s Republic of China among others spoke out to the press addressing topics]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Following late night meetings to address tension along the Sino-Indian border, the People&#8217;s Republic of China among others spoke out to the press addressing topics that are occurring at the moment.</p>



<p>&#8220;China has met with India before to find the diplomatic solution to our bordering conflict,&#8221; said the representative from the People&#8217;s Republic of China. &#8220;India refuses to engage. China dropped the subject and left India alone, focusing on its internal affairs.&#8221;</p>



<p>&#8220;There was peace at the border until India murdered innocent Chinese citizens,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;China will not be complacent in the face of this attack. China has a plan for conflict ahead, one that will be executed with utmost precision. To the Chinese people, the coming days will be trying but we must stay united. Trust in China. You are about to feel the full power and fury of the People&#8217;s Liberation Army.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>India Refutes China</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/india-refutes-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=402</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The current conflict between China and India is escalating, especially at the recent press conference. India has explained how they are a powerful and growing]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The current conflict between China and India is escalating, especially at the recent press conference. India has explained how they are a powerful and growing especially in the economic pact, and they will not be backing down from their “‘wonderful power.” Furthermore they have stated that they have no alliances and will be using all their power and whatever it takes to maintain their borders. </p>



<p>Similarly, a representative from China has stated that they are strong, united, and growing. China holds a lot of empathy for its neighbors and on the topic of the war, they have said that India is wrongly claiming Chinese territory and have called out Nehru on lying about their alliances with the USSR as they have been meeting time and time again with Nikita Khrushchev. Additionally, they have stated that some Indian Ministers may have communist sympathies. </p>



<p>In specific response to the current conflicts between India and China, India has a message for its members of the non-alignment pact. They confirm that this pact is still on, and still happening, and that they have no sort of association with the USSR nor any other associations as they wish to solely focus on themselves. </p>



<p>Additionally, India&#8217;s response to the leaked pictures of their ministers is one; that they do not accept these pictures. They have strongly stated the fact that these pictures were unsolicited and no prior consent was asked. Along with this is the fact that they were abruptly caught off guard when they were attacked by these individuals taking photos, leaving them utterly confused. Continuing on the topic of attacks, the Minister of Finance has made a declaration that he was attacked by a delegate from China. </p>



<p>India feels strongly about avoiding any sort of violence or war and acknowledges the fact that they have tried to negotiate and have peace talks and have given China multiple opportunities, however this has been met with ignorance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Due to the fact that China wishes nothing to have nothing to do with India, India feels that it is in their best interests to not be involved in any way. They wish to solely focus on themselves and be able to develop themselves due to their recent independence. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
