<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Northrop Grumman Corporation &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2021/category/northrop-grumman-corporation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:13:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>Northrop G Harris III Condemns Raytheon “Funny Business”</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/northrop-g-harris-iii-condemns-raytheon-funny-business/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fatimah Moe, Miami Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:13:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[L3 Harris Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northrop Grumman Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=327</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The story broke earlier from AP News that the DoD ordered an investigation into defense contractors, Raytheon, and investigators found evidence of account discrepancies and]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The story broke earlier from AP News that the DoD ordered an investigation into defense contractors, Raytheon, and investigators found evidence of account discrepancies and fraudulent contracts. Investigators also found that while President Joe Biden and his team knew about these discrepancies, and still appointed Former General Lloyd Austin to be Secretary of Defense, despite his ties to Raytheon. An investigation will be launched by The House Armed Forces.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Raytheon has faced many controversies and internal issues recently. Just earlier this year, Raytheon delayed their missile defense contract with the US Government for the second time. This was after the contract had been increased to 600 million last June. An anonymous source from the DoD said “I don’t know what the **** Raytheon is doing”</p>



<p>It&#8217;s clear that Raytheon is struggling and their fraudulent behaviour may affect dealings with the government. Many companies are seeing this, and are jumping on the chance to promote their own company in light of the issues at Raytheon.</p>



<p>In an Miami Herald Exclusive with Northrop G Harris III, the company “very strongly denounces Raytheon for what can only be called corruption and funny business.” says Director of Marketing. She also adds that nothing of that sort would ever happen under N.G.H. III and “transparency with our clients is something we strive for.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Director of Strategy and Development clarifies that N.G.H. III is most upset with Raytheon’s “budgetary practices” rather than the CIA agreement. While they are speaking out against Raytheon, they are clearly attempting to maintain ties with the CIA by not condemning their actions. “We do not engage in such underhanded behavior” The Director of Strategy and Development adds.</p>



<p>Related to the controversy at Boeing the Director of Global Business says it is “very concerning” to see such behaviors, but “we are very happy to report that similar situations don’t occur under NGH III.”</p>



<p>If the DoD turns away from Raytheon for business, N.G.H. III is trying to demonstrate they are a similar if not better fit. While not directly bashing on Boeing or Raytheon, N.G.H. III is trying to capture the attention of DoD by condemning the behavior of other Defense Contractors.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">327</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Northrop Grumman rockets injure civilians in Afghanistan</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/northrop-grumman-rockets-injure-civilians-in-afghanistan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fatimah Moe, Miami Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 02:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[L3 Harris Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northrop Grumman Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=316</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“Multiple Northrop Grumman MQ-4C TRITON rockets went awry in Afghanistan striking and injuring innocent civilians,” said an anonymous source Saturday. The source says this is]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>“Multiple Northrop Grumman MQ-4C TRITON rockets went awry in Afghanistan striking and injuring innocent civilians,<strong>” </strong>said an anonymous source Saturday. The source says this is related “directly to poor manufacturing on Northrop&#8217;s end.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>In a rocket launch headed by Northrop G. Harris III, things went awry resulting in multiple injuries. An investigation into the company suggests that there was an issue with engineering communication.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We would like to offer our sincerest apologies for the accident” says Vice President of marketing of Northrop G. Harris III and “we have the best wishes for anyone injured.” She guarantees that Northrop G. Harris III will conduct a “comprehensive internal investigation” into the incident. “If it comes to it, we are prepared to take full responsibility,” she adds.</p>



<p>General Counsel to Northrop G. Harris III assures all products and research currently out are fully functional and useful. Their hope is that the investigation will be beneficial for future innovation and assuring that, upon the results of their investigations, they will take actionable change.</p>



<p>Northrop G. Harris III is trying to maintain their current deals and those still in the works. When asked about their ongoing dealings with Belarus, the director of marketing affirms that they “intend to fulfill all of our contractual obligations to Belarus and will continue working with them however they require our services.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">316</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stock declines for US companies due to COVID-19</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/stock-declines-for-us-companies-due-to-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin Corporation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northrop Grumman Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The New York Stock Exchange closed yesterday and the stocks of Lockheed Martin Stock and Northrop Grumman are down about 30 points and they have]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The New York Stock Exchange closed yesterday and the stocks of Lockheed Martin Stock and Northrop Grumman are down about 30 points and they have no revenue left after the economic downturn due the Covid-19 pandemic. However, Sukhoi-TCM has almost ample capital available with about 457 million dollars of cash on hand to develop infrastructure, technology and ensure the security and safety of the Russian Federation and economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The economy has stalled in many parts of the world, with unemployment rising and many companies close to bankruptcy, yet the Russian Sukhoi-TCM is economically strong and planning for a “prosperous future” Deputy Edmonds said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I am proud of the economic prosperity that Russia has,” Edmonds said. “In response to the lack of funds of US companies this shows America’s dwindling lack of influence. This clearly shows how American hegemony has been lost and the world is tired of their over policing and control.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States’ economic recession and failure to maintain the success of their business illustrates the fall of the United States as the global superpower. Vice-Minister Raymond states that the “failed economic status of the United States and its industrial military complex” will allow the growth of Russian companies and power around the world. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Northrop G. Harris III Discusses Supplying Arms to Belarus after Death of their President</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/northrop-g-harris-iii-discusses-supplying-arms-to-belarus-after-death-of-their-president/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fatimah Moe, Miami Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 19:41:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[L3 Harris Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northrop Grumman Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=188</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Northrop G Harris III, held a joint meeting with previous companies L3 Harris and Northrop Grumman about press, US contracts, and reaching out to Belarus]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Northrop G Harris III, held a joint meeting with previous companies L3 Harris and Northrop Grumman about press, US contracts, and reaching out to Belarus after the assasination of their President.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In a recent press release, Northrop G Harris III assured the public that their merger would not cause issues with monopolisation and “will allow us to offer stronger and more innovative technologies than ever before”. With the combination of the mutually beneficial merger, they hope to “extend our diversified defense technologies to a truly global market”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As events in Belarus escalate, defense companies are competing to supply arms to the Belarus democratic resistance. While not asserted in their agenda, the company hopes to engage Belarus and offer them weapons. Belarus has not made any deals public, but Northrop G Harris III still wishes to support Belarus’ democracy directly, according to the VP of marketing.</p>



<p>The company also wishes to outpace Raytheon and the contract that the DOD is making with them and the CIA,&nbsp; regarding surveillance technology, unmanned vehicles, and drones. This contract was leaked and not made public. While there is no indication of the DOD sending armed forces into Belarus directly, they are engaging in these secret contracts. General Council of Northrop G Harris III&#8217;s calls these private deals with Raytheon “inappropriate.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, according to the CFO, there is no want to prioritize one country’s agenda over the other, and upset the DOD, where much of their business goes through. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Northrop-Gruman and L3 Harris Technologies announce Merger</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/northrop-gruman-and-l3-harris-technologies-announce-merger/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 18:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L3 Harris Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northrop Grumman Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Press Communique from Northrop G. Harris III: Northrop Grumman Corp is delighted to announce the publication of the merger with American technology company L3 Harris.&#160;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Press Communique from Northrop G. Harris III:</p>



<p>Northrop Grumman Corp is delighted to announce the publication of the merger with American technology company L3 Harris.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The merger of Northrop Grumman and L3 Harris will herald a new age of global arms cooperation in the service of expanding democracy. To this end, we will continue to support the United States Government in all of its endeavors, on land, across the seas, aerospace, cybersecurity, and the final frontier. The new company, now to be known as Northrop G. Harris III, intends to extend our diversified defense technologies to a truly global market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the world stage is always evolving, Northrop G. Harris III will be at the forefront of technology and innovation. We will be “fast and forward while redefining possible.” This merger is one combining two complementary companies that will allow us to offer stronger and more innovative technologies than ever before. Through the combination of revenue for two secure companies, our combined revenue is now the strongest on the market, with the highest quality of resources to be developed for this project. This merging will also allow us to create stronger, more effective products which will pressure other companies in the defense industry to improve their products as well, increasing competition. Additionally, effective leadership will allow us to move forward into the cybersecurity field, supporting the contracting needs of our clients in an evolving world.</p>



<p>Northrop G. Harris III intends to look towards governments for direction on the technologies and resources needed and will consistently support what is just. We will be “fast and forward while redefining possible” in achieving what’s best for global democracy and international cooperation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Signed,&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Executive Board of Northrop G. Harris III</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">168</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
