<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cabinet of South Korea &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2021/category/cabinet-of-south-korea/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:20:48 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>Whistleblower Reveals Chinese Secrets: Will the World go M.A.D.?</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/whistleblower-reveals-chinese-secrets-will-the-world-go-m-a-d/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Justin Wytmar, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In both North Korea and Iran, the situation is inching increasingly nearer to Mutually Assured Destruction (M.A.D.). China has publicly moved troops to the North]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In both North Korea and Iran, the situation is inching increasingly nearer to Mutually Assured Destruction (M.A.D.). China has publicly moved troops to the North Korean border after affirming the legitimacy of Choe Ryong Hae. The PRC is denouncing the rule of Kim Yo Jong, the de facto leader of the North Korean state, and has affirmed that &#8220;the best course of action is to engage militarily.&#8221; On Saturday, a Chinese whistleblower leaked further information to the New York Times.&nbsp;</p>



<p>China is actively using its military against the South Korean military at the North Korean Border. Additionally, the Chinese cabinet is making preparations to bomb Seoul with non-nuclear munitions. The whistleblower informed us that &#8220;the nuclear option was also brought up as a final straw.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Chinese have made plans for an attempted South Korean counter-invasion of China. Under the circumstance that South Korean forces cross the Chinese border, Beijing &#8220;will go nuclear.&#8221; A nuclear war cannot lead to a victory for any of the belligerents. To be as blunt as possible: This is not good.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The whistleblower asked the New York Times to print the following statement: &#8220;By leaking documents to publications like yours I am doing everything in my power to prevent the doomsday scenario and I hope that everyone in my cabinet does the same, even if this includes overthrowing Xi Jinping who has been a notorious warmonger in this situation.&#8221;</p>



<p>As the possibility of a bombing, coup, or nuclear war increases, the world holds their breath. The New York Times will continue to keep you updated as the situation develops.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">332</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>United States takes position on Korea</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/united-states-takes-position-on-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Isabella Rosinia, BuzzFeed News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:05:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since the announcement of Iran’s furthering of nuclear development, nations around the world have voiced their views on the situation.  Specifically, the Association of Southeast]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since the announcement of Iran’s furthering of nuclear development, nations around the world have voiced their views on the situation.  Specifically, the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) Committee had been discussing and negotiating situations similar to that of Iran.  During the interview with the Iranian leader, hinted that North Korea could pose a nuclear threat.  This notion has caused much panic among the international community.  </p>



<p>Buzzfeed was given the opportunity to interview Vice President of the United States, Kamala Harris, on the subject of North Korea.  Harris declared “The United States is giving military aid to the People’s Liberation Front of Korea and supporting our South Korean allies in the midst of this crisis, meaning that while we are not putting United States boots on the ground, we are giving the Liberation Front money so that they can fight for a free, fair, and democratic North Korea.  Above all, we are for the safety of innocent civilians, so if North Korea continues to push for nuclear development, we will obviously have to take military action, since we cannot let innocent lives be jeopardized.”  Based on the statement made by Harris, the United States is seeking peace and diplomacy with Korea.  However, the United States will not hesitate to use military force if the threat of nuclear action is presented.  While no one is sure of North Korea’s next steps, Buzzfeed will keep you updated with any action that occurs.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">323</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Korean tensions escalate with China and North Korea.</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/south-korean-tensions-escalate-with-china-and-north-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Zhang, The Korea Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 01:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=313</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Political and militaristic tensions have reached a breaking point as China and the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea face off against South Korea and its]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Political and militaristic tensions have reached a breaking point as China and the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea face off against South Korea and its allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Earlier today, China and Russia officially recognized Choe Ryong-hae, Kim Jong Un&#8217;s former Head of State.</p>



<p>South Korea, Japan, and India, backed by the United States, recognized the North Korean People&#8217;s Liberation Front (PLF) as the legitimate government of Korea. The PLF is a group of military defectors from North Korea that support the reunification of the Korean Peninsula. While political tensions rise, militaristic tensions follow. According to a recent leak, Chinese aircraft have fired upon South Korean soldiers at the 38th parallel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although the Cabinet of South Korea has not made action yet, action may be taken against The People’s Republic of China.&nbsp; After the recent encounter with China, it may be reasonable that the two countries will enter war against each other.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If war is to occur, nuclear arms may be involved. Foreshadowing this today, Iran released a statement that “western nations do not have power over other countries, like Iran and North Korea” after conducting a successful nuclear test. This may suggest that North Korea will go to extreme means if South Korea were to invade the DPRK.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>Whether the South Korean government will go to war is unknown, but tomorrow, the world will find out whether the tensions between China and the Korean peninsula will deescalate.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">313</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Nuking North Korea” would not affect South Korea “too much”: Singapore officials</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/nuking-north-korea-would-not-affect-south-korea-too-much-singapore-officials/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Zhang, The Korea Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Association of Southeast Asian Nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China and Laos have pushed for diplomatic solutions to solve dangerous nuclear instability within North Korea. A statement from the South Korean delegates has also]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>China and Laos have pushed for diplomatic solutions to solve dangerous nuclear instability within North Korea.</p>



<p>A statement from the South Korean delegates has also been released. “South Korea should maintain peace, until or unless threatened by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) [North Korea]. North Korea has continued to provoke the delegation of South Korea, and we would like to not act on a whim.”</p>



<p>The consensus is currently that continuing to be diplomatic is the best way to move forward. Still, some delegates oppose this.</p>



<p>‘Diplomatic action is not the best action” said the representative from Singapore Saturday evening.</p>



<p>The delegation from Singapore called for military pressure, believing that the European Union and the United States would support them.</p>



<p>“South Korea would not be affected too much, if we dropped one on (DPRK)” they reiterated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Clearly, some countries do not have civilians and general welfare in mind.&nbsp;</p>



<p>ASEAN will continue to achieve a resolution to bring peace to the world and the Korean peninsula.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">292</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Korean Government Recognizes Choi Jung-Hoon As Leader of North Korea</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/south-korean-government-recognizes-choi-jung-hoon-as-leader-of-north-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 22:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To our beloved people of South Korea and the esteemed citizens of the world,The Republic of Korea recognizes Choi Jung-Hoon of the North Korea People’s]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To our beloved people of South Korea and the esteemed citizens of the world,<br>The Republic of Korea recognizes Choi Jung-Hoon of the North Korea People’s Liberation Front as the rightful leader of North Korea. He has long been an advocate for democracy, freedom, and peace in North Korea, and is committed to denuclearization, cooperation, mutual prosperity, and most importantly, reunification. Choi Jung-Hoon was born in North Korea, and will be an upstanding leader for the long-oppressed masses of North Korea. Mr. Choi will be not just a new face to represent North Korea, but a new future: one where citizens are not starving, where they are not imprisoned for expressing their thoughts, where they are free to go where they want and be who they want to be. We look forward to negotiating with the next leader of North Korea, Choi Jung-Hoon, and bridging the gap between us.<br>&#8211; The Office of the President</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">239</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Statement from the Office of the President  of South Korea</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/a-statement-from-the-office-of-the-president-of-south-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At this time, the Office of the President is wary of the destabilization occurring in North Korea, and intends to prevent this destabilization from harming]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>At this time, the Office of the President is wary of the destabilization occurring in North Korea, and intends to prevent this destabilization from harming our citizens and residents in any way. We feel that peace is the best response to all potential crises at this time, and encourage our neighbors and allies to commit to peace on the Korean peninsula. We hope that North Korea is able to experience a peaceful transition of power to their next leader, and that we may work with whomever that leader may be to achieve denuclearization and reunification.</p>



<p>The Presidential Cabinet of the Republic of Korea has moved to increase our alert level from Jindogae 3 to Jindogae 2, and as a result, advise all citizens to report any signs of North Korean aggression at home to the police. Our citizens’ safety is our top priority, and as a result, we have decided to install joint military and police checkpoints around the country to ensure this safety. We encourage all residents to, as always, have knowledge of where their nearest bomb shelter lies, not because we believe that there is imminent internal conflict in North Korea that will lead to attacks on our soil, but because we must proceed with an abundance of caution, given the volatility of the situation. We encourage any members of the public to direct their questions to local government officials, who will answer any questions they can, and who will relay any other questions to Presidential Cabinet members.</p>



<p>We encourage all residents to remain calm at this time.</p>



<p>Signed,</p>



<p>The Office of the President</p>



<p></p>



<p>Should you have any questions regarding our recent press release, please direct them to the South Korean Home Government, who will then relay questions to the Prime Minister, the Minister of Foreign Affairs, and the Minister of Economy and Finance, as well as the cabinet at large, if requested. These questions may be answered in writing, but reporters may also request a video or voice conference. Please note that we cannot guarantee that all questions will be answered, regardless of relevancy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">227</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
