<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Miriam Israel, Buzzfeed &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/2022/author/misrael/feed/?simply_static_page=162" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2022</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 19:04:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cabinets and Committees as Disney Princesses</title>
		<link>/2022/cabinets-and-committees-as-disney-princesses/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miriam Israel, Buzzfeed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 18:59:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2022/?p=722</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Russia and Turkey embody the early stages of the Disney Princesses from the movie Frozen, Anna and Elsa. In Frozen, Anna sings Do You Want]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full" datatext=""><img decoding="async" width="300" height="168" src="/ipd-archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image-2.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-737"/></figure>



<p>Russia and Turkey embody the early stages of the Disney Princesses from the movie Frozen, Anna and Elsa. In Frozen, Anna sings <em>Do You Want To Build A Snowman</em>, one lyric in this song is &#8216;we used to be best buddies, and now we&#8217;re not&#8217;. This refers to Russia and Turkey being very good trading partners but then President Erdogan of Turkey screaming at Russia and asking them to take a, &#8220;Big fat L.&#8221; As you can see, Russia and Turkey are no longer best buddies.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image is-resized" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://i.quotev.com/2hrkwbbrdxcq.jpg" alt="Encanto One-shots!" width="234" height="234"/></figure>



<p>The World Health Organization can be seen in Encanto&#8217;s Isabella. When you first look at both of them, you think that there is nothing that could go wrong with them, no drama, nothing. Although, if you look inside and find their true selves, you see that there is actually quite a lot of inner drama. For Isabella, it was the cacti and for the WHO, it was the claims of espionage and racism.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="258" height="195" src="/ipd-archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image-3.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-745"/></figure>



<p>The US is like Sleeping Beauty because when they were not paying attention, similar to when Aurora was sleeping, their kingdom was invaded by outsiders. In the US cabinet, that example would be the Russians but in Sleeping Beauty, it was the thorns that took over her kingdom as she slept for 100 years.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="212" height="237" src="/ipd-archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image-4.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-750"/></figure>



<p>Finally, China is like Moana because in the movie of Moana, the main character broke several rules as she left her home island of Motunui. In the same way, China has broken several treaties by making the decision to nuke many other countries.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Watch what they do, not what they say.&#8221; US&#8217; doubt on Russia&#8217;s reputation</title>
		<link>/2022/watch-what-they-do-not-what-they-say-us-doubt-on-russias-reputation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miriam Israel, Buzzfeed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 23:26:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2022/?p=586</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Russia has made it clear that they are trying to increase the positivity that they put into their public image. The Russian Ambassador to the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="/ipd-archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/image.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-632" width="400" height="263"/></figure>



<p>Russia has made it clear that they are trying to increase the positivity that they put into their public image. The Russian Ambassador to the United States has stated, &#8220;The current view that Russia is the enemy is purely incorrect. We, as a country, are working incredibly hard to mediate and moderate the Belarusian and Bosnian crisis and this is just one way we want to show the world that we are not bad and that Russia can be a collaborative force&#8221;</p>



<p>Although, in a recent interview with the United States Secretary of Defense, it was made clear that the country of the US is very doubtful towards Russia&#8217;s so-called &#8216;improved global reputation&#8217;.</p>



<p>In the Secretary&#8217;s words exactly, &#8220;Watch what they do, not what they say,&#8221; she continues on, &#8220;Look at the past and see what they are doing now.&#8221;</p>



<p>Another source from within the US Cabinet also states that they are extremely ambivalent about Russia&#8217;s new global stance. They believe that Russia as an ally would be helpful but they too are concerned about Russia&#8217;s past actions and are unwilling to completely trust them. </p>



<p>With all this information, what do <em>you</em> think Russia&#8217;s real motive is?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WHO, Gates Foundation promote vaccine distribution in underdeveloped countries</title>
		<link>/2022/who-gates-foundation-promote-vaccine-distribution-in-underdeveloped-countries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miriam Israel, Buzzfeed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Health Organization (WHO)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2022/?p=617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Currently, Nigeria, Kenya, Paraguay, and Trinidad and Tobago are working together in the World Health Organization to create a resolution that would target the issue]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Currently, Nigeria, Kenya, Paraguay, and Trinidad and Tobago are working together in the World Health Organization to create a resolution that would target the issue of vaccine distribution within underdeveloped countries. After the EU passed over Nigeria for a grant that would have severely helped Nigeria create more vaccine manufacturing factories, the country decided to take matters into their own hands.</p>



<p>As the previously mentioned countries wait to hear back from the Bill and Melinda Gates foundation, their tentative sponsor, they have plans ready to be set in motion. These include the increase in the speed of the creation of current vaccine manufacturing and storage facilities that are being built in Kenya, more vaccine creation in these countries.</p>



<p>According to the Nigerian WHO delegate, “Nigeria would like to further the research toward its own COVID vaccine because we want to be more self-reliant and less at the whim of other countries,&#8221; according to the representative to WHO from Nigeria. This pandemic has made it known that we need to worry both about possible supply shortages and the current global enemy, the coronavirus.</p>



<p>As they move forward into committee session 3, this group is hopeful that their resolution will successfully pass. If it does indeed pass, these nations and their citizens will certainly thrive.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turkish Cabinet stalled on development programs</title>
		<link>/2022/turkish-cabinet-stalled-on-development-programs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miriam Israel, Buzzfeed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 17:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Cabinet of Turkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2022/?p=462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Turkish Minister of Energy and Natural Resources is attempting to pass an economic development plan similar to former U.S. President Roosevelt’s New Deal. Despite]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Turkish Minister of Energy and Natural Resources is attempting to pass an economic development plan similar to former U.S. President Roosevelt’s New Deal. Despite the ingenuity of this plan, which involves cleaning up waterways, limiting carbon emissions, and much more, she has been shut down as the council has focused mainly on military actions and classical economical solutions.</p>



<p>Simply put, these ministers are focusing on receiving monetary benefits in the short term, rather than focusing on long term advantage.</p>



<p>While the majority of Turkey’s Cabinet is searching for these ideas, the energy minister’s plan to promote the achievement of sustainable development goals within Turkey will also provide more jobs, thus stimulating its economic growth, which makes her plan all the more beneficial since it targets multiple points of interest. In the energy minister&#8217;s words, &#8220;I know this will work to stimulate the economy through increasing jobs, without increasing inflation because it has been done before,&#8221; she continues on, stating, &#8220;This solution will not only help solve the crises of Turkey’s Syrian refugees, climate change, and the economic downfall within Turkey, but it will also show other countries that Turkey wants to make a difference and that it cares about global issues.&#8221;</p>



<p>“If we want to no longer be treated as a laughing stock, we must look to tested, project-based plans that will make Turkey better for many years to come,&#8221; she continued. &#8220;Isn’t that the entire point of our work?”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
