<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cabinet of the United States &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/pd-committees/cabinet-of-the-united-states/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:56:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. cabinet: cry for action</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/u-s-cabinet-cry-for-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=651</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for pressuring China with the situation in Taiwan, and the proposal of possible sanctions which the UNSC is open to was discussed. </p>



<p>The U.S. cabinet currently already has ships in Japan for a diplomatic presence in the region, moving forward with sanctions they feel will be the most effective way Additionally, they feel that these harder sanctions will pressure China about their wrongdoings and have more international pressure about correcting their wrongs. </p>



<p>The representative from the UNSC had advised that there is a firm reason for these sanctions on China, and that the body does whatever they can in significance with their cause, supporting Taiwan. </p>



<p>Later on, in the press conference, the United States cabinet, madam Press Secretary had explained that the United States was shocked by China’s reaction to the call for a revote. The U.S. has time and time again reached out to the PRC yet has received no response, but the PRC was reported to barge into the U.S. cabinet&#8217;s closed session when it was “most convenient for them.” China’s sudden aggression within Taiwan now gives the U.S. reason to believe that there is heavy Chinese involvement, as their own social media platform, Tencent has also been explicitly spreading disinformation that directly influenced the results of the election. </p>



<p>The cabinet has also called upon the UNSC to help with the current issues within Taiwan, specifically the corruption seen within the election and the democracy impeded from within it. Additionally, they have coordinated asking for how the UNSC will choose to move forward with China’s actions as the U.S. government specifically will no longer be contacting the Chinese government due to the “disrespect of sanctity diplomacy.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>An intercepted source has also let us know that China is threatening the U.S. and threatening to get rid of some things that are unknown in regard to the U.S. The U.S. economy also is thriving and has no further need for China. </p>



<p>Furthermore, in an interview with UN Ambassador Linda Thomas Greenfield, “The U.S. is trying their best in order to help Taiwan as the United States has empathy for all and they are heavily focused on the economy to help our citizens. Alongside this, we are arranging a meeting with the U.S. delegation from the Security Council as their input is valuable.”</p>



<p>The response from the UNSC is still being awaited and more developments will continue as debate on the next steps to be taken continue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PRESS CONFERENCE: United States is Shocked China&#8217;s Actions</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/press-conference-united-states-is-shocked-chinas-actions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between the two countries. The U.S. representative has sensed some aggression from China, also shown through how they have allowed themselves to come into meetings with no prior conversation. </p>



<p>The United States has further commentary on the fact that China has said they do not want forgiven involvement at the moment because of any possible influence on their election. Yet, the United States mentioned how the Chinese app, Tencent,  is spreading misinformation and has directly influenced China’s election. Showing that even with no current foreign relations, there are still direct influences on their election via the country’s social media app. Was it really worth it to cut connections with other countries that have not had an influence when you country has had an influence first? </p>



<p>Due to the previous actions that China has taken, the United States feels that China is rejecting any possible diplomatic offers. Furthermore, the U.S. has called upon the United Nations Security Council to help deal with these issues in China and even Taiwan as it is going to be needed to keep international peace between countries. After coordinating with the U.S. Security Council representative, the U.S. is urging the most powerful peacekeeping body in the world to help to deal with China’s actions as quickly and as effectively as possible. Now, the United States will no longer be in contact with the China government because of all the previously mentioned issues and that they have disrespected diplomacy. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X is Getting Sued? What Will Happen Now?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/x-is-getting-sued-what-will-happen-now/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[X Corporation, owner of the social media platform formerly known as Twitter and currently developing X-Connect, is currently being sued by the U.S. government. They]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>X Corporation, owner of the social media platform formerly known as Twitter and currently developing X-Connect, is currently being sued by the U.S. government. They say they have nothing to hide, but, if they have nothing to hide, what is the real reason for them getting sued? The X representative said that they have not had government involvement because of the issues that are surrounded with it, but they are not involved and are having issues with that same government. </p>



<p>They say that they are still committed to the development of the X-Connect app while following regulations and focusing on innovations even after this information of them being sued. After a U.S. cabinet meeting in which an A.I. implication was brought up, the U.S. government and X each threatened to sue the other entity. So they say that they have no government relations, yet still talk to the U.S. cabinet? That is directly going against what the X representative said they were doing. How are you able to go against your own words?</p>



<p>Even though they are receiving an abundance of backlash and are in the midst of getting sued, X Corporation is still attempting to further develop their app. Which also raises the question, will that affect the amount of users that will use their X-Connect app? They have said that they are going to continue to control their app because they have trust in their own systems, and as of now have no further comment on the situation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNSC: Disappointment Over Veto</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/unsc-disappointment-over-veto/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UN Security Council is facing debates over the humanitarian aid paper as China has used its veto power and has vetoed the idea of]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The UN Security Council is facing debates over the humanitarian aid paper as China has used its veto power and has vetoed the idea of humanitarian aid for the Russia-Ukraine war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The sole purpose of this paper was to help both sides in the conflict, as seen in the proposed paper, by being able to have equal sponsors and aid sent on both sides for the reason of basic human equality. It was supposed to help the millions of civilians living in distress, which now seems a hard goal to reach. </p>



<p>The United States has had very strong opinions regarding this situation as they do not support the use of the veto. The United States is against China’s veto in the humanitarian aid paper as there was perhaps no true basis for China to use its powers. It is also important to note that this humanitarian aid paper was supported by the Russian Federation. </p>



<p>In an interview with the United States, they expressed their deep disappointment, saying, “humanitarian aid was crucial, and support for both eastern and western powers was on this paper. It is disappointing that China has used its veto powers.” </p>



<p>Changes occur rapidly within this conflict and the UNSC’s debate only further stretches out the future of this nation. </p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The U.S. Cabinet: CALL FOR A REVOTE</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/the-u-s-cabinet-call-for-a-revote/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Historically speaking, the Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) in Taiwan has been known as the party that takes a Taiwanese nationalist position, advocating for strengthening Taiwanese]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Historically speaking, the Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) in Taiwan has been known as the party that takes a Taiwanese nationalist position, advocating for strengthening Taiwanese identity. This government has been leading and helping Taiwan with creating and enacting new developments. </p>



<p>Despite their increased efforts, in the most recent election in Taiwan, the KMT, a Chinese Nationalist Party, won. The consequences of this were the fact that the people regretted their decision and this is causing violent riots within Taiwan. The U.S. continued to investigate this matter further. Simultaneously, the People&#8217;s Republic of China made statements saying how they are all for democracy, and democracy has spoken. </p>



<p>This caused quite a stir within U.S. government, as there were talks of impeachment from the Republican party as they felt no proper measures were being taken. This stir took quite some time to settle down, but once it did, the U.S. made the firm decision of calling for a reflection in Taiwan. </p>



<p>The effects of this re-election on the people of Taiwan, and what is held for the future of Taiwan have not yet been discussed publicly. The U.S. has not made any further statements and more developments are to come. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Cabinet: Actions Regarding Ukraine</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/u-s-cabinet-actions-regarding-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=467</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the U.S. Cabinet, discussions dive deeper regarding the Russia-Ukraine war and how humanitarian aid seems to be the most crucial part of resolution. Alongside]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the U.S. Cabinet, discussions dive deeper regarding the Russia-Ukraine war and how humanitarian aid seems to be the most crucial part of resolution. Alongside this, expanding food security along other necessities for living seem to be another critical point. </p>



<p>Ambassador to the UN, Linda Thomas Greenfield, proposes brining in the Secretary of Energy to help with the heating and lighting in Ukraine which is heavily supported by many others such as the CIA who stresses the importance of humanitarian aid rather than militia aid. </p>



<p>The goal of the Cabinet is to protect as many people in the international community as possible. There were talks and debates over an operation in order to sway public opinion, however, Russia does not require the validation of any others to motivate or demotivate. There appears to be consensus regarding Russia being in the wrong not only on the basis of this War, but also mentioned by one cabinet member possible Neo-Nazi and Anarchists groups operating with Russia and the relation with this to past acts of violence. </p>



<p>This led to a possible solution regarding self-reliant measures in Ukraine rather than constant exports with the help of an economic team, in the hopes to make Ukraine more independent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nothing is agreed upon so far, but solutions and debates continue as the situation further advanced rapidly. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Can Climate Change be Stopped?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/how-can-climate-change-be-stopped/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Climate change is not a new problem. It&#8217;s been an ever-growing issue since back in 1988 with the depletion of the ozone layer. It has]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Climate change is not a new problem. It&#8217;s been an ever-growing issue since back in 1988 with the depletion of the ozone layer. It has continued to grow and has had lasting effects on the economy. Some of these effects can be seen through unbalances in weather, and the increase in temperatures throughout the years.</p>



<p>These increasing temperatures have also affected the production of food, which has had an increase in hunger and a decrease in nutrition. Heat can diminish water, which also can lead to droughts, which are creating more deserts and people are facing threats of not having enough water. Along with the talk of water, these temperatures can affect the amount of rainfall, increasing the frequency of storms, landslides, and destroying homes, which is costing billions of dollars to repair. Along with that, climate change is making ice sheets melt, which is making the ocean levels rise, which can be threatening to islands and communities on those islands. </p>



<p>A representative from India shared, “Holding countries accountable and allocating our resources and funds towards combating climate change.” Most countries have their own contributions to climate change, but holding them accountable can help stop this threatening issue. </p>



<p>“All of us have established a climate goal and not all of us are meeting it. That’s an issue.”, the representative from India mentioned. Most countries have brought up the issue of climate change, it is whether or not they actually exceed the standards to actually attempt to stop climate change. </p>



<p>“Seeing why they can’t meet their goals and giving them resources to allow them too,” which was also mentioned by the delegate from India. India is willing to help and wants to make sure that countries, even their own country, has the needed resources to put a stop on climate change. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>War in Ukraine: Viewpoint from the United States</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/war-in-ukraine-viewpoint-from-the-united-states/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The tensions that exist between Ukraine and Russia are far from new. It is something that has existed for many years now, some dating back]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The tensions that exist between Ukraine and Russia are far from new. It is something that has existed for many years now, some dating back to 2014; almost a decade ago. Since then, as of February of 2022, Russia has sent many troops to go and invade Ukraine. Since that time, many civilians have died, mass destruction has occurred, and the continuous attacks do not seem to be dying down. </p>



<p>Many European countries are attempting to help Ukraine and the Ukrainian people, but the United States has also had their fair share of involvement. Including their attempts to provide aid, and spread information about the topic at hand. But, with the information at hand which has been covered by other media outlets, with the U.S. President Joe Biden, as well as coverage seen from the Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy. There have been some issues within the United States regarding the spread of misinformation of the issues that have been going on during this conflict between Russia and Ukraine. </p>



<p>The big picture is “the mass amount of disinformation being spread,” which the United States press secretary commented on, and also commented that, “The United States has been working on a solution.” </p>



<p>There was not much to comment on about what the actual solution is that is being worked on currently. This would attempt to stop the spread of misinformation, further allowing the advancement of support for Ukraine, which can be done with truthful information being put out for the public. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Liveblog (Present Day)</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/friday-liveblog-present-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael McCarthy, Deputy USG for Media]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Treasury Secretary Yellen pledges continued US support to Ukraine</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/07/treasury-secretary-yellen-promotes-continued-us-support-to-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 06:00:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=108</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Foreign aggression is a concerning issue today in the U.S. and bolstering American influence is a topic of exigence brought to the attention of the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Foreign aggression is a concerning issue today in the U.S. and bolstering American influence is a topic of exigence brought to the attention of the U.S. cabinet. The abiding consequences of the ongoing Russia-Ukraine War has led to fluctuation in the U.S. economy which concerns itself as an issue in the long term. The U.S. cabinet will take on this matter for possible resolution to ongoing conflicts affecting the economy and U.S. influence.</p>



<p>Treasury secretary Janet Yellen plays an influential financial role in the direct control of U.S. monetary policy. “When it comes to foreign conflicts, I firmly believe in continued U.S. financial support of Ukraine against Russian aggression,&#8221; Yellen said. &#8220;However, this comes with many risks and I plan on implementing significant regulation and protocols in order to prevent abuse of this emerging sector.” </p>



<p>With the issue at hand, Yellen plays a key role in the resolution of this international conflict, and who desires peace that potentially invokes advancements in the U.S. to a higher technologically advanced position within the international community.</p>



<p>As a whole the cabinet strives to achieve democracy and personal freedom as an outcome of this resolution. While Yellen could not comment on everything the cabinet may or may not do, she directs that there is a clear focus on economic support towards Ukraine and does not have military-related plans against Russia. Momentary outcomes would be not to pursue trade aggression with foreign adversaries such as China and look inward to adjust American government agencies as well as modify tax policy in order to raise revenue for our future plans. Ideally as a long term resolution they want to come out of this with peace both foreign and domestically, provide Americans with a bright future and strengthen their personal wealth as well as promote innovation and American private enterprise.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
