<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ruchi Akula, Assistant Editor &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/archive/2022/author/rakula/feed/?simply_static_page=169" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2022</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 18:01:29 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The Nightcap Episode 3</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/the-nightcap-episode-3/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruchi Akula, Assistant Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 17:55:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=706</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-audio" datatext=""><audio controls src="https://model-un.github.io/ipd-archive/assets/CIMUN-Podcast-5.mp3"></audio></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large" datatext=""><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="512" src="/ipd-archive/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-2-1024x512.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-714" srcset="/ipd-archive/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-2-1024x512.jpg 1024w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-2-300x150.jpg 300w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-2-768x384.jpg 768w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-2-1536x768.jpg 1536w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-2.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WMUN – CIMUN News Radio Episode 2</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/wmun-cimun-news-radio-episode-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruchi Akula, Assistant Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speaker 1 0:06You’re Listening to WMUN- CIMUN News Radio This news update has been brought to you by the Duck and Cover! Parents, make sure]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-audio" datatext=""><audio controls src="/ipd-archive/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/CIMUN-Podcast-4.mp3"></audio></figure>



<p><strong>Speaker 1 0:06</strong><br>You’re Listening to WMUN- CIMUN News Radio</p>



<p>This news update has been brought to you by the Duck and Cover!</p>



<p>Parents, make sure to teach your children the importance of Duck and Cover! In the event of total nuclear annihilation, you can trust that a school desk will keep your children safe from falling debris, right before they are vaporized! That’s right, in the event of an atomic detonation, get under the nearest piece of furniture and brace for the force of the sun in your backyard!</p>



<p>The New York Times received a transcript of an emergency military budget proposal president Truman sent to the senate in response to the growing red menace. The president requested that the Senate immediately approve a 100% increase in military spending in an effort to strengthen the military in response to the growing communist threat. But the senate rebuked the president, only approving a 75% increase.</p>



<p><strong>Speaker 2 1:03</strong><br>The senate has also approved a bill addressing the Korean conflict. It calls for armed neutrality, and approved funds for arming South Korea, as well as funds for humanitarian aid to displaced Korean citizens.</p>



<p>The New York Times is also reporting that an unnamed Chinese official has called for moving Chinese troops away from the Korean border due to health concerns.</p>



<p>Finally, the Chicago Tribune is reporting that the Red Scare is gripping the United States. The United States Representative to the UN Security council warned other countries the dangers of the so-called Domino Effect of countries falling to communism. U.S. Senator McCarthy has reportedly collected a list of more than 200 communists within the U.S., while others such as Senator Murray, caution against using this list without proper verification.</p>



<p><strong>Speaker 1 1:41</strong><br>This has been your NEWS on the Hour. Stay tuned to WMUN- CIMUN News Radio</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Nightcap Episode 2</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/the-nightcap-episode-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruchi Akula, Assistant Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=596</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speaker 1 0:07Welcome back to the Nightcap, brought to you by the CIMUN Chronicle. Today’s World News Roundtable is brought to you by NFTs. For]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-audio" datatext=""><audio controls src="/ipd-archive/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/CIMUN-Podcast-3.mp3"></audio></figure>



<p><strong>Speaker 1 0:07</strong><br>Welcome back to the Nightcap, brought to you by the CIMUN Chronicle.</p>



<p>Today’s World News Roundtable is brought to you by NFTs. For just a few hundred thousand dollars, you can buy a JPEG of an ape with a hat! How does it work you might ask? Simply buy an NFT, then get others to buy NFTs, thus increasing your ape’s value! How do you make money? Once enough people buy NFTs, you can cash out! Imagine a pyramid… uh I mean reverse funnel… of people buying cartoon apes, the more people under you, the more money you make! NFTs, Definitely not a pyramid Scheme. <em>results may vary</em></p>



<p><strong>Speaker 2 0:10</strong><br>Belarusian President Aleksandr Lukashenko released a statement saying that Russia has “spit in our face by unilaterally declaring territory in our country belongs to you,” He also declared that he will block Russia’s efforts to withdraw refugees from the border, and will reconsider their relationship with Russia.</p>



<p>In response, the Russian government released a statement apologizing for not consulting with Lukashenko before taking action involving the Iraqi kurds. Russia emphasized the importance of their relationship with Belarus, and cited their long standing cooperation, dating back to the time of the Soviet Union. Russia also cited the importance of their pipeline sovereignty, and indicated that they hope that Belarus will continue to be a partner on this project.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, President Biden put out a statement regarding his recent talks with Chinese President Xi. He accused the Chinese president of acting undiplomatically, and aggressively. He also called out the Chinese for reportedly launching cyber attacks on the US. He also called out the recent arrest of Bosnian Journalists, and called for freedom of the press to be respected. Milorad Dodik has arrested 7 Bosnian journalists who have been critical of his actions thus far.</p>



<p><strong>Speaker 3 1:45</strong><br>Buzzfeed is reporting The Turkish Minister of Energy and Natural Resources is attempting to pass an economic development plan similar to the former U.S. President Roosevelt’s New Deal. However, these efforts have stalled, as the council has focused mainly on military actions and classical economic sanctions.</p>



<p>As reported in the Sunday Times of South Africa, the United Nations Security council has been working on addressing the ongoing Tigray Conflict in Ethiopia. The United States has pledged to work with other nations in giving humanitarian aid to the region.</p>



<p>Finally, The U.S government has lost interest in Pfizer&#8217;s bioweapon in favor of the Defense Leadership Foundation&#8217;s new Nuclear Space Station. Pfizer&#8217;s stock has plummeted and been delisted from the NYSE; all balance sheets are inaccessible and the Gates Foundation has lost all hope of recovering losses</p>



<p><strong>Speaker 1 2:34</strong><br>Thank you for joining us tonight on the Nightcap, brought to you by the CIMUN Chronicle.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WMUN &#8211; CIMUN News Radio Episode 1</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/wmun-cimun-news-radio-episode-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruchi Akula, Assistant Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 17:14:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=463</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[TRANSCRIPT: Speaker 1 0:07 You’re listening to WMUN - CIMUN News Radio. Here is your news at the top of the hour. AD 0:13 This]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-audio" datatext=""><audio controls src="/ipd-archive/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/CIMUN-Podcast-Episode-2.mp3"></audio></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="602" src="/ipd-archive/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Chicago_skyline_74255_cropped-1024x602.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-472" srcset="/ipd-archive/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Chicago_skyline_74255_cropped-1024x602.jpg 1024w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Chicago_skyline_74255_cropped-300x176.jpg 300w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Chicago_skyline_74255_cropped-768x452.jpg 768w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Chicago_skyline_74255_cropped-1536x904.jpg 1536w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/Chicago_skyline_74255_cropped-2048x1205.jpg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">TRANSCRIPT:</span></strong>

<strong>Speaker 1  0:07  </strong>
You’re listening to WMUN - CIMUN News Radio. Here is your news at the top of the hour. 

<strong>AD  0:13 </strong> 
This news update has been brought to you by SUBURBS. The Suburbs: Are you tired of living in crowded cities? Do you want to live the AMERICAN DREAM? Do you want to have a house with a white picket fence and 2 kids and a dog? Of course you do, you’re a true-blooded American after all. The American Dream is here. Move to the Suburbs! *RESTRICTIONS APPLY*
  

<strong>Speaker 2  0:27 </strong> 
In Washington, the Senate has been in debate over the situation on the Korean Peninsula. Senators have to consider if they should authorize President Truman to deploy military and financial assistance to the South Korean Government. 

The New York Times is reporting that “Some Senators are considering lethal force in response to the threat of the USSR and North Korea”. One Senator, on the condition of anonymity, said that the move would involve striking North Korea and Russia with “such 
 force that they cannot respond”. More developments as they come
. 

<strong>
Speaker 1  0:52 </strong> 
Meanwhile, President Truman and his cabinet have met with Republic of Korea president Syngman Rhee. We expect an official statement soon. 

In New York, the United Nations Security Council is debating on whether they should take proactive measures on the Korean peninsula. Western nations favor these measures while the Eastern bloc has opposed international intervention. More updates will come as they are available.

<strong>
Speaker 3  1:15  </strong>
The Soviets have met with Mao Zedong of China and Kim Il-Sung of North Korea, in a summit of socialist powers in Asia, and discussed the situation on the Korean Peninsula and how to “Foster a region safe for Communism,”

Furthermore, Joseph Stalin has discussed how to protect and proliferate communism around the globe.

Meanwhile, Mao Zedong and the People’s Republic of China have discussed how to expand the influence of communism into traditionally Chinese areas.
 

Kim Il-Sung has discussed protecting the security and stability of the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea, as well as how to best prevent the Western Threat.
 

<strong>Speaker 1  1:53  </strong>
This has been your NEWS on the Hour. Stay tuned to WMUN- CIMUN News Radio
 


</pre>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Nightcap Episode 1</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/the-nightcap-episode-1/</link>
		"/ipd-archive/archive
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruchi Akula, Assistant Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 15:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>"/ipd-archive/archive"/ipd-archive/archive
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Transcript: Speaker 1 0:00 Hey everyone, welcome to The Nightcap, brought to you by The CIMUN Chronicle. Moving on to world headlines, a fistfight broke]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-audio" datatext=""><audio controls src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/CIMUN-Podcast-1-2022.mp3"></audio></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="512" src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-1024x512.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-446" srcset="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-1024x512.jpg 1024w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-300x150.jpg 300w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-768x384.jpg 768w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-1536x768.jpg 1536w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p></p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Transcript:</span></strong>

<strong>Speaker 1  0:00 </strong> 
Hey everyone, welcome to The Nightcap, brought to you by The CIMUN Chronicle. 

Moving on to world headlines, a fistfight broke out at the border between Greece and Turkey on the partitioned island of Cyprus. Officials claim that Greek nationals protesting against Turkish companies drilling for oil have crossed the UN-enforced green line separating the island,  instigated by civilians, and set fire to dozens of buildings. They were detained and sent back across the green line. Dozens of injuries have been reported but nobody has been killed. 

In other news, some Turkish officials are becoming increasingly frustrated with President Erdogan. According to one anonymous minister,  "he's [Erdogan] not very effective and "he's not taking necessary steps to keep turkey stable". 

President Erdogan has fired the president of the Turkish Central Bank for his failure to stop the fall the Lira.

<strong>Speaker 2  0:42  </strong>
CIA reported the discovery of intercontinental ballistic missiles in the Gansu province of China, while Pentagon officials report China is rapidly increasing its capacity to develop nuclear warheads. 

Top Taiwanese Officials say, "Pooh Bear got crushed by a building" in reference to President Xi causing outrage on mainland China. 

The Wall Street Journal is reporting that President Xi made it very clear that he was upset and  "wants Taiwan to suffer".

<strong>Speaker 3  1:09 </strong> 
A Chinese national was reportedly injured in an accident at the Port of Hamburg in Germany. German-Chinese relations have been strained since Germany criticized China's human rights violations and Hong Kong's 2020 National Security Law. 

The Chinese national, Wang Xianwen, a Cargo Manager, and father of three is reportedly in critical condition. 

The times of South Africa's reporting that the UN Security Council is asking Russia to stop selling weapons to Ethiopia because of the worsening Tigray conflict. 

Similarly, Buzzfeed is reporting that several Russian officials have claimed that "NATO has been discriminating against Russia because NATO was created in a way that would end up turning certain countries against Russia and making them seem like an antagonist when they are not always the enemy. 

<strong>Speaker 1  1:56 </strong> 
And that's gonna do it for us today at the nightcap. Thank you all for joining us and we'll see you again tomorrow!

</pre>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
<br />
<b>Notice</b>:  ob_end_flush(): failed to send buffer of zlib output compression (0) in <b>/home/public/news/wp-includes/functions.php</b> on line <b>5279</b><br />
