<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Richa Sharma, Times of India &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/author/rsharma/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 04:47:40 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The U.S. Senate: Senator William Proxmire Sepaks on Behalf of the Senate</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/10/the-u-s-senate-senator-william-proxmire-sepaks-on-behalf-of-the-senate-ready-for-edit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 16:04:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the most recent press conference, Sen. Proxmire represented the U.S. Senate and started with his condolences for the loss of Eleanor Roosevelt. He continued]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the most recent press conference, Sen. Proxmire represented the U.S. Senate and started with his condolences for the loss of Eleanor Roosevelt. He continued to express that as they dealt with the Cuban Missile Crisis, they felt that it was important to discuss the civil rights issue within the nation, specifically women’s rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>In an interview with Senator Proxmire, he stated many things not only on behalf of himself, but speaking overall for the U.S. Senate.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The Cuban missile crisis has impacted many and caused chaos, and the U.S. Senate reassures their unity and doing “not only what is in our best interest, but in the best interest of the American people.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Senate attempted solutions to help de-escalate the situation in Cuba, and at the same time protect the U.S. and its public as a whole, ensuring the safety of all Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the topic of the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women, Sen. Proxmire said, “we understand women’s rights and civil rights are an issue that requires prioritization, and they are the most important thing to the Senate. Currently, we are working on solutions to try and implement more education, as well as other social reforms which are in the process.” </p>



<p><strong>“As a senator that wants every American to know the truth, I wish all of you to know that we are trying to do the best for all American people, and I acknowledge the discontent with us, but rest assured we are using our power to ensure the happiness and great state of the U.S.A.”</strong></p>



<p>Overall not only as a senator, but a representative of our government, Sen. Proxmire and the rest of the U.S. Senate want the American people to rest assured knowing they are working on solutions to help with women’s rights, civil rights, and the overall safety of the nation, which will further unveil as debates and bills continue to develop. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. cabinet: cry for action</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/u-s-cabinet-cry-for-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=651</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for pressuring China with the situation in Taiwan, and the proposal of possible sanctions which the UNSC is open to was discussed. </p>



<p>The U.S. cabinet currently already has ships in Japan for a diplomatic presence in the region, moving forward with sanctions they feel will be the most effective way Additionally, they feel that these harder sanctions will pressure China about their wrongdoings and have more international pressure about correcting their wrongs. </p>



<p>The representative from the UNSC had advised that there is a firm reason for these sanctions on China, and that the body does whatever they can in significance with their cause, supporting Taiwan. </p>



<p>Later on, in the press conference, the United States cabinet, madam Press Secretary had explained that the United States was shocked by China’s reaction to the call for a revote. The U.S. has time and time again reached out to the PRC yet has received no response, but the PRC was reported to barge into the U.S. cabinet&#8217;s closed session when it was “most convenient for them.” China’s sudden aggression within Taiwan now gives the U.S. reason to believe that there is heavy Chinese involvement, as their own social media platform, Tencent has also been explicitly spreading disinformation that directly influenced the results of the election. </p>



<p>The cabinet has also called upon the UNSC to help with the current issues within Taiwan, specifically the corruption seen within the election and the democracy impeded from within it. Additionally, they have coordinated asking for how the UNSC will choose to move forward with China’s actions as the U.S. government specifically will no longer be contacting the Chinese government due to the “disrespect of sanctity diplomacy.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>An intercepted source has also let us know that China is threatening the U.S. and threatening to get rid of some things that are unknown in regard to the U.S. The U.S. economy also is thriving and has no further need for China. </p>



<p>Furthermore, in an interview with UN Ambassador Linda Thomas Greenfield, “The U.S. is trying their best in order to help Taiwan as the United States has empathy for all and they are heavily focused on the economy to help our citizens. Alongside this, we are arranging a meeting with the U.S. delegation from the Security Council as their input is valuable.”</p>



<p>The response from the UNSC is still being awaited and more developments will continue as debate on the next steps to be taken continue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Sen. James Pearson expresses his disappointment</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/u-s-sen-james-pearson-expresses-his-disappointment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=556</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Senate has officially passed many resolutions regarding the Cuban Missile Crisis, including plans regarding the U.S. Presidential Cabinet.&#160; With this, one of the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. Senate has officially passed many resolutions regarding the Cuban Missile Crisis, including plans regarding the U.S. Presidential Cabinet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With this, one of the papers not passed was the RULE paper, sponsored in part by Republican Sen. James Pearson from Kansas. This paper essentially planned on making sure that the executive branch would inform Congress of any military action to keep Congress updated and they would be able to move forward or not with the actions after 30 days. Sen. Pearson was disheartened and shared his sentiments on this matter by expressing how he felt strongly regarding the resolutions passed, as well as his resolution. </p>



<p>In an interview with Sen. Pearson, he expressed how “the cabinet has not been informing the senate of practically anything that has been going on with Cuba.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Regarding the failure of his paper he has stated the reason behind this is due to “a few people who were very much like ‘this is too much bureaucracy, this is raising tensions between the executive and legislative branch.'&#8221; </p>



<p>He further explained how the reasons for not passing his paper seem hypocritical due to his fellow senators having a similar resolution where the president would be in power for no more than 30 days with the military to protect the country. </p>



<p>He finished by explaining how “this is just quite frankly ridiculous that the senate passed this because again, it just increases tensions between the executive and legislative branch” and how on day 31 of a conflict, “we are out of luck.”  Even after coming up with solutions, they do not seem to be solving the issue at hand, but rather creating possible internal resentment within the senate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNSC: Disappointment Over Veto</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/unsc-disappointment-over-veto/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UN Security Council is facing debates over the humanitarian aid paper as China has used its veto power and has vetoed the idea of]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The UN Security Council is facing debates over the humanitarian aid paper as China has used its veto power and has vetoed the idea of humanitarian aid for the Russia-Ukraine war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The sole purpose of this paper was to help both sides in the conflict, as seen in the proposed paper, by being able to have equal sponsors and aid sent on both sides for the reason of basic human equality. It was supposed to help the millions of civilians living in distress, which now seems a hard goal to reach. </p>



<p>The United States has had very strong opinions regarding this situation as they do not support the use of the veto. The United States is against China’s veto in the humanitarian aid paper as there was perhaps no true basis for China to use its powers. It is also important to note that this humanitarian aid paper was supported by the Russian Federation. </p>



<p>In an interview with the United States, they expressed their deep disappointment, saying, “humanitarian aid was crucial, and support for both eastern and western powers was on this paper. It is disappointing that China has used its veto powers.” </p>



<p>Changes occur rapidly within this conflict and the UNSC’s debate only further stretches out the future of this nation. </p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The U.S. Cabinet: CALL FOR A REVOTE</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/the-u-s-cabinet-call-for-a-revote/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Historically speaking, the Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) in Taiwan has been known as the party that takes a Taiwanese nationalist position, advocating for strengthening Taiwanese]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Historically speaking, the Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) in Taiwan has been known as the party that takes a Taiwanese nationalist position, advocating for strengthening Taiwanese identity. This government has been leading and helping Taiwan with creating and enacting new developments. </p>



<p>Despite their increased efforts, in the most recent election in Taiwan, the KMT, a Chinese Nationalist Party, won. The consequences of this were the fact that the people regretted their decision and this is causing violent riots within Taiwan. The U.S. continued to investigate this matter further. Simultaneously, the People&#8217;s Republic of China made statements saying how they are all for democracy, and democracy has spoken. </p>



<p>This caused quite a stir within U.S. government, as there were talks of impeachment from the Republican party as they felt no proper measures were being taken. This stir took quite some time to settle down, but once it did, the U.S. made the firm decision of calling for a reflection in Taiwan. </p>



<p>The effects of this re-election on the people of Taiwan, and what is held for the future of Taiwan have not yet been discussed publicly. The U.S. has not made any further statements and more developments are to come. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNGA: Finally solving climate change</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/unga-finally-solving-climate-change/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 08:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the main policy-making hub of the United Nations, regarding the ever-growing problem of Climate Change, India recognizes its issues with struggling to get to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the main policy-making hub of the United Nations, regarding the ever-growing problem of Climate Change, India recognizes its issues with struggling to get to net zero emissions. India is the third largest contributor of greenhouse gasses and realizes the impacts of climate change on its people and is hoping to combat this through what the representative said were “accountability solutions and trying to allocate resources from different countries.” </p>



<p>As the committee finally begins to pass its resolutions, we see plans such as focuses on sustainability through technological development, and deforestation. In particular, the Green Deal Action Plan which is using innovative technology such as floor tiles which as they are walked on create kinetic energy. They plan on obtaining funding from developed countries as well as NGOs. They are ambitious that they will be able to help the people in countries facing deforestation as their economies heavily depend on activities such as logging and others related to deforestation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite these ideas for combating climate change, overall the committee struggles with merging and coming up with solid solutions that would be able to pertain to everyone, especially both developed and underdeveloped countries.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Cabinet: Actions Regarding Ukraine</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/u-s-cabinet-actions-regarding-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:59:33 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=467</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the U.S. Cabinet, discussions dive deeper regarding the Russia-Ukraine war and how humanitarian aid seems to be the most crucial part of resolution. Alongside]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the U.S. Cabinet, discussions dive deeper regarding the Russia-Ukraine war and how humanitarian aid seems to be the most crucial part of resolution. Alongside this, expanding food security along other necessities for living seem to be another critical point. </p>



<p>Ambassador to the UN, Linda Thomas Greenfield, proposes brining in the Secretary of Energy to help with the heating and lighting in Ukraine which is heavily supported by many others such as the CIA who stresses the importance of humanitarian aid rather than militia aid. </p>



<p>The goal of the Cabinet is to protect as many people in the international community as possible. There were talks and debates over an operation in order to sway public opinion, however, Russia does not require the validation of any others to motivate or demotivate. There appears to be consensus regarding Russia being in the wrong not only on the basis of this War, but also mentioned by one cabinet member possible Neo-Nazi and Anarchists groups operating with Russia and the relation with this to past acts of violence. </p>



<p>This led to a possible solution regarding self-reliant measures in Ukraine rather than constant exports with the help of an economic team, in the hopes to make Ukraine more independent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Nothing is agreed upon so far, but solutions and debates continue as the situation further advanced rapidly. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PRESS RELEASE: Cabinet of the People&#8217;s Republic of China regarding Solving The Issues of the Dalai Lama’s Disappearance- ready for edit</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-cabinet-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china-regarding-solving-the-issues-of-the-dalai-lamas-disappearance-ready-for-edit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:33:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=446</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Dawn and Times of India In a brief press release with the Cabinet of the Peoples Republic of China, they have made a statement]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><em>The Dawn and Times of India</em></p>



<p>In a brief press release with the Cabinet of the Peoples Republic of China, they have made a statement regarding Dalai Lama;</p>



<p>&#8220;The disappearance of the Dalai Lama is concerning and China believes that the people will who are responsible must be held accountable. When The Dalai Lama was living in China, he was safe and sound, protected by The People’s Republic of China. After leaving China, he disappeared. China finds this very concerning. China is not in any way involved with the disappearance and will work with the rest of the international community to investigate the issue.”    <br><br>Could there be an underlying message behind this statement? Only time will tell as this matter further advances. </p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ELEANOR ROOSEVELT DEAD</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/eleanor-roosevelt-dead/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women: The Head Chairman, an important, influential woman who was a friend to many, Eleanor Roosevelt was abruptly injured.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Presidential Commission on the Status of Women: The Head Chairman, an important, influential woman who was a friend to many, Eleanor Roosevelt was abruptly injured. It was later informed that Miss Rosevelt has passed away, due to the impact of a letter, more information to come soon!!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>India Refutes China</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/india-refutes-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:03:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=402</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The current conflict between China and India is escalating, especially at the recent press conference. India has explained how they are a powerful and growing]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The current conflict between China and India is escalating, especially at the recent press conference. India has explained how they are a powerful and growing especially in the economic pact, and they will not be backing down from their “‘wonderful power.” Furthermore they have stated that they have no alliances and will be using all their power and whatever it takes to maintain their borders. </p>



<p>Similarly, a representative from China has stated that they are strong, united, and growing. China holds a lot of empathy for its neighbors and on the topic of the war, they have said that India is wrongly claiming Chinese territory and have called out Nehru on lying about their alliances with the USSR as they have been meeting time and time again with Nikita Khrushchev. Additionally, they have stated that some Indian Ministers may have communist sympathies. </p>



<p>In specific response to the current conflicts between India and China, India has a message for its members of the non-alignment pact. They confirm that this pact is still on, and still happening, and that they have no sort of association with the USSR nor any other associations as they wish to solely focus on themselves. </p>



<p>Additionally, India&#8217;s response to the leaked pictures of their ministers is one; that they do not accept these pictures. They have strongly stated the fact that these pictures were unsolicited and no prior consent was asked. Along with this is the fact that they were abruptly caught off guard when they were attacked by these individuals taking photos, leaving them utterly confused. Continuing on the topic of attacks, the Minister of Finance has made a declaration that he was attacked by a delegate from China. </p>



<p>India feels strongly about avoiding any sort of violence or war and acknowledges the fact that they have tried to negotiate and have peace talks and have given China multiple opportunities, however this has been met with ignorance.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Due to the fact that China wishes nothing to have nothing to do with India, India feels that it is in their best interests to not be involved in any way. They wish to solely focus on themselves and be able to develop themselves due to their recent independence. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
