<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>United Nations General Assembly Plenary &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/pd-committees/united-nations-general-assembly-plenary/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:26:32 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>UNGA: Finally solving climate change</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/unga-finally-solving-climate-change/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 08:22:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=381</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the main policy-making hub of the United Nations, regarding the ever-growing problem of Climate Change, India recognizes its issues with struggling to get to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the main policy-making hub of the United Nations, regarding the ever-growing problem of Climate Change, India recognizes its issues with struggling to get to net zero emissions. India is the third largest contributor of greenhouse gasses and realizes the impacts of climate change on its people and is hoping to combat this through what the representative said were “accountability solutions and trying to allocate resources from different countries.” </p>



<p>As the committee finally begins to pass its resolutions, we see plans such as focuses on sustainability through technological development, and deforestation. In particular, the Green Deal Action Plan which is using innovative technology such as floor tiles which as they are walked on create kinetic energy. They plan on obtaining funding from developed countries as well as NGOs. They are ambitious that they will be able to help the people in countries facing deforestation as their economies heavily depend on activities such as logging and others related to deforestation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Despite these ideas for combating climate change, overall the committee struggles with merging and coming up with solid solutions that would be able to pertain to everyone, especially both developed and underdeveloped countries.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Can Climate Change be Stopped?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/how-can-climate-change-be-stopped/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Climate change is not a new problem. It&#8217;s been an ever-growing issue since back in 1988 with the depletion of the ozone layer. It has]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Climate change is not a new problem. It&#8217;s been an ever-growing issue since back in 1988 with the depletion of the ozone layer. It has continued to grow and has had lasting effects on the economy. Some of these effects can be seen through unbalances in weather, and the increase in temperatures throughout the years.</p>



<p>These increasing temperatures have also affected the production of food, which has had an increase in hunger and a decrease in nutrition. Heat can diminish water, which also can lead to droughts, which are creating more deserts and people are facing threats of not having enough water. Along with the talk of water, these temperatures can affect the amount of rainfall, increasing the frequency of storms, landslides, and destroying homes, which is costing billions of dollars to repair. Along with that, climate change is making ice sheets melt, which is making the ocean levels rise, which can be threatening to islands and communities on those islands. </p>



<p>A representative from India shared, “Holding countries accountable and allocating our resources and funds towards combating climate change.” Most countries have their own contributions to climate change, but holding them accountable can help stop this threatening issue. </p>



<p>“All of us have established a climate goal and not all of us are meeting it. That’s an issue.”, the representative from India mentioned. Most countries have brought up the issue of climate change, it is whether or not they actually exceed the standards to actually attempt to stop climate change. </p>



<p>“Seeing why they can’t meet their goals and giving them resources to allow them too,” which was also mentioned by the delegate from India. India is willing to help and wants to make sure that countries, even their own country, has the needed resources to put a stop on climate change. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNGA: The Real &#8220;Heroes&#8221; of Climate Change</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/unga-the-real-heroes-of-climate-change/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UNGA plans for solving the climate crisis have reached a stalemate. The general assembly is slow on their topic and the world does not]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The UNGA plans for solving the climate crisis have reached a stalemate. The general assembly is slow on their topic and the world does not have enough time for them to take their sweet time. No solution of any kind has been mainly addressed, countries are not getting anywhere on there on a plan of any kind. However, many countries pushed for the topic of climate change to be primarily addressed. </p>



<p>Since the 1850s, the climate crisis has shadowed the world every day. The climate of the world has been majorly changing the ideologies of countries through the years. Today the climate crisis is a major crisis for each and every country and the UNGA is taking their time on the issue that has increasingly been affecting every country. The UNGA will be wiped out because of climate change before they can help climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Delegations such as New Zealand have stated that “These solutions have taken much longer than they would like” and climate change is going to affect countries faster than we think. Other countries such as Tanzania say ,“ They agree with the resolutions going on currently.” The UNGA needs to pick a common direction and recommend a plan before it&#8217;s too late. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Liveblog (Present Day)</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/friday-liveblog-present-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael McCarthy, Deputy USG for Media]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>United Kingdom Plans to Discuss the Promotion of Beneficial Artificial Intelligence at Upcoming United Nations Session</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/07/united-kingdom-plans-to-discuss-the-promotion-of-beneficial-artificial-intelligence-at-upcoming-united-nations-session/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 04:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=88</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Artificial intelligence (A.I) and its recent surge in global usage has undoubtedly raised a myriadof questions as to how this powerful technology should be used]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Artificial intelligence (A.I) and its recent surge in global usage has undoubtedly raised a myriad<br>of questions as to how this powerful technology should be used and regulated. Furthermore, it<br>has become increasingly evident that the integration of A.I. into society not only poses a liability<br>to the global economy (via workforce downturns), but also threatens the health of Earth’s<br>environment. With the start of the United Nations General Assembly (UNGA) plenary meeting<br>on the horizon, the United Kingdom agreed to an interview with the nation’s UNGA delegate<br>Abigail Shaw to discuss the trivial issues at hand.</p>



<p>The interview began with the question: “What is the United Kingdom’s stance on the promotion<br>of beneficial artificial intelligence?” Shaw responded by emphasizing that A.I. is a tool that has<br>the potential to dramatically change billions of lives for the better, however, “The governance of<br>AI technologies must be done correctly in order to encourage meaningful innovation and<br>investment into the technology that also protects the public.”</p>



<p>The subsequent question for Shaw was: “How does the United Kingdom plan to approach the<br>promotion of beneficial artificial intelligence?” Shaw’s response was the proposal of the<br>“L.O.C Plan”, a multifaceted solution whose abbreviation stands for Limits, Oversight, and<br>Creation. Through this plan, the United Kingdoms strives to limit the amount of harmful A.I.<br>available on the internet, implement a UN subcommittee to monitor A.I. activity, and eventually<br>have new beneficial A.I. be created that’s properly regulated from the ground up.</p>



<p>As hopeful as the contents of the L.O.C. Plan appear upon first glance, there is still legitimate<br>concern to be had for the lack of consideration towards the effect that artificial intelligence has<br>on the environment. As the A.I. Industry grows, it will have to comply with the U.N. Sustainable<br>Development Goals. At this current rate, studies show that compliance won’t be possible if<br>the energy required to operate artificial intelligence is not harnessed sustainably.</p>



<p>As the interview concluded, Shaw provided that the United Kingdom’s hopes for the<br>plenary committee itself are to witness “vivid displays of international diplomacy” in the<br>aspiration that member states of the UNGA can engage in “peaceful negotiations and dialogue<br>with one another that allows the committee to pass solutions that effectively promote the use of<br>beneficial A.I.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
