<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>UN General Assembly &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/archive/2021/category/unga/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:13:19 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>UNGA Comes Together to Deal with Nuclear Arms in DPRK after Kim Jong Un&#8217;s Death</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/unga-comes-together-to-deal-with-nuclear-arms-in-dprk-after-kim-jong-uns-death/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Zhang, The Korea Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 19:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UN General Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Due to the death of Kim Jong Un and to avoid potential instability, the United Nations General Assembly is currently working to find a solution]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Due to the death of Kim Jong Un and to avoid potential instability, the United Nations General Assembly is currently working to find a solution on denuclearizing North Korea.</p>



<p>As of now, the United Nations General Assembly has recognized Kim Yo-Jong as the new successor of the DPRK.</p>



<p>On Feb. 6th, the committee comes together to work on a solution to the possible denuclearization of the state. Two blocs have been formed, one for denuclearization and another that believes that denuclearization is unachievable. </p>



<p>South Korea, Poland, Russia, Rwanda, Nigeria, and others are for denuclearization.&nbsp; As a solution, the bloc calls for a three phase plan to limit the country’s nuclear power.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Phase 1 begins with a pause on all development and testing on arms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Phase 2 terminates all production of enriched uranium and plutonium. They also call for the dismantling of nuclear processing infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Phase 3 removes all existing warheads and fissile materials.</p>



<p>The bloc has also proposed to create a Euroasian energy and transportation link. They also wish to safely dispose of the nuclear weapons from the DPRK.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the other end, there are many other&nbsp; countries who do not believe that denuclearization is achievable under Kim Yo Jong.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Denuclearization is not possible under the regime of Kim Yo Jung. She has proven to be an ambitious leader who cracks down with brutality. Suggesting denuclearization will be viewed as a threat and taken with hostilities. Kim Yo Jung is an isolationist who will not work for the benefit of international peace.”, stated the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There is a clear divide within the General Assembly right now but as the meeting progresses, the delegates will continue to work on a solution to find peace.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">184</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
