<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>UN Environment Assembly &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/unea/feed/?simply_static_page=1163" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:02:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>UNEA looks ahead to climate resiliency</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/unea-looks-ahead-to-climate-resiliency/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juliana Gunvalsen, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 21:31:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1633</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Having finished their first topic, the UNEA is well underway with their next concern in debate: empowering climate resilience. Yesterday, the RRECO bloc was one]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Having finished their first topic, the UNEA is well underway with their next concern in debate: empowering climate resilience. Yesterday, the RRECO bloc was one of the three papers voted on, though it did not pass.</p>



<p>“I think that our paper RRECO was realistic and people could not handle that fact,&#8221; a representative from the bloc stated. &#8220;There was a certain piece of western bias… We just thought it was logical to have big developed countries and a few small countries so we really wanted to express the stress in the realistic portion.”</p>



<p>Despite these events, many of the same countries resumed their work together this morning in order to tackle the new issues at hand. Countries such as Mauritania, Venezuela, Syria, China, Iran, and Russia. </p>



<p>Collectively they “came together to start working on this one solution really because we knew that our countries get along, have similar policies, and things that definitely affect each other.” Syria stated, “For instance, droughts can really cause floods, that can be the main contributor, and Syria suffers from droughts. We feel like at this point we are probably the farthest along bloc, it&#8217;s the most comprehensive paper.”</p>



<p>Other delegates, such as Indonesia and Uruguay, were simply glad to see a display of diplomacy in the cabinet. Indonesia feels that “it was absolutely wonderful that this paper got passed and got passed unilaterally in various countries who had various different interests. I initially came out on the opposition but when I saw the paper and examined it more closely I realized we shared a common goal, so I ended up supporting it very strongly.”</p>



<p>Uruguay, a sponsor on the Net Green paper that was passed, shared a similar sentiment. The delegate said, “I&#8217;m just really happy I could be apart of the sponsors for this amazing paper. It was really really fun just to work out these differences between countries, talking to different blocs trying to make it so we can get our paper passed and it&#8217;s just amazing to see the world take a step in the right direction. It&#8217;s the first time I&#8217;ve ever seen this many countries come together to do something and not say something, but objectively do something.”</p>



<p>The committee is working relentlessly to solve the current issues and anticipates the presentation of working papers at some point during today’s session.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sustainability! What are it’s goals?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/sustainability-what-are-its-goals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mira Polyakov, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 15:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After making a visit to the UNEA, Iran, Tunisia, and India introduced their resolution about a more sustainable world. Green economies make a green world]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After making a visit to the UNEA, Iran, Tunisia, and India introduced their resolution about a more sustainable world. Green economies make a green world right? These economies can provide a low-carbon, resource-efficient, and socially inclusive economy preventing the loss of biodiversity and ecosystem services. </p>



<p>Soon a switch will be made, superseding the irreplaceable non-renewable resources, to more valuable renewable resources. Renewable sources may include wind and solar power, biomass, and bioenergy which would strongly promote sustainability.  Following those, everything hydro comes into play, with hydro-energy, and hydro-thermal energy. But questions remain such as what body of water they plan to use, and what areas are deep enough underground?</p>



<p>With nuclear power our economy can be pushed 3 steps forward, the disposal of nuclear waste, the expansion of the power, and intense research for nuclear facilities all can help rid the atmosphere of harmful byproducts emitted by fossil fuels and significantly contribute to both the economic and environmental dimensions of sustainability. </p>



<p>The world is in good hands, let&#8217;s just hope this is not too good to be true.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNEA battles to solve sustainability</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/unea-battles-to-solve-sustainability/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Juliana Gunvalsen, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:17:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1146</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[UNEA is hard at work this afternoon as they hash out various working papers and the varying ideas within them. Two opposing blocs, the Realistic]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="768" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/IMG_4191-1024x768.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1148" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/IMG_4191-1024x768.jpg 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/IMG_4191-300x225.jpg 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/IMG_4191-768x576.jpg 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/IMG_4191-1536x1152.jpg 1536w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/IMG_4191-800x600.jpg 800w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/IMG_4191.jpg 2016w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Delegates Present Their Working Paper</figcaption></figure>



<p>UNEA is hard at work this afternoon as they hash out various working papers and the varying ideas within them. Two opposing blocs, the Realistic Renewable and Economics Cooperation Operation (RRECO) bloc and the Net Green bloc, shared some of their views with the Chicago Tribune. </p>



<p>The RRECO bloc is comprised of nations such as China, Russia, India, Iran, Syria, Venezuela, and more. During their interview, they expressed the desire to understand all sides of the issue, both from developed and developing countries. </p>



<p>The bloc released the following statement: “We believe that our bloc is probably more realistic financially because it doesn&#8217;t necessarily focus on completely stopping the use of fossil fuels immediately because that&#8217;s a very one way approach …So, we&#8217;re focusing on incentivizing the use of renewable energy but also not affecting them detrimentally for using oil resources… We definitely think it&#8217;s important to acknowledge why we have been trying to move toward renewable energy for so long and the reason it hasn&#8217;t worked is because it isn&#8217;t sustainable at all and we are trying to move towards a sustainable future. For instance, Syria is a very solar heavy, wind heavy country, that&#8217;s going to work really well for us, but that&#8217;s not going to work for Russia… Many of the smaller countries are heavily dependent on fossil fuels and by cutting that entirely you&#8217;re ruining their economy and some of the western nations want to take advantage of that and that would mean that the smaller countries would have to rely on the larger powers… This is going to make developing countries dependent on large countries as they are dependent on fossil fuels now. If we uproot these developing countries economically they are not going to have the ability to make the hefty investment that is renewable energy sources.”</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="480" height="640" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/IMG_4188-rotated.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1149" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/IMG_4188-rotated.jpg 480w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/IMG_4188-225x300.jpg 225w" sizes="(max-width: 480px) 100vw, 480px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">RRECO Bloc Members (from right to left: Lesotho, Mozambique, Venezuela, Sweden)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Opposing them stands the Net Green working paper, composed primarily of Uruguay, the United States, and Honduras. They have been debating for quite some time with RRECO regarding funding and other resources.</p>



<p>Statement from the representative of Uruguay: “Our paper is specifically about giving developing countries an edge into this climate resilient and net zero world. Our entire thing is about helping small nations… I think they are taking a situation and expecting it to go one way and making assumptions by which we continue to operate, understanding exactly what our paper is. We take underdeveloped countries into account. Honduras, one of the undeveloped countries, is actually a sponsor and a presenter and has taken charge of some of our most important clauses. … So, I think that they are misrepresenting our bloc and making assumptions and I don&#8217;t think that&#8217;s what our bloc means anyway… One of our main clauses is about funding, especially funding underdeveloped countries through developed countries using a grant system. This would be present internationally as something that helps countries that are especially in danger and countries that are trying to move towards turning into a net zero country.” </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNEA Progression</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/unea-progression/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elly Noble-Schueller, Islamic Republic News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 19:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1035</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While spectating the UNEA, also known as the United Nations Environment Assembly, they were ferociously debating weighty issues surrounding climate change that could be deemed]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-03-1.26.17-PM-150x150.png" alt="" width="270" height="270"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Iran&#8217;s expansion of nuclear power</figcaption></figure></div>


<p class="has-black-color has-white-background-color has-text-color has-background has-medium-font-size">While spectating the UNEA, also known as the United Nations Environment Assembly, they were ferociously debating weighty issues surrounding climate change that could be deemed detrimental to humankind and all other possible living things on the planet Earth. The delegation from Uruguay discusses the three environmental issues covered by UNEA this weekend while participating in an exclusive moderated caucus, &#8220;We need to focus on sources for renewable energy, ocean biodiversity, and natural disasters resulting from the effects of climate change&#8221;. The committee then discussed which issue needed to be tackledfirst depending on their country&#8217;s idea of importance. Pulling the Iranian delegation of the UNEA aside, they voice their strong opinion,  &#8220;We want to create aid, to then increase the amount of nuclear energy being used in developing countries since these tend to be the countries suffering most from climate change.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNEA on energy resources</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/unea-on-energy-resources/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josie Barnes, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 19:22:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1068</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Times (South Africa) had the opportunity to visit the U.N. Environmental Assembly. We choose to ask additional questions after listening to the conversation on]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Times (South Africa) had the opportunity to visit the U.N. Environmental Assembly. We choose to ask additional questions after listening to the conversation on energy, biodiversity, and climate change.</p>



<p><strong>How does your country contribute to renewable energy?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Mexico: “</strong>Mexico aims to make a thirty-two percent reduction in fossil fuel emissions by twenty-thirty. We are committed to ending the use of fossil fuels, even though a large portion of our country still does use them”.</p>



<p><strong>Nepal: “</strong>We don&#8217;t have a lot of renewable energy right now. We are an underdeveloped nation attempting to address that, but we require more funding and resources and hope to eventually contribute”.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Kenya: “</strong>The bulk of the energy used in our nation is renewable. Geothermal, wind, and solar energy account for around eight-one percent”.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Does your country believe renewable energy can replace fossil fuels, and are you working on anything to do that?</strong></p>



<p><strong>Mexico: “</strong>Yes, we do think so. Renewable energy will someday be able to replace all fossil fuels. As a nation, we are now unable to completely eliminate the use of fossil fuels. Due of the lack of resources and the several other issues we are trying to address, it will take time”.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Nepal: “</strong>Yes. We are currently attempting to persuade more developed nations to act more, as they have the means and capacity to do so. We are hoping for a clean future even if it will take time”.</p>



<p><strong>Kenya: “</strong>We are certain that it can. Our nation is currently working to forge alliances that will enable us to extend that transfer. While the transition may take time, once it is complete, economies will be able to grow without the need for fossil fuels or oil”.</p>



<p><strong>What do you hope to accomplish so far in powering the energy transformation?&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p><strong>Mexico: “</strong>We hope that we can gradually phase out fossil fuels. Because our nation cannot uphold strict restrictions, we do not want to pass resolutions that impose them”.</p>



<p><strong>Nepal: </strong>​​”We expect action from developed nations. We hope that they resolve their problem and make use of their resources to assist other developing nations”.</p>



<p><strong>Kenya:</strong> “We aim to accomplish a goal for the amount of renewable energy it produces annually worldwide. Whatever that goal is, we want to work with other countries and make it happen”.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The cancerous corrosion of coral environments</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/the-cancerous-corrosion-of-coral-environments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Marquez, Der Speigel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Climate change has already wreaked havoc on the world’s populations and environments, and its damages will only further escalate with time. Humanity has accomplished countless]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Climate change has already wreaked  havoc on the world’s populations and environments, and its damages will only further escalate with time. Humanity has accomplished countless impressive feats in fields of education, innovation, sports, physical performance, philosophy, and wisdom. Yet, despite all our time on this beloved planet, so little effort has been directed towards sustaining the planet that has provided so much. Nature contains immensely beautiful landscapes, habitats, and environments that oftentimes play second fiddle to the interest of advancement, whether directly through actions including deforestation to make room for factories or indirectly through those same factories spewing out boundless and unchecked pollution. The world simply needs to start taking better care of the planet or we will tear it apart until the once gorgeous and abundant world we once knew vanishes before our very eyes.</p>



<p> It is so easy for anyone with a laptop to write about the horridness of climate change crisis but offer no further explanation, guidance, or commentary on the issue. When facing any giant problem, it remains wise to break the issue down into more manageable and approachable issues, such as issues about climate/environmental changes that lie in coral reefs. Coral environments are crucial to marine life across the globe and support many oceanic communities and even nations. When asked about the significance of coral reefs to an island nation’s cultural identity and economy, the representative from New Zealand said, “It is important to maintain coral and reef habitats because they are the crutch on which so many ecosystems rely. These reefs are home to numerous species of small fish who in turn, feed and nourish the predator fish who are consumed by the nearby populaces for food. If the reefs disappear, so will the fish we eat. With societies polluting and overfishing, people really aren&#8217;t making it easy for the oceanic ecosystems to keep up with this outrageous pace.” Unfortunately, many individuals live in areas of the world where the effects of climate change are so visible as they are in a nation such as New Zealand that faces the devastating reality that their cherished reefs are in danger of disappearing. </p>



<p>The New Zealand representative continued, listing numerous plans of action to protect their reefs from the effects of climate and environmental change, citing wishes to, “subsidize the game and wildlife department to help further protect the numerous ecosystems from being overhunted and overfished. Additionally, increasing fines for littering along beach areas, as well as the number of organizations which are tasked with cleaning up ecosystems, including reefs.” </p>



<p>The representative&#8217;s parting words to those who are still failing to realize the brevity of time with which the world has to act on this matter are captured in the following statement: “When island nations begin to sink, and the damage is too far gone, maybe then they’ll realize it all could have been avoided.” With these solemn words, hopefully, enough people and nations will be called to take immediate action, realize yesterday was the time to act, and hopefully, tomorrow will not be the day when we look back on a ravaged and depleted world too far gone and lament what we have done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Renewables are replacing fossil fuels, but some worry about their drawbacks</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/renewables-are-replacing-fossil-fuels-but-some-worry-about-their-drawbacks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ishan Dixit, BBC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 23:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since the dawn of the industrial age, humans have harmed our world. Humans have pouredcarbon dioxide into the atmosphere, causing lasting worldly effects. Now, as]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since the dawn of the industrial age, humans have harmed our world. Humans have poured<br>carbon dioxide into the atmosphere, causing lasting worldly effects. </p>



<p>Now, as more data and statistics emerge regarding the plausibility of saving the planet emerge, countries are starting to take action. Many European countries such as France and Germany have a tangible dream of reaching net zero emissions by 2050. </p>



<p>Reform will not be easy as many mid-high income countries, which make up most industries within the world, still rely on natural resources to fuel the ever-growing world. Renewable energy is emerging as a concept that should be implemented in society. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="692" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-02-at-10-23-21-2023-UNEA-Background-Guide.docx-UNEA-2023.pdf-1024x692.png" alt="" class="wp-image-810" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-02-at-10-23-21-2023-UNEA-Background-Guide.docx-UNEA-2023.pdf-1024x692.png 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-02-at-10-23-21-2023-UNEA-Background-Guide.docx-UNEA-2023.pdf-300x203.png 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-02-at-10-23-21-2023-UNEA-Background-Guide.docx-UNEA-2023.pdf-768x519.png 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-02-at-10-23-21-2023-UNEA-Background-Guide.docx-UNEA-2023.pdf.png 1532w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>According to data from the BP Statistical Review of World Energy, many of the world powerhouses are exploring renewable energy sources as an alternative to the fossil fuels that science is trying so hard to combat. </p>



<p>Although these modes of energy do seem appealing, the idea of such energy sources is sometimes frowned upon as they prove to be dangerous if things go south. Take Chernobyl as an example, the Soviet nuclear power station went down causing havoc and a nuclear meltdown. Thus, because of a rising world temperature and concerns regarding the future of the earth, the world is moving towards a greener future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
