<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Fiddah Shereef, Chicago Tribune &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/archive/2022/author/fshereef/feed/?simply_static_page=200" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2022</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 19:18:41 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>WHO Lebanon Drama</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/who-lebanon-drama/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fiddah Shereef, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 18:50:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=718</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As working papers were being written on solutions for the distribution of covid vaccines, Turkey first joined Lebanon&#8217;s bloc VACC, which supported funding from the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As working papers were being written on solutions for the distribution of covid vaccines, Turkey first joined Lebanon&#8217;s bloc VACC, which supported funding from the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation. After discovering their plans and perspective, they decided to switch and work with Israel in their bloc DDD (Distribution, Discipline, and Dedication).</p>



<p>An angered Lebanon confronted Turkey, outraged at Israel&#8217;s racism for not vaccinating Palestinians and questioned Turkey&#8217;s support.</p>



<p>Later, Senegal, one of the members of the DDD bloc, approached VACC to see if they could collaborate to make sure that the papers would pass, which they made very clear. However, on orders of Lebanon, Senegal was kicked out on allegations of spying.</p>



<p>Lebanon then spreads the conspiracy theory through the press that Israel was manipulating the situation to benefit themselves economically.</p>



<p>As many were now against Lebanon, a coalition was created to prevent Lebanon&#8217;s paper from passing, including DDD and other smaller blocs. However, this angered Lebanon once again; they decided to create fake messages involving Turkey spreading fake news to the press.</p>



<p>An anonymous statement was released saying &#8220;the VACC bloc has to make false posts and give false statements because they know that on their own, they won&#8217;t win. In the VACC paper, they talk lots about the importance of education and in being informed, but meanwhile, they feed conspiracy theories to other newspapers to try and undermine other papers.&#8221;</p>



<p>More to come as the story develops.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S Senators Work to Aid South Korea</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/u-s-senators-work-to-aid-south-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fiddah Shereef, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 02:18:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1950)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=630</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Resolution 11, &#8220;A Resolution to Aid South Korea&#8217;s Defense,&#8221; just recently passed in the U.S. Senate sponsored by Sens. Kenneth McKellar (D-TN), James E. Murray]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Resolution 11, &#8220;A Resolution to Aid South Korea&#8217;s Defense,&#8221; just recently passed in the U.S. Senate sponsored by Sens. Kenneth McKellar (D-TN), James E. Murray (D-MT), Burnet R. Maybank (D-SC), and Ralph Flanders (R-VT).</p>



<p>South Korea seeks aid from the U.S. senators as they are far underprepared to protect South Korea&#8217;s sovereignty from the communist North Korean government. Resolution 11, while clearly expressing the United State&#8217;s intention of eradicating the spread of communism and the influence and power of the Soviet Union, looks to support South Korea as seen through its ten sections of the resolution.</p>



<p>As seen in Section 1: Authorization of Force, Section 2: Funding, Section 3: Establishment of MASH Medical Centers, and Section 6: Providing Humanitarian Aid to Refugees, the U.S Senators are working to support South Korea in eliminating escalation of communism in foreign countries.</p>



<p><strong>Section 1:</strong>&nbsp;<strong>Authorization of Force</strong> states that the president is approved to deploy military forces to South Korea to prevent a North Korean invasion by establishing a base on the front line. As they are authorized to protect the sovereignty of South Korea, they will be permitted to utilize force when necessary.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>Section 2:</strong> <strong>Funding</strong> authorizes the United States to mobilize any excess funds deemed necessary and expendable to aid the efforts of the Republic of Korea Army. This section of the resolution encompasses initiatives such as creating an agency to investigate and make new weapons and tools to benefit their martial prowess, including possible organizations such as the Defense Advanced Research Projects Agency or DARPA. Funding for these initiatives may come from a mild increase in taxes as new jobs will be available, and wages will increase. It is also stated that the United States should attempt to lure in scientists from around the world with higher investments in the scientific sector in America. </p>



<p><strong>Section 3: Establishment of MASH Medical Centers</strong> is a sector requesting Mobile Army Surgical Hospitals that would remain neutral and protected by the Geneva convention. These hospitals would be staffed by officers of the U.S. Army and equipped to provide first aid to frontline patients received via helicopter or ambulance.</p>



<p><strong>Section 6:</strong> <strong>Providing Humanitarian Aid to Refugees</strong> involves Sen. Maybank&#8217;s refugee program, and the funding would be derived from Sen. Murray&#8217;s One Dollar initiative rather than from taxes. It is being requested that these refugee camps alongside hospitals and education centers be provided as soon as possible. Jobs and workplaces also need to be established for refugees as well as translators should be made easily accessible due to the language barrier. </p>



<p>The U.S. senators are providing as much as they can to guide South Korea, according to Sen. Murray.</p>



<p>&#8220;The Senate is doing stuff,&#8221; Sen. Murray said. &#8220;We are acting, there is bipartisan support, and we have sent all we can to Korea in order to aid their fight against the communist forces and it&#8217;s working! The releases by the New York Times and other press releases are incorrect in their characterization of this body as a bickering, inefficient body.&#8221; </p>



<p>The U.S. Senate has succeeded in taking action and is doing all that they can do to aid South Korea as they work to diminish the spread of the communist government.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>US Communist Pressure</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/us-communist-pressure/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fiddah Shereef, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 20:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1950)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States fears the domino effect of the spread of communism from the USSR. They are looking to put an end to the communist]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The United States fears the domino effect of the spread of communism from the USSR. They are looking to put an end to the communist threat, as a member of the UN Security Council stated that &#8220;this is not because it is a different way of life but because it has been used in corrupt ways to gain more power in control&#8221; when referring to why the U.S does not like the spread of communism. The more communism spreads amongst other countries, the more countries will fall as it destabilizes the nation allowing communist regimes to continue to dominate and spread.</p>



<p>It was revealed that the U.S plans to observe and will intervene when necessary; however, they have no intention of starting a war against communism as they cannot afford a third round of a world war. </p>



<p>Senator McCarthy has created a list of about 200 names of members of the Communist Party but, many senators like Senator Murray are opposed to taking the list and running with it without confirmation. They are looking to further investigate this list rather than &#8220;reading it like gossip.&#8221;</p>



<p>Senator Howard McGrawth displays his strong animosity for communism and claims that &#8220;Where there are stains of communism, there is evil. Where there is capitalism, there is good for the people.&#8221; At this moment he is unwilling to share his proposition on how the U.S. should take action but is certain that communism will not prevail.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S Senator Ralph Flanders Stolen Resolution</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/u-s-senator-ralph-flanders-stolen-resolution/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fiddah Shereef, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 20:36:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1950)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=542</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.S Senator Murray reveals the current conflict arising between Senator Ralph Flanders and Senator Bridges of New Hamphsire. As Senator Ralph Flanders was working alongside]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>U.S Senator Murray reveals the current conflict arising between Senator Ralph Flanders and Senator Bridges of New Hamphsire. </p>



<p>As Senator Ralph Flanders was working alongside Senator Bridges and Senator Taft to write their first set of papers on ways to aid South Korea humanitarily and economically conflict first arose as Senator Bridges was against the idea of writing a section on disarment however, the majority had ruled and Senator Ralph Flanders began his section in the paper. Senator Flanders claims that he had written two pages of work and a title while &#8220;Senator Bridges barley wrote half a sentence.&#8221; Senator Bridges had then demoted his access as an editor to a viewer and attempted to delete his name from the sponsor list.</p>



<p>Senator Taft had created a new document with Senator Flanders&#8217; work and submitted the document to the chair. Shortly after a political officer granted Senator Flanders&#8217; approval to publicily acuse Senator Bridges of plagairism. </p>



<p>Senator Bridges of New Hampshire is now being faced with allegations of plagiarism and Senator Ralph Flanders, Senator James E. Murray, and Senator Robert Taft work to censure and impeach her as they demand compensation be made for Senator Flanders.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
