<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>United Nations Security Council (1950) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/2022/category/united-nations-security-council-1950/feed/?simply_static_page=121" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2022</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:51:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>US Communist Pressure</title>
		<link>/2022/us-communist-pressure/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fiddah Shereef, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 20:55:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1950)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2022/?p=482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United States fears the domino effect of the spread of communism from the USSR. They are looking to put an end to the communist]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The United States fears the domino effect of the spread of communism from the USSR. They are looking to put an end to the communist threat, as a member of the UN Security Council stated that &#8220;this is not because it is a different way of life but because it has been used in corrupt ways to gain more power in control&#8221; when referring to why the U.S does not like the spread of communism. The more communism spreads amongst other countries, the more countries will fall as it destabilizes the nation allowing communist regimes to continue to dominate and spread.</p>



<p>It was revealed that the U.S plans to observe and will intervene when necessary; however, they have no intention of starting a war against communism as they cannot afford a third round of a world war. </p>



<p>Senator McCarthy has created a list of about 200 names of members of the Communist Party but, many senators like Senator Murray are opposed to taking the list and running with it without confirmation. They are looking to further investigate this list rather than &#8220;reading it like gossip.&#8221;</p>



<p>Senator Howard McGrawth displays his strong animosity for communism and claims that &#8220;Where there are stains of communism, there is evil. Where there is capitalism, there is good for the people.&#8221; At this moment he is unwilling to share his proposition on how the U.S. should take action but is certain that communism will not prevail.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
