<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cabinet of the People&#8217;s Republic of China &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/pd-committees/cabinet-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:56:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. cabinet: cry for action</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/u-s-cabinet-cry-for-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=651</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for pressuring China with the situation in Taiwan, and the proposal of possible sanctions which the UNSC is open to was discussed. </p>



<p>The U.S. cabinet currently already has ships in Japan for a diplomatic presence in the region, moving forward with sanctions they feel will be the most effective way Additionally, they feel that these harder sanctions will pressure China about their wrongdoings and have more international pressure about correcting their wrongs. </p>



<p>The representative from the UNSC had advised that there is a firm reason for these sanctions on China, and that the body does whatever they can in significance with their cause, supporting Taiwan. </p>



<p>Later on, in the press conference, the United States cabinet, madam Press Secretary had explained that the United States was shocked by China’s reaction to the call for a revote. The U.S. has time and time again reached out to the PRC yet has received no response, but the PRC was reported to barge into the U.S. cabinet&#8217;s closed session when it was “most convenient for them.” China’s sudden aggression within Taiwan now gives the U.S. reason to believe that there is heavy Chinese involvement, as their own social media platform, Tencent has also been explicitly spreading disinformation that directly influenced the results of the election. </p>



<p>The cabinet has also called upon the UNSC to help with the current issues within Taiwan, specifically the corruption seen within the election and the democracy impeded from within it. Additionally, they have coordinated asking for how the UNSC will choose to move forward with China’s actions as the U.S. government specifically will no longer be contacting the Chinese government due to the “disrespect of sanctity diplomacy.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>An intercepted source has also let us know that China is threatening the U.S. and threatening to get rid of some things that are unknown in regard to the U.S. The U.S. economy also is thriving and has no further need for China. </p>



<p>Furthermore, in an interview with UN Ambassador Linda Thomas Greenfield, “The U.S. is trying their best in order to help Taiwan as the United States has empathy for all and they are heavily focused on the economy to help our citizens. Alongside this, we are arranging a meeting with the U.S. delegation from the Security Council as their input is valuable.”</p>



<p>The response from the UNSC is still being awaited and more developments will continue as debate on the next steps to be taken continue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PRESS CONFERENCE: United States is Shocked China&#8217;s Actions</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/press-conference-united-states-is-shocked-chinas-actions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between the two countries. The U.S. representative has sensed some aggression from China, also shown through how they have allowed themselves to come into meetings with no prior conversation. </p>



<p>The United States has further commentary on the fact that China has said they do not want forgiven involvement at the moment because of any possible influence on their election. Yet, the United States mentioned how the Chinese app, Tencent,  is spreading misinformation and has directly influenced China’s election. Showing that even with no current foreign relations, there are still direct influences on their election via the country’s social media app. Was it really worth it to cut connections with other countries that have not had an influence when you country has had an influence first? </p>



<p>Due to the previous actions that China has taken, the United States feels that China is rejecting any possible diplomatic offers. Furthermore, the U.S. has called upon the United Nations Security Council to help deal with these issues in China and even Taiwan as it is going to be needed to keep international peace between countries. After coordinating with the U.S. Security Council representative, the U.S. is urging the most powerful peacekeeping body in the world to help to deal with China’s actions as quickly and as effectively as possible. Now, the United States will no longer be in contact with the China government because of all the previously mentioned issues and that they have disrespected diplomacy. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China: Humanitarian Aid is a Given</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/china-humanitarian-aid-is-a-given-ready-to-be-published/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As more debate arises in the Security Council on the Russia-Ukraine War, China raises its position on the solution by vetoing the resolution of humanitarian]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As more debate arises in the Security Council on the Russia-Ukraine War, China raises its position on the solution by vetoing the resolution of humanitarian aid in the council.</p>



<p>The reason for this is that China believes through this crisis the Security Council has failed to commit to helping the major crisis going on within Ukraine. If the Security Council cannot commit to the bigger task that was at hand the act for humanitarian aid should be put at a pause.</p>



<p>The Security Council failed to amend a peace talk between Russia and Ukraine and has failed to release any statement on the matter. The representative from China commented, &#8220;it shows a lack of commitment towards ending a War&#8221; and putting funds toward humanitarian aid would be unreasonable due to the lack of commitment the Council has. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNSC: Disappointment Over Veto</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/unsc-disappointment-over-veto/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UN Security Council is facing debates over the humanitarian aid paper as China has used its veto power and has vetoed the idea of]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The UN Security Council is facing debates over the humanitarian aid paper as China has used its veto power and has vetoed the idea of humanitarian aid for the Russia-Ukraine war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The sole purpose of this paper was to help both sides in the conflict, as seen in the proposed paper, by being able to have equal sponsors and aid sent on both sides for the reason of basic human equality. It was supposed to help the millions of civilians living in distress, which now seems a hard goal to reach. </p>



<p>The United States has had very strong opinions regarding this situation as they do not support the use of the veto. The United States is against China’s veto in the humanitarian aid paper as there was perhaps no true basis for China to use its powers. It is also important to note that this humanitarian aid paper was supported by the Russian Federation. </p>



<p>In an interview with the United States, they expressed their deep disappointment, saying, “humanitarian aid was crucial, and support for both eastern and western powers was on this paper. It is disappointing that China has used its veto powers.” </p>



<p>Changes occur rapidly within this conflict and the UNSC’s debate only further stretches out the future of this nation. </p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The U.S. Cabinet: CALL FOR A REVOTE</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/the-u-s-cabinet-call-for-a-revote/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:51:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=512</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Historically speaking, the Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) in Taiwan has been known as the party that takes a Taiwanese nationalist position, advocating for strengthening Taiwanese]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Historically speaking, the Democratic Progressive Party (DPP) in Taiwan has been known as the party that takes a Taiwanese nationalist position, advocating for strengthening Taiwanese identity. This government has been leading and helping Taiwan with creating and enacting new developments. </p>



<p>Despite their increased efforts, in the most recent election in Taiwan, the KMT, a Chinese Nationalist Party, won. The consequences of this were the fact that the people regretted their decision and this is causing violent riots within Taiwan. The U.S. continued to investigate this matter further. Simultaneously, the People&#8217;s Republic of China made statements saying how they are all for democracy, and democracy has spoken. </p>



<p>This caused quite a stir within U.S. government, as there were talks of impeachment from the Republican party as they felt no proper measures were being taken. This stir took quite some time to settle down, but once it did, the U.S. made the firm decision of calling for a reflection in Taiwan. </p>



<p>The effects of this re-election on the people of Taiwan, and what is held for the future of Taiwan have not yet been discussed publicly. The U.S. has not made any further statements and more developments are to come. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Liveblog (Present Day)</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/friday-liveblog-present-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael McCarthy, Deputy USG for Media]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
