<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ishan Dixit, BBC &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/author/ibenet/feed/?simply_static_page=1396" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:05:50 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Cabinet of the UK continues to address Energy conflict</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/cabinet-of-the-uk-continues-to-address-energy-conflict/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ishan Dixit, BBC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:01:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1133</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The cabinet of the United Kingdom finds itself in a difficult place as there is a real threat to Britain’s main source of energy. In]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="458" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/40BF941E-EDCD-4E03-AB75-0BC36DF5B687-1024x458.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-1134" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/40BF941E-EDCD-4E03-AB75-0BC36DF5B687-1024x458.jpeg 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/40BF941E-EDCD-4E03-AB75-0BC36DF5B687-300x134.jpeg 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/40BF941E-EDCD-4E03-AB75-0BC36DF5B687-768x343.jpeg 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/40BF941E-EDCD-4E03-AB75-0BC36DF5B687.jpeg 1266w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>The cabinet of the United Kingdom finds itself in a difficult place as there is a real threat to Britain’s main source of energy. In recent events, the Government of Her Majesty the Queen has condemned the misuse of the labor union system.</p>



<p>In a recent meeting with her Majesty the Queen’s cabinet, a National Union of Mineworkers representative, Patricia Longsong, tension was especially high. Longsong, in a letter to the cabinet, listed the demands of the unions, such demands include the following:</p>



<ul>
<li>A 15% raise for all workers in UK Coal Pits</li>



<li>The end of any plans to UK Coal Pits</li>



<li>Continuation of subsidies to UK Coal Mines</li>



<li>Cessation of government’s “Anti union propaganda system”</li>



<li>Public statement of support for unions by PM Thatcher</li>
</ul>



<p>Prime Minister Thatcher challenged this by calmly stating that the Union is “lining their own pockets”. The UK maintains that the union is corrupted by greed, not protecting the interests of the individuals they represent.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The coal industry has a large impact on the people of the United Kingdom, Her Majesty’s cabinet maintains that both the Cabinet and Margret Thatcher are with the people of England. A Cabinet member stated in an interview, “we are not going to meet the demands of the coal strike as it is detrimental to Great Britain”. With tens of thousands without power in the coming future, the cabinet is working diligently to maintain the welfare of the United Kingdom.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Renewables are replacing fossil fuels, but some worry about their drawbacks</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/renewables-are-replacing-fossil-fuels-but-some-worry-about-their-drawbacks/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ishan Dixit, BBC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 23:52:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=782</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Since the dawn of the industrial age, humans have harmed our world. Humans have pouredcarbon dioxide into the atmosphere, causing lasting worldly effects. Now, as]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Since the dawn of the industrial age, humans have harmed our world. Humans have poured<br>carbon dioxide into the atmosphere, causing lasting worldly effects. </p>



<p>Now, as more data and statistics emerge regarding the plausibility of saving the planet emerge, countries are starting to take action. Many European countries such as France and Germany have a tangible dream of reaching net zero emissions by 2050. </p>



<p>Reform will not be easy as many mid-high income countries, which make up most industries within the world, still rely on natural resources to fuel the ever-growing world. Renewable energy is emerging as a concept that should be implemented in society. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="692" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-02-at-10-23-21-2023-UNEA-Background-Guide.docx-UNEA-2023.pdf-1024x692.png" alt="" class="wp-image-810" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-02-at-10-23-21-2023-UNEA-Background-Guide.docx-UNEA-2023.pdf-1024x692.png 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-02-at-10-23-21-2023-UNEA-Background-Guide.docx-UNEA-2023.pdf-300x203.png 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-02-at-10-23-21-2023-UNEA-Background-Guide.docx-UNEA-2023.pdf-768x519.png 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-02-at-10-23-21-2023-UNEA-Background-Guide.docx-UNEA-2023.pdf.png 1532w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>According to data from the BP Statistical Review of World Energy, many of the world powerhouses are exploring renewable energy sources as an alternative to the fossil fuels that science is trying so hard to combat. </p>



<p>Although these modes of energy do seem appealing, the idea of such energy sources is sometimes frowned upon as they prove to be dangerous if things go south. Take Chernobyl as an example, the Soviet nuclear power station went down causing havoc and a nuclear meltdown. Thus, because of a rising world temperature and concerns regarding the future of the earth, the world is moving towards a greener future.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
