<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Lockheed Martin Corporation &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2021/category/lockheed-martin-corporation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:22:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>Lockheed Martin Possibly Partners with BAE to save them from Bankruptcy</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/lockheed-martin-possibly-partners-with-bae-to-save-them-from-bankruptcy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dima Llanos, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BAE Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin has proposed a contract that would make BAE Systems and LM partners. LM proposed this plan to save BAE from bankruptcy by giving]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Lockheed Martin has proposed a contract that would make BAE Systems and LM partners. LM proposed this plan to save BAE from bankruptcy by giving them a small percentage of LM’s yearly budget, in exchange for BAE’s technological discoveries.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>If BAE signs this contract, BAE will receive .001% of Lockheed Martin’s yearly budget, which totals to around $600,000. BAE will pay back LM in a 2 year period following a 4 month grace period on either a&nbsp; quarterly or monthly basis.</p>



<p>&nbsp;The CEO of BAE, Lisa Carr, released a tweet stating that she is looking forward to signing with LM. The Senior Vice President of Communications in LM, Dean Acosat, released a statement to the press replying to the CEO of BAE’s tweet</p>



<p>“ Lockheed Martin is deeply concerned about the jobs in the United Kingdom that could be lost if BAE went to bankruptcy, as well as for the implications this would have in Europe’s security. That is why we made an agreement in which Lockheed Martin will prevent BAE from bankruptcy in exchange of a fair amount of technology. This created an open door for new collaborations.”</p>



<p>So what does LM get out of this? The plan is to pool resources with BAE to help them in the following areas</p>



<ul><li>Rotorcraft developments on the Defiant X program, and any future rotorcraft study will be done in a joint fashion, taking into account the past success of both corporations in this field&nbsp;</li><li>Lockheed Martin will become a full collaborator within the Tempest innovation and it will be fully implemented into the F-35 program in Britain and Australia.</li><li>Lockheed Martin will gain full advertising rights of collaborative innovation including Tempest and other EW programs implemented into the F-35 program.</li><li>Countries currently using BAE fighter jets will be offered an option to switch to our collaborative F-35 program.</li><li>The Missions Systems radars programs of BAE and LM should work together to enhance and improve upon both companies systems,</li><li>The Sentinel A4 radar system will stay under the development of the LMC</li><li>New radar systems will begin to be developed jointly in both the UK sectors and US sectors of both companies&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Boeing, Lockheed Martin&#8217;s competitors, will be affected by this greatly. Since the 2019 plane crashes with the 737 Max, Boeing has been struggling financially. Boeing’s two biggest competitors are BAE and Lockheed Martin, so the companies combining forces will leave them even farther behind financially and technologically.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">320</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Stock declines for US companies due to COVID-19</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/stock-declines-for-us-companies-due-to-covid-19/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:45:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin Corporation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northrop Grumman Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=295</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The New York Stock Exchange closed yesterday and the stocks of Lockheed Martin Stock and Northrop Grumman are down about 30 points and they have]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The New York Stock Exchange closed yesterday and the stocks of Lockheed Martin Stock and Northrop Grumman are down about 30 points and they have no revenue left after the economic downturn due the Covid-19 pandemic. However, Sukhoi-TCM has almost ample capital available with about 457 million dollars of cash on hand to develop infrastructure, technology and ensure the security and safety of the Russian Federation and economy.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The economy has stalled in many parts of the world, with unemployment rising and many companies close to bankruptcy, yet the Russian Sukhoi-TCM is economically strong and planning for a “prosperous future” Deputy Edmonds said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“I am proud of the economic prosperity that Russia has,” Edmonds said. “In response to the lack of funds of US companies this shows America’s dwindling lack of influence. This clearly shows how American hegemony has been lost and the world is tired of their over policing and control.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The United States’ economic recession and failure to maintain the success of their business illustrates the fall of the United States as the global superpower. Vice-Minister Raymond states that the “failed economic status of the United States and its industrial military complex” will allow the growth of Russian companies and power around the world. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">295</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boeing SVP of Treasury Leaked Email Shows Attempts to Thwart Lockheed Martin</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/boeing-svp-of-treasury-leaked-email-shows-attempts-to-thwart-lockheed-martin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dima Llanos, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 22:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin Corporation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Boeing Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A leaked email from the Senior Vice President of Finance and Treasury reveals an attempt to recruit a Lockheed Martin employee to give inside information]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A leaked email from the Senior Vice President of Finance and Treasury reveals an attempt to recruit a Lockheed Martin employee to give inside information to Boeing in order to reestablish Boeing&#8217;s power and reputation after the 737 MAX crashes in 2019 (see Boeing 737 Max returns to the skies after almost 2 Years, Chicago Tribune.)</p>



<p>Below, you can see the email that was sent:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/iKrddHx_x3OWqTrvbp_mI8DufS3OiolSXQMXU4a_Hiqt1qKhdVbNH_pvSglQusOwfNEOe8XM0MYMaousSxr6WQ15s5baqZlk4kUolrns3aJKbT2956UPWrQZNfgThN7DvWwW4w_X" alt=""/></figure>



<p>When asked for a statement, all Boeing delegates simply said “no comment” and the Lockheed Martin delegates have not replied to journalists requests for statements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In an attempt to find out more information, a journalist from the Chicago Tribune sat in on a Boeing committee session. Almost immediately after the journalist joined, a motion for a closed debate was passed unanimously, and the journalist was forced to leave. Shortly after leaving the committee session, an anonymous source reached out and revealed that the Senior Vice President of Finance and Treasury was the one who wrote the email.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The CEO of Boeing, in his own words, said “We are doing a lot of illegal stuff. We are committing, you know, campaign finance violations. We’re doing the same stuff the other companies are doing, but it is still illegal.” The SVP of Finance/Treasury was demoted to Finance and Treasurers intern almost as soon as the identity of the email writer was found. The CEO also added an addendum to the former SVP’s contract, adding an NDA and a non-compete clause.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">248</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BAE Systems Considering Lockheed Martin Partnership, In Turmoil</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/bae-systems-considering-lockheed-martin-partnership-in-turmoil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BAE Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a dramatic shift in the status quo of international technological contractors, UK-based company BAE Systems has initiated communications with Lockheed Martin. Executives are considering]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a dramatic shift in the status quo of international technological contractors, UK-based company BAE Systems has initiated communications with Lockheed Martin. Executives are considering a partnership with Lockheed Martin, with sharing of European transportation infrastructure and servers on the table, with other possibilities being cooperation on cybersecurity. However, terms of the deal are uncertain, and strong opposition to a merger is widespread. CIA partnerships have also been proposed, but have temporarily been tabled.</p>



<p>BAE Systems has faced turmoil, both internal and external, in recent months. Conflict within company leadership has also presented issues, as strong disagreement between BAE’s CEO and members of the board of directors has hampered progress on a deal and has already resulted in changes in position within the company. The corporation is bankrupt, and the implementation of a new CEO presents the opportunity for radical change in the company.</p>



<p>BAE Systems’ newly appointed CEO, Ms. Lisa Carr, has stated that the company’s current financial difficulties are entirely the responsibility of the previous CEO, Charles Woodburn, and has promised significant changes in the company’s strategy moving into 2021. It’s unclear exactly what these changes may include, but increased foreign partnership appears to be a very viable option, with potential markets including Europe, Asia, and the US. Division is present over the possibility of a Belarusian deal, with major decisions being revisited due to Belarus’s rapidly deteriorating situation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">163</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
