<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>ExxonMobil &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/tag/exxonmobil/feed/?simply_static_page=1491" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:40:37 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>ExxonMobil is making a playlist for Reception Tonight?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/exxonmobil-is-making-a-playlist-for-reception-tonight/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 21:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MTV just listened to ExxonMobil Board of Directors was asked to add some songs to a playlist for our Reception tonight, and boy it&#8217;s a]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>MTV just listened to ExxonMobil Board of Directors was asked to add some songs to a playlist for our Reception tonight, and boy it&#8217;s a good one!  The reason why MTV was invited was that the CEO of ExxonMobil told MTV, “We are all on fire. It is time to turn this ship around.” </p>



<p>Here is the Link to all of the Songs &#8211; <a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/5i110Ukju6zKUmHy7CKrFf?si=EWdn6qcKTU6Fsw5tsTI4IA">https://open.spotify.com/playlist/5i110Ukju6zKUmHy7CKrFf?si=EWdn6qcKTU6Fsw5tsTI4IA</a></p>



<p>The first song brought up was <strong>Eraser by Ed Sheeran.</strong> This song had absolutely no explanation and no significance, it failed 2 to 4. </p>



<p>The next song that was brought up was <strong>Mo Bamba by Sheck West</strong> But, alas, they choose to use the clean one. Their reason was for giggles because it doesn&#8217;t sound like the original. Hence, why it passed Unanimously! </p>



<p>Calling all Swifties! The next song is <strong>You Belong with Me by the Queen of Pop, T-Swift</strong>! This song was suggested by the VP of Corporate Strategic Planning. “The citizens on the tanker belong in our hearts.”</p>



<p>This next song was the biggest Party song (Pun intended) in the 2010s. <strong>Party in the U.S.A by Miley Cyrus. </strong>There was no exact reason why it was mentioned but none the matter. It passed unanimously.</p>



<p>This next song is very controversial, but nonetheless, it was mentioned. The song is <strong>Touch the Sky by Kanye West</strong>. The Board of Directors did a one-for and one-against debate for this song. The Director for this song was the VP of Public and Government Affairs. &#8220;It&#8217;s Musical genius! It’s just one song, it&#8217;s insane!” The director that was against the song was the VP of Corporate Strategic Planning. He said that &#8220;With everything going on with Kayne, do we want our public image to show we support Kayne? With everything against him, this could affect our image. This is your (VP of Public and Government Affairs) job and your reputation on the line.&#8221; Despite the VP of Public and Government Affairs speaking for this song, it failed unanimously. </p>



<p>This next song did the opposite of the Kayne song, it passed unanimously! This song is <strong>Runaway Baby by Bruno Mars</strong>. They also didn&#8217;t give me a reason why but it is a good song though!</p>



<p>The final song that was voted on failed. With 2 votes for and 4 votes against, was the song <strong>Butter by BTS</strong>. Even though they&#8217;re being enlisted into the army, they still are loved in people&#8217;s hearts. The now-former VP of Public and Government Affairs&#8217; explanation was butter equals oil in cooking, and ExxonMobil stands for oil. </p>



<p>The Board is very excited about the reception and can&#8217;t wait for the participants to hear the tunes playlist. If you have any suggestions for songs to add to the list, click the link below to add songs to the potential list!</p>



<p><a href="https://forms.gle/eu9nyhPhXTn4QeBx5">https://forms.gle/eu9nyhPhXTn4QeBx5</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
