<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/house-of-commons-of-the-united-kingdom-1982/feed/?simply_static_page=1258" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:34:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Patrick Wall: Traitor to the UK</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/patrick-wall-traitor-to-the-uk/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1663</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The House of Commons is discussing which member of parliament has been committing treasonous acts against the UK in the Falkland Islands. The Prime Minister]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="960" height="582" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-21.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1670" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-21.png 960w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-21-300x182.png 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-21-768x466.png 768w" sizes="(max-width: 960px) 100vw, 960px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">House of Commons furious about the betrayl</figcaption></figure>



<p>The House of Commons is discussing which member of parliament has been committing treasonous acts against the UK in the Falkland Islands. The Prime Minister revealed to the House of Commons that there was one member of parliament that created instability in the government and risked the lives of Argentinians and British citizens in the Falkland Islands and abroad. </p>



<p>The House believes that the traitor is Patrick Wall. &#8220;Patrick Wall has been switching his own policy from the beginning,&#8221; said one anonymous member of parliament. &#8220;He made one too many compromises with the Labour party and would do anything for his bill to go through. Also, his bowler hat sucks.&#8221; Another member said he was &#8220;mentally, physically, and emotionally abused by our traitor, Patrick Wall.&#8221; </p>



<p>Prime Minister Thatcher revived the intercepted note, detailing with irrefutable proof that the traitor is Patrick Wall. Wall is now considered a traitor to the UK and will be punished accordingly. The committee is convinced that Patrick Wall is at fault, and investigating how this treason occurred, leaving everyone wondering, what on earth is going on in the House of Commons?</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK House of Commons and Cabinet Respond to Emergency Crisis</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/uk-house-of-commons-and-cabinet-respond-to-emergency-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 21:58:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1624</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an emergency crisis early this morning the cabinet of the UK convened to solve the Falkland islands crisis and the Soviet control of the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In an emergency crisis early this morning the cabinet of the UK convened to solve the Falkland islands crisis and the Soviet control of the Afghan government. The Cabinet reached a new and restrengthened alliance between the US and the UK in regard to the Falkland Islands. The Falkland islands are off the southern coast of South America, and due to the close proximity of the US, their CIA will supply intelligence and put diplomatic pressure on the islands, as well as impose sanctions upon Argentina.<br>The cabinet then tackled the crisis of the USSR&#8217;s presence in Afghanistan. The UK cabinet is taking anti-communist actions and is in valiant support of the Mujahadeen and stands strong against communism. With the outcome of Ronald Regan&#8217;s health still uncertain, the UK may give into the demands of the USSR. The UK is firmly against communism but lacks the action and strength to defend democracy until the last second. The UK debated the possible idea of surrendering to Afghanistan and the USSR.</p>



<p><br>When Le Monde informed the UK cabinet of the Soviet invasion of the Afghan government, the UK responded by saying that the USSR just has close ties to the Afghan government working together, but there is no infiltration of the government. Despite direct quotes from the USSR ministers, the UK was adamant about this fact.</p>



<p><br>Additionally, with the betrayal in the house of commons, the cabinet is investigating the treasonous actions of a member of parliament initiating an offensive attack into the Falkland Islands risking the lives of the British and Argentinian people living there. The House of Commons, The UK Cabinet, and Margret Thatcher are all working diligently to investigate and prosecute the offender.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Anti-U.S. sentiment and division in House of Commons</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/anti-u-s-sentiment-and-division-in-house-of-commons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dia Murali, Buenos Aires Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 17:19:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1503</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Thatcher has inspired the conservatives to promote anti-U.S. rhetoric. Members of Parliament have claimed that &#8220;Britain is the greatest country in the world&#8221;, taking advantage]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Thatcher has inspired the conservatives to promote anti-U.S. rhetoric. Members of Parliament have claimed that &#8220;Britain is the greatest country in the world&#8221;, taking advantage of the current U.S. crisis to further their own agenda. At this moment in time, parts of the House of Commons are against the U.S. despite their generous promises of coal aid. The coal dispute is now in question by the U.K. and they are almost ready to go against the deal, which would result in the starvation and suffering of the British people. This spiteful decision neglects the needs of the British people, and for what reason? To frustrate the U.S.?</p>



<p>U.S. comments about Britain have &#8220;pissed Thatcher off&#8221; and the conservative House of Commons will of course stand by their Prime Minister. They go so far as to express their love for the PM by ending their statements with &#8220;I love Thatcher!&#8221; However, Prime Minister Thatcher sent a secret memo to the members of the conservative party in the House of Commons addressing unnamed party members that have &#8220;failed on their promises of loyalty to the United Kingdom.&#8221; The memo contains a thinly veiled threat to &#8220;take care of&#8221; potential &#8220;traitors&#8221;. The Labor Party and Conservative Party have always been at odds, but now the division in the House of Commons has seeped so deep that the close knit party is starting to divide. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The U.K. conquers Argentinian Falklands territory</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/the-u-k-conquers-argentinian-falklands-territory/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dia Murali, Buenos Aires Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 16:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Britain&#8217;s brutalization of Argentinian forces over the occupation of the Falklands seems to have inflated the egos of House of Commons representatives. They callously deem]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Britain&#8217;s brutalization of Argentinian forces over the occupation of the Falklands seems to have inflated the egos of House of Commons representatives. They callously deem this conflict as an &#8220;economic opportunity&#8221; and discuss plans to initiate a war with Argentina. The consensus of the body establishes that &#8220;war is imminent&#8221; and slanders Argentina by deeming the country as &#8220;aggressors.&#8221;</p>



<p>It is confirmed by a House of Commons member that the U.K. is working to &#8220;preemptively&#8221; attack Argentina. The only justification for this is Argentina&#8217;s supposed antagonizing of the U.K., which was merely a question of Argentina defending their rightful territory. This proposition of extreme violence serves as a statement to establish that the U.K. is &#8220;the greatest country in the world&#8221; and that &#8220;if war is what it takes to prove it, so be it.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Conservative Party in the House is working on a paper named &#8220;Beating Argentina Badly Efficiently&#8221; to begin militarizing the Falklands in an attempt to intimidate and bombard Argentina. The aggressively named paper is being kept under wraps to avoid attention from other nations—especially the U.S. The U.K. is looking to convert current residents of the Falklands to British citizens and extend U.K. infrastructure. Establishing a 45,000 strong military presence in the Falklands will serve to help Britain maintain its dictator-like control over the islands. The paper goes so far as to condone lethal violence and &#8220;extermination&#8221; against those &#8220;invaders&#8221; who oppose their reign.</p>



<p> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Rumors of U.S./U.K. conflict denied</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/rumors-of-u-s-u-k-conflict-denied/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dia Murali, Buenos Aires Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 15:17:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1264</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Rumors circulate about potential conflict between the ostensibly steadfast allies, the U.S. and the U.K. Alleged &#8220;protests&#8221; were observed to be occurring in the closed]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Rumors circulate about potential conflict between the ostensibly steadfast allies, the U.S. and the U.K.  Alleged &#8220;protests&#8221; were observed to be occurring in the closed session between the countries. </p>



<p>A House of Commons member accused a U.S. delegate of plotting to veto a U.K. proposal in relation to fighting against communism. </p>



<p>The House of Commons&#8217; reactions to certain topics discussed between the two countries during the signing of a new public treaty alludes to present conflicts, perhaps within the House itself. </p>



<p>The U.K. received extremely mixed reactions from the House when speaking about abolishing unions. Prime Minister Margaret Thatcher initially declined to comment on future union plans, but later established plans to rid the U.K. of all union organizations.</p>



<p>Accusations were thrown at the U.K. Secretary of Energy, with a member of the House calling them a potential &#8220;conservative traitor&#8221;. This was met with anger from Prime Minister Thatcher, who swiftly denied such a thing. </p>



<p>Despite all the evidence that points towards antagonism on these multiple levels, the U.S. Central Intelligence Director vehemently denies all accusations of conflict between the U.S. and the U.K.. President Ronald Reagan also firmly dismisses any such ideas. The bond between the two countries is only further strengthened by their mutual desire to end communism across the globe. Though the meeting between the two cabinets was initially hectic, their common goal and strong partnership prevailed. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK Prime Minister Divides the Conservative and the Labour Party</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/uk-prime-minister-divides-the-conservative-and-the-labour-party/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 02:43:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1244</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Questions with the prime minister resume in the British House of Commons discussing issues ranging from the recent crisis of a mob in Manchester protesting]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Questions with the prime minister resume in the British House of Commons discussing issues ranging from the recent crisis of a mob in Manchester protesting over the coal labour strike to England&#8217;s disdain for Ireland. The Prime Minister secured a deal with the USA to obtain enough coal for the UK to stay warm this winter and as long as the nation needs. The bill the Prime Minister is working on has to do with making union-themed violence a more harshly prosecuted crime and urges the House to vote for this bill. When questioned if Thatcher’s close personal relationship with American president Ronald Reagan influenced the bill, Thatcher responded by defending the strong relationship between the U.K. and the U.S.</p>



<p>Several ministers made suggestions and gave commentary about the hill, most notably Winston Churchill asking the Prime Minister if she thought that increasing interest rates for banks would be an adequate solution to solving the ongoing tense relationship between unions and the government, and the Prime Minister agreed that it was a brilliant idea, and plans to implement it soon.</p>



<p>The conservative party&#8217;s stronghold on parliament leads to the dismissal of labour party ideas and policy in the House. Labour party suggestions such as taking away excess spending money from citizens were completely overlooked and outright mocked. When the labour party brought up the leaked note detailing how there are traitors within the conservative party working diligently to oust Thatcher, the Prime Minister simply responded by saying that the conservative party is the dominant party, and the labour party is simply in the bitter majority.</p>



<p>Following the questioning, the ministers debated Thatcher&#8217;s commitment to her promises of supporting workers&#8217; rights and dissolving the monopoly unions have on the workforce. Thatcher was devoted to putting an end to union violence, but ministers are unconvinced. The divide between parties looms large over the House and is splitting the objectives like hair. Ministers noted Thatcher&#8217;s sentiments to be about dismantling unions when a large faction believes that simply limiting union power is enough. The House of Commons needs to be closely monitored as tensions continue to rise between the parties.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>House of Commons Update</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/house-of-commons-update/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Josie Barnes, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 01:21:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1181</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The House of Commons is getting loud! Plenty of commotion on the floor. If you pass the Monroe room, you will hear hissing, cheering, talking,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/house-of-commons-chamber-1986-1.webp" alt="" class="wp-image-1209" width="355" height="299" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/house-of-commons-chamber-1986-1.webp 1000w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/house-of-commons-chamber-1986-1-300x253.webp 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/house-of-commons-chamber-1986-1-768x648.webp 768w" sizes="(max-width: 355px) 100vw, 355px" /></figure>



<p>The House of Commons is getting loud! Plenty of commotion on the floor. If you pass the Monroe room, you will hear hissing, cheering, talking, clapping, etc. You will also hear the sound of multiple working papers in progress.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With around five working papers on the floor, they hope to address the domestic economic crisis and secure the homeland against external threats. Currently, a significant paper on the floor is the M.A.R.G.A.R.E.T (the act of making additional reforms, gains, and amends to revitalize the economic transformation act). The paper highlights the hopes to bring the parliament together in nonpartisan ways and recognize the need for British people and all included, especially given the ongoing recession and unstable job market. With multiple more papers on the floor, we are excited to see what is to come.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tensions Rise in the House of Commons</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/tensions-rise-in-the-house-of-commons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 17:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The House of Commons is invested in finding the best way to support the economy and how to deal with the power grab of unions,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The House of Commons is invested in finding the best way to support the economy and how to deal with the power grab of unions, ignoring the Falkland Islands crisis. Several Parliamentary members including Winston Churchill believed that the best way to support the British economy is to “increase interest value to decrease inflation.” Churchill fears that the UK is at risk of an economic depression. Churchill then questioned the prime minister about economic diversity, however, the Prime minister was unable to answer the question in full, leading to the question if the Prime Minister feels confident in their solutions to the economic crisis.</p>



<p><br>The Prime Minister is steering the committee into valuing workers&#8217; rights whilst warning parliamentary members that unions don’t support human rights and that union bosses are motivated solely by greed and selfishness. A parliamentary member emphasizes that human rights are stifled by unions.<br>The House of Commons is working towards deregulations in the British economy to let economies function to the best of their ability without unions undermining the effort.</p>



<p><br>Furthermore, the conservative party has split into factions. Half of the party aimed solely at ousting Margaret Thatcher from her position as Prime Minister, despite being a strong member of the conservative party. This divide has caused confusion about the other branch of the conservative party whose goal is to support workers&#8217; rights by restricting British unions.</p>



<p><br>The House of Commons is a tense, evolving situation that needs to be monitored closely as the split could cause emotions and a faction between the conservative party, leading to the labour party taking control of the House for the first time in years.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
