<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bill &amp; Melinda Gates Foundation &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2022/category/bill-melinda-gates-foundation/feed/?simply_static_page=118" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2022</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 20:24:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>A major political figure slid into my DMs and the Gates Foundation is planning on developing their own vaccine</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/a-major-political-figure-slid-into-my-dms-and-the-gates-foundation-is-planning-on-developing-their-own-vaccine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kate Ravenscroft, Huffington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 18:15:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bill & Melinda Gates Foundation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=486</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Welcome to the #Huff Post Influencer blog, written by yours truly. If you want a more entertaining summary of this article, feel free to follow]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Welcome to the #Huff Post Influencer blog, written by yours truly. If you want a more entertaining summary of this article, feel free to follow the Youtube link: <a href="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oSoLISA_DUs" data-type="URL" data-id="https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oSoLISA_DUs">https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=oSoLISA_DUs</a> If you think you take yourself too seriously, feel free to proceed <img src="https://s.w.org/images/core/emoji/14.0.0/72x72/1f642.png" alt="🙂" class="wp-smiley" style="height: 1em; max-height: 1em;" /></p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="#huffpostinfluencer1 A SOMEWHAT MAJOR POLITICAL FIGURE slid into my DMS (not clickbait)" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/k9WZSeSOYkY?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<p>After being kicked out of the U.S. Cabinet Friday evening by an aggressive CIA director and a sympathetic, albeit totally cool, President Biden, I may or may not have found myself stumbling into the Bill and Melinda Gates Foundation committee. I was greeted by the one and only Bill Gates himself, and quickly ushered into a meeting. At the time, the committee was in deep discussion surrounding current COVID-19 directives. </p>



<h2 id="i-was-totally-annoying">I was totally annoying </h2>



<p>and may or may not have interrupted a functional caucus in order to ask my silly little press question about my silly little assigned beat. </p>



<p>Q: &#8220;Does the Bill and Melinda Gates foundation have any plans to prepare for a potential future global health crisis?&#8221; </p>



<p>&#8230;the room fell silent and I was afraid the answer was &#8220;not really,&#8221; ALTHOUGH I am happy to report that this is not, in fact, the case. </p>



<p>“We are planning on more closely working with the WHO and governments in order to ensure vaccine development and distribution and providing support to civilians at this time, admittedly with a focus on COVID-19,” the Chief Strategy Officer said.</p>



<p>They continued to elaborate for 10 minutes although unfortunately, the passage of time is a thing that exists and by the next time I clocked into the IPD staff room, developments had already progressed past the vague statements which proceeded the quote above.</p>



<h2 id="i-received-a-dm-from-a-major-political-figure">I received a DM from a major political figure???!!!</h2>



<p>During my preparation for the first committee this morning, I received a DM from the Chief of Diversity, Equity and Inclusion officer from the &#8220;Billy Milly G FUNdation,&#8221; (BMGF) as he referred to it, explaining to me how they passed a new directive! </p>



<ul><li>BMGF to pay $2.5 billion for the construction of 5 new international Pfizer vaccine manufacturing facilities </li><li>Focusing aforementioned facilities in the Global South in order to reach areas with low vaccine stats</li><li>New facilities intended to be near airports in order to reduce carbon footprint <em>(impressive environmental concerns for a mainstream foundation)</em></li><li>$500 million to be given to international NGOs for distribution of vaccinations</li></ul>



<p>A concern of these directives is their lack of focus on the future: to many, it may appear that the Gates Foundation is doing too much, too late. Although these efforts are COVID focused, it has been heavily implied to me that the foundation would be able to use these facilities in order to produce other vaccines in the future, and that the facilities could be viewed as potential preparation for future global health crises. </p>



<p>Additionally, some may express concern for the massive nature of these financial commitments. Notably, the CFO was relatively silent in these meetings, to an arguably worrying extent. Is the Gates Foundation running with their romanticized version of a plan without considering the reality of the financing behind it? </p>



<h2 id="billymillygfundation-plans-to-develop-their-own-covid-19-vaccine">#BillyMillyGFUNdation Plans to develop their own COVID-19 Vaccine</h2>



<p>This morning, when I entered the Gates foundation Zoom room unannounced just to check in with my beat, they were in deep discussion, led by the Chief Communications Officer (who very much seems to be in charge of this whole ordeal at the moment), concerning the potential development of a Gates vaccine in order to even better accommodate their current directives. </p>



<p>If this is so, the implication of said vaccine development could mean the immersion of the Gates foundation into the vaccine and pharmaceutical market as a whole. Future #Google Vaccines might just change our perception of vaccination as we know it. Stay tuned!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
