<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>AP Wire &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/ap-wire/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:52:22 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Press Release from The Kennedy Administration</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-the-kennedy-administration/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:44:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=464</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good afternoon esteemed members of the press, The Kennedy Administration is ecstatic to announce a huge step forward in world peace. We have had a]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Good afternoon esteemed members of the press,</p>



<p>The Kennedy Administration is ecstatic to announce a huge step forward in world peace. We have had a breakthrough in negotiations with the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics in that they have agreed to remove their nuclear missiles from Cuba in exchange for the United States removing their nuclear missiles from Turkey. Therefore we are delighted to inform the American people that they can sleep well at night with there no longer being an enemy nuclear power 103 miles away from the American mainland.<br></p>



<p>Delightfully,</p>



<p>The Kennedy Administration</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release from The Kennedy Administration Regarding the Death of Eleanor Roosevelt</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-the-kennedy-administration-regarding-the-death-of-eleanor-roosevelt/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:42:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=461</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Good evening fellow Americans, I am deeply saddened to announce the passing of former First Lady Eleanor Roosevelt. Through her time as the First Lady,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Good evening fellow Americans,</p>



<p>I am deeply saddened to announce the passing of former First Lady Eleanor Roosevelt. Through her time as the First Lady, she made many great strides in championing women&#8217;s rights. Her legacy will live on through the recent passing of legislation by the PCSW on the status of women&#8217;s rights in the US.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Somberly,</p>



<p>The Kennedy Administration</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Castro announces nuclear capabilities, takes credit for downed U2 spy plane</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/castro-announces-nuclear-capabilities-takes-credit-for-downed-u2-spy-plane/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:59:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=370</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="CIMUN XX - A speech by Castro" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/pYF3LZ5qoaU?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release from Tencent</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-tencent/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As of today, allegations have raised concerns over the operations of Tencent. We are disappointed by the existence of such allegations. As a company, we]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As of today, allegations have raised concerns over the operations of Tencent. We are disappointed by the existence of such allegations. As a company, we are fully committed to the safety and privacy of our consumers and the creation of a positive user environment. We will continue to provide our highly-rated and important services to our customers along with our guaranteed online protections. Thank you</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release from USSR</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-ussr/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:22:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Union of Soviet Socialist Republics (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=309</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Comrades, the recent escalation of actions towards Cuba with blockades has only shown theaggression of Capitalism. We have been forced to reinforce our border to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Comrades, the recent escalation of actions towards Cuba with blockades has only shown the<br>aggression of Capitalism. We have been forced to reinforce our border to protect our allies in<br>the Warsaw Pact and abroad. We would like to inform the world that these actions are not<br>meant to be aggressive, only protective. The USSR is still strong and supporting our allies<br>against possible actions of US aggression. We want to lend a humanitarian hand where the US<br>won&#8217;t. Under communism you will be supported, under communism you are free. Now is the<br>time of communism and now is the time for safety which is why the USSR is entering peaceful<br>negotiations with the US regarding nuclear weapons, to show our generosity and equality.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release from X Board of Directors</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-x-board-of-directors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 20:59:50 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=299</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[We will handle these fake allegations with grace and efficiency. X as a company prides ourselves as upstanding and lawful. The accusations made against our]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>We will handle these fake allegations with grace and efficiency. X as a company prides ourselves as upstanding and lawful. The accusations made against our Chair of Legal Department along with the blatant attack on X-connect are excessive. We are not unlawful and our business never violated U.S. policy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release from the Tencent Board of Directors</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-the-tencent-board-of-directors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=230</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tencent would like to respond to concerns over our claimed expansion to western markets. Tencent is unaware of the source of these claims. Tencent has]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Tencent would like to respond to concerns over our claimed expansion to western markets. Tencent is unaware of the source of these claims. Tencent has always been a Chinese company, and our business interests and WeChat user base primarily exists within China. The rumors over western expansion are just that &#8211; rumors. Tencent is committed to providing communication and technological improvements throughout China, and this is our primary goal as we look towards the future. We are currently discussing sustainable climate initiatives like our previously stated carbon neutrality by 2060 plan. Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
