<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Tencent Corporate Board &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/pd-committees/tencent-corporate-board/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 21:56:04 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Who Can Be Trusted?: Tencent Disregards Accusations of Spreading Misinformation on Taiwanese Election</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/who-can-be-trusted-tencent-disregards-accusations-of-spreading-misinformation-on-taiwanese-election/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 21:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a run-in with an anonymous source from the Tencent Corporate Board (TNCT), the Washington Post was able to gather that a response to the allegations]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a run-in with an anonymous source from the Tencent Corporate Board (TNCT), the Washington Post was able to gather that a response to the allegations of spreading misinformation about the Taiwanese election. Tencent made it clear that the Chinese tech conglomerate stands by the results of the election and expresses wishes for the nations of the world to respect said results as well.</p>



<p>The source claimed that the accusations against Tencent are simply due to negative US sentiments held against China and its enterprises, leading to finger-pointing whenever the western press sees fit. </p>



<p>Especially in a world where the truth can be so easily manipulated by those in power and of influence. The Washington Post stands with the publications and journalists internationally that practice their craft ethically, and contribute their energy to the fight of bringing life to the truth, no matter the issue or stakes at hand</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tencent announces new app to rival X-Connect</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/tencent-announces-new-app-to-rival-x-connect/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Swadha Garnaik, BBC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 08:42:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=482</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the midst of China&#8217;s election crisis, Tencent has confirmed that they have no stance on current political issues. While expressing regret for the civil]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the midst of China&#8217;s election crisis, Tencent has confirmed that they have no stance on current political issues. While expressing regret for the civil unrest, they have unequivocally disclaimed that they are not at all involved with the election. However, they are actively engaged with exciting new developments as they announced &#8220;Link&#8221; at the latest press conference. Similar to X-Connect, Link is also a so-called &#8220;everything app,&#8221; allowing users to access multiple services through one cohesive program. Tencent describes unique features such as consumer subscription, benefits including points and reward systems, and integrated access to companies. Delegates should be looking out for what Tencent will present next!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New X, New Problems?: X Loses Two Board Members and Takes on Three in Replacement</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/new-x-new-problems-x-loses-two-board-members-and-takes-on-three-in-replacement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Elon Musk has made his decision. At approximately 9:15pm on Dec. 8, 2023, X saw two of its board members promptly resign upon the announcement]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Elon Musk has made his decision. At approximately 9:15pm on Dec. 8, 2023, X saw two of its board members promptly resign upon the announcement of Mr. Musk possibly taking members off the board himself. These members were the Director of Marketing and Director of Operations, and upon their resignation they donated all of their stocks to the charity foundations backed by Elon Musk. In their replacement, the X corporate board added a Director of Investments in addition to a Department Chair of IT. </p>



<p>Furthermore, rival company Tencent has gained 10% of X&#8217;s shares in a previous transaction with Vanguard, an investment management company. Due to Tencent holding at least a 10% share within the corporation, they have earned themselves a seat at the table of X&#8217;s corporate board, one with the additional right to cast votes that can held guide the course in which things go for the corporation</p>



<p>Now, X struggles yet again with internal issues that could prove detrimental to the security of the board as an American corporation as well as users of X and X-Connect.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release from Tencent</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-tencent/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:35:57 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=321</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As of today, allegations have raised concerns over the operations of Tencent. We are disappointed by the existence of such allegations. As a company, we]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As of today, allegations have raised concerns over the operations of Tencent. We are disappointed by the existence of such allegations. As a company, we are fully committed to the safety and privacy of our consumers and the creation of a positive user environment. We will continue to provide our highly-rated and important services to our customers along with our guaranteed online protections. Thank you</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Press Release from the Tencent Board of Directors</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/press-release-from-the-tencent-board-of-directors/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 17:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=230</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tencent would like to respond to concerns over our claimed expansion to western markets. Tencent is unaware of the source of these claims. Tencent has]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Tencent would like to respond to concerns over our claimed expansion to western markets. Tencent is unaware of the source of these claims. Tencent has always been a Chinese company, and our business interests and WeChat user base primarily exists within China. The rumors over western expansion are just that &#8211; rumors. Tencent is committed to providing communication and technological improvements throughout China, and this is our primary goal as we look towards the future. We are currently discussing sustainable climate initiatives like our previously stated carbon neutrality by 2060 plan. Thank you.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Liveblog (Present Day)</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/friday-liveblog-present-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael McCarthy, Deputy USG for Media]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
