<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Associated Press Wire &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/author/apwire/feed/?simply_static_page=1473" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 03:05:27 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Statement from the USSR Cabinet of Ministers</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/statement-from-the-ussr-cabinet-of-ministers/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 03:05:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Soviet Union (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1297</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Unfortunately we are reluctant to inform the press that the Minister of Finance has been murdered by a Right Wing in a USSR city. This]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Unfortunately we are reluctant to inform the press that the Minister of Finance has been murdered by a Right Wing in a USSR city. This rightist group has been put to justice by the Council of Ministers and is no longer active. We will sorely miss this Minister among our rules, and the finance sector will never be the same. </p>



<p>Respectfully, </p>



<p>USSR Cabinet of Ministers</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Cabinet Press Release</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/u-s-cabinet-press-release/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:28:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To the Citizens of the United States of America, The United States of America would like to clarify information surrounding our recent deal with EXXON]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To the Citizens of the United States of America,<br><br>The United States of America would like to clarify information surrounding our recent deal with EXXON Mobil, as well as reinforce the principles we are making this decision based on. Businesses are not taking advantage of the war, rather, they are being used as a means to combat it. Providing $1.5 billion in subsidies to EXXON Mobil, given their recent commitment to sustainability, we ensure that peacemaking and sustainable development projects go hand-in-hand. We are by no means encouraging drilling within the United States, rather allocating funds towards environmental research, programs, and peacemaking in Ukraine.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Stressing unity during this time, we are open to working with multiple private companies towards the overarching goal of benefiting global trade. Ukraine’s closed port in Odessa poses a threat towards food insecurity and the approach to overall conflict within the international trade community. The Russian government has been very stubborn in its efforts of blockades, further harming the Ukrainian people. The UNSC has been working diligently to solve this issue, and the Cabinet of the United States is committed to helping them accomplish their goal.&nbsp;</p>



<p>We also understand that there are some domestic concerns regarding this decision. We would like to affirm that this deal with EXXON Mobil will strongly benefit our own citizens, as it will lower domestic gas prices. We continue to stay firm in our focus on sustainable development, which is why we are specifically providing a significant portion of this funding for research and development regarding increased sustainability. There are many dissenters who believe this is a move from Big Oil to simply increase production, but we would like to clarify that the Cabinet is trying to increase supply so the domestic prices of oil will go down, and benefit the American people. The money will be used on subsidies, but a significant portion will also be used on sustainability research to allow the U.S to reach its environmental goals. We also firmly emphasize that we will not be increasing the amount of drilling. Rather, we will be using the funds allocated to EXXON Mobil to lower gas and oil prices, as well as to promote further sustainability in the industry.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sincerely,<br>President Joe Biden and the Cabinet of the United States of America</p>


<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="aligncenter is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/YUANkFdIu9F34kQt2JCvhtpcMkXbn1HoHp1fTtvtSFIGUie_cJtvS8Ly59zhjOWtnWww2O5OMzPoz2KLK50wjinb_WwYFMXVsWh0ulVeLZqHa3TS7ZwY54zev_C-hAEMN9QIKScnSM0CwG5j174PiLI" alt="" width="306" height="213"/></figure></div>]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
