<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Associated Press Wire &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2021/author/apwire/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 01:18:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>General Dynamics Insider Publicly Reaches Out to Belarus</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/general-dynamics-insider-publicly-reaches-out-to-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Dynamics Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear General Major General Viktor Khrenin, Minister of Defense of Belarurs,Gulfstream feels for you and your grieving country at this time. However, we realize your]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Dear General Major General Viktor Khrenin, Minister of Defense of Belarurs,<br>Gulfstream feels for you and your grieving country at this time. However, we realize your need of protection during these difficult times of forming yopur Democracy. If you are interested, Gulfstream would like to provide aircrafts for your military. Payment programs are available. If you are interested like me know and we can work put further details. -VP/CFO of Gulfstream</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">284</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>DoD Whistleblower: Biden Team Knew of Misconduct at Raytheon under Lloyd Austin</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/dod-whistleblower-biden-team-knew-of-misconduct-at-raytheon-under-lloyd-austin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:01:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=270</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Investigators from the Department of the Navy, on orders from the DoD, found massive accounting discrepancies and fraudulent contract behaviors at the defense contractor, Raytheon.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Investigators from the Department of the Navy, on orders from the DoD, found massive accounting discrepancies and fraudulent contract behaviors at the defense contractor, Raytheon. The investigators found that President Joe Biden and his transition team knew about these discrepancies, and still appointed Former General Lloyd Austin to be Secretary of Defense. The whistleblower alleges that the White House sent a staffer to the Pentagon to kill the investigation, and the DoD complied. The House Armed Forces committee has stated they will be launching an investigation</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">270</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Korean Government Recognizes Choi Jung-Hoon As Leader of North Korea</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/south-korean-government-recognizes-choi-jung-hoon-as-leader-of-north-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 22:13:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=239</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To our beloved people of South Korea and the esteemed citizens of the world,The Republic of Korea recognizes Choi Jung-Hoon of the North Korea People’s]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To our beloved people of South Korea and the esteemed citizens of the world,<br>The Republic of Korea recognizes Choi Jung-Hoon of the North Korea People’s Liberation Front as the rightful leader of North Korea. He has long been an advocate for democracy, freedom, and peace in North Korea, and is committed to denuclearization, cooperation, mutual prosperity, and most importantly, reunification. Choi Jung-Hoon was born in North Korea, and will be an upstanding leader for the long-oppressed masses of North Korea. Mr. Choi will be not just a new face to represent North Korea, but a new future: one where citizens are not starving, where they are not imprisoned for expressing their thoughts, where they are free to go where they want and be who they want to be. We look forward to negotiating with the next leader of North Korea, Choi Jung-Hoon, and bridging the gap between us.<br>&#8211; The Office of the President</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">239</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A Statement from the Office of the President  of South Korea</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/a-statement-from-the-office-of-the-president-of-south-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:43:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=227</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[At this time, the Office of the President is wary of the destabilization occurring in North Korea, and intends to prevent this destabilization from harming]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>At this time, the Office of the President is wary of the destabilization occurring in North Korea, and intends to prevent this destabilization from harming our citizens and residents in any way. We feel that peace is the best response to all potential crises at this time, and encourage our neighbors and allies to commit to peace on the Korean peninsula. We hope that North Korea is able to experience a peaceful transition of power to their next leader, and that we may work with whomever that leader may be to achieve denuclearization and reunification.</p>



<p>The Presidential Cabinet of the Republic of Korea has moved to increase our alert level from Jindogae 3 to Jindogae 2, and as a result, advise all citizens to report any signs of North Korean aggression at home to the police. Our citizens’ safety is our top priority, and as a result, we have decided to install joint military and police checkpoints around the country to ensure this safety. We encourage all residents to, as always, have knowledge of where their nearest bomb shelter lies, not because we believe that there is imminent internal conflict in North Korea that will lead to attacks on our soil, but because we must proceed with an abundance of caution, given the volatility of the situation. We encourage any members of the public to direct their questions to local government officials, who will answer any questions they can, and who will relay any other questions to Presidential Cabinet members.</p>



<p>We encourage all residents to remain calm at this time.</p>



<p>Signed,</p>



<p>The Office of the President</p>



<p></p>



<p>Should you have any questions regarding our recent press release, please direct them to the South Korean Home Government, who will then relay questions to the Prime Minister, the Minister of Foreign Affairs, and the Minister of Economy and Finance, as well as the cabinet at large, if requested. These questions may be answered in writing, but reporters may also request a video or voice conference. Please note that we cannot guarantee that all questions will be answered, regardless of relevancy.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">227</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bluebird Aero to Sell drones to new Belarus Government</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/bluebird-aero-to-sell-drones-to-new-belarus-government/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 20:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bluebird Aero Systems]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An excerpt from a new directive from the Board of the Israeli-based Bluebird Aero Systems: Sells drones to Belarus Unrestricted line of sales to Belarus]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>An excerpt from a new directive from the Board of the Israeli-based Bluebird Aero Systems:</p>



<ul><li>Sells drones to Belarus</li><li>Unrestricted line of sales to Belarus</li></ul>



<ol><li>Sells the new Belarusian government under Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya the requested combat drones as part of its widespread reform of the military.</li><li>Offers an unrestricted line of access to the Belarusian government to purchase more products from Bluebird</li></ol>



<p>This story is developing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">207</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>A New Day for Belarus?</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/a-new-day-for-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 18:39:41 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=177</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Belarus has a new government in place after a mystifying and contested series of events earlier in the day. At noon, electricity, cell service, and]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Belarus has a new government in place after a mystifying and contested series of events earlier in the day. At noon, electricity, cell service, and internet service all went out for exactly three hours, and when these utilities returned, a televised broadcast was beamed to all televisions in the country. The message was a speech by the newly named President Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya addressing the nation, saying that “Democracy has won and it is a bright new day for the Belauran people”. Armed security forces without clear identifications have locked down the city and arrested prominent pro-Russia figures. There has been no comment as of yet from the other claimed leader of Belarus, Viktor Khrenin, and his whereabouts and condition is unknown. This story is developing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">177</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Northrop-Gruman and L3 Harris Technologies announce Merger</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/northrop-gruman-and-l3-harris-technologies-announce-merger/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 18:11:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[L3 Harris Technologies]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Northrop Grumman Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=168</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Press Communique from Northrop G. Harris III: Northrop Grumman Corp is delighted to announce the publication of the merger with American technology company L3 Harris.&#160;]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Press Communique from Northrop G. Harris III:</p>



<p>Northrop Grumman Corp is delighted to announce the publication of the merger with American technology company L3 Harris.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The merger of Northrop Grumman and L3 Harris will herald a new age of global arms cooperation in the service of expanding democracy. To this end, we will continue to support the United States Government in all of its endeavors, on land, across the seas, aerospace, cybersecurity, and the final frontier. The new company, now to be known as Northrop G. Harris III, intends to extend our diversified defense technologies to a truly global market.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the world stage is always evolving, Northrop G. Harris III will be at the forefront of technology and innovation. We will be “fast and forward while redefining possible.” This merger is one combining two complementary companies that will allow us to offer stronger and more innovative technologies than ever before. Through the combination of revenue for two secure companies, our combined revenue is now the strongest on the market, with the highest quality of resources to be developed for this project. This merging will also allow us to create stronger, more effective products which will pressure other companies in the defense industry to improve their products as well, increasing competition. Additionally, effective leadership will allow us to move forward into the cybersecurity field, supporting the contracting needs of our clients in an evolving world.</p>



<p>Northrop G. Harris III intends to look towards governments for direction on the technologies and resources needed and will consistently support what is just. We will be “fast and forward while redefining possible” in achieving what’s best for global democracy and international cooperation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Signed,&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Executive Board of Northrop G. Harris III</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">168</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Multiple Protestors Killed in Demonstrations against Military Rule in Belarus</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/multiple-protestors-killed-in-protests-against-military-rule-in-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:33:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=149</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[15 protestors were shot and killed and dozens more were injured as violence broke out during protests against military rule in the capital city of]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>15 protestors were shot and killed and dozens more were injured as violence broke out during protests against military rule in the capital city of Minsk. It is estimated that potentially thousands of others have been detained and arrested. The situation in the country is made worse by the fact that ICU beds are currently at 100% capacity as the Covid-19 pandemic continues to stretch the nation’s resources. In a country that has lived under a rigid dictatorship since the end of the Cold War, resentment to military rule continues to grow among the population, as former presidential candidate Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya continues to call for a full transition to democracy. General Khrenin has imposed a 9PM curfew for all citizens and has called for restoring order and peace. This story is developing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">149</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UK-Based BAE Systems to work with CIA</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/uk-based-bae-systems-to-work-with-cia/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:29:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[BAE Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=143</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Top level executives in BAE Systems corporation have confirmed that their leadership board has reached out independently of the UK Government to work with the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Top level executives in BAE Systems corporation have confirmed that their leadership board has reached out independently of the UK Government to work with the US CIA. These executives have been independently verified by AP News but have chosen to remain anonymous since they are not authorized  to speak on the matter. No comment from Boris Johnson. This story is developing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">143</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Deteriorating Situation in Belarus</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/deteriorating-situation-in-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:26:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=134</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[BREAKING NEWS &#8211; MINSK- The situation in Belarus appears to be rapidly deteriorating, as an explosion rocked the capital in the early morning. The primary]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>BREAKING NEWS &#8211; MINSK- The situation in Belarus appears to be rapidly deteriorating, as an explosion rocked the capital in the early morning. The primary opposition leader, Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya, was nearly the victim of a car-bombing that claimed the life of a close friend who was allegedly borrowing her car. This latest act of violence has inflamed an already tumultuous civil society that is increasingly chaotic. This story is developing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">134</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
