<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>League of Arab States (1982) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/league-of-arab-states-1982/feed/?simply_static_page=1249" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 03:37:10 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Iran Gains New Allies in Iran-Iraq War</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/iran-gains-new-allies-in-iran-iraq-war/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hongtao Hu, The Sun]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 01:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of Iraq (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[League of Arab States (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran-Iraq War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Sun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1223</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently,&#160; the Iranian Cabinet has gained additional allies in the Iran-Iraq war, countering the support the Arab League provides to Iraq’s military, of which appears]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/p4rOMIyh9qeN9oWDs5Ptr0KrPE1wXKpPFVXWIBHHB6-P8TiQYUCh26-3o__0GzTseJ-LXjMq3Umk858KdBmbVc-WeXjUxaKfz87UA_Jl9nCDltF9_AXNRkLBrGwKIuCdWivys5xZn_zzU2qRNYzxBhM" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Recently,&nbsp; the Iranian Cabinet has gained additional allies in the Iran-Iraq war, countering the support the Arab League provides to Iraq’s military, of which appears to be more divided than it may seem.</p>



<p>Iraq, as part of the Arab League, has long had resources to draw upon from its neighboring countries. Such support from the Arab League was demonstrated today, when Iraq’s Minister of Foreign Affairs delivered a rousing speech claiming that Iraq would achieve stability in the Middle East if it defeated Iran in the ongoing Iran-Iraq war. Conversely, the minister also warned of the consequences in the event of an Iranian victory: “If Iran wins this war, then it poses a threat to the entire Middle East”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, during a question and answer segment, detractors spoke up: the delegation from Libya questioned Iraq’s “aggressive” stance in the invasion of Iran, to which the Foreign Minister stated: “Iraq is the sword that protects the entire Middle East”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is important to note that Iran is not in the Arab League. However, this does not mean that Iran is without allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In a recent interview The Sun conducted with The Minister of Petroleum in the Iran Cabinet, he stated that the Iranian Cabinet had written directives to ally with and buy weapons from Romania and North Yemen, adding: “When we are going to other countries, we are not going for some ideological basis that has been perpetuated by the Cold War”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is cooperated by a document The Sun obtained from the Iran Cabinet, where “R” stands for Romania and “NY” stands for North Yemen.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="1024" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-1024x1024.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-1227" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-1024x1024.jpeg 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-300x300.jpeg 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-150x150.jpeg 150w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-768x768.jpeg 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-1536x1536.jpeg 1536w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1.jpeg 1735w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>What does this mean for Iraq? Well, we can turn to a correspondence the delegate for Iraq in the Arab League sent to their cabinet. This war will not only be a “war of attention” that the delegate most certainly misspelled, as both countries may turn to additional Western countries for aid, but also a “war of attrition” where evenly matched militaries reach a deadlock, where they each attempt to capture yards, not kilometers of territory. Even if the delegate for Iraq made a simple spelling error, this time, it’s important to listen to what he means, and<strong> </strong>what he says. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
