<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>United Nations Security Council &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/pd-committees/united-nations-security-council/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:56:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. cabinet: cry for action</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/u-s-cabinet-cry-for-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=651</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for pressuring China with the situation in Taiwan, and the proposal of possible sanctions which the UNSC is open to was discussed. </p>



<p>The U.S. cabinet currently already has ships in Japan for a diplomatic presence in the region, moving forward with sanctions they feel will be the most effective way Additionally, they feel that these harder sanctions will pressure China about their wrongdoings and have more international pressure about correcting their wrongs. </p>



<p>The representative from the UNSC had advised that there is a firm reason for these sanctions on China, and that the body does whatever they can in significance with their cause, supporting Taiwan. </p>



<p>Later on, in the press conference, the United States cabinet, madam Press Secretary had explained that the United States was shocked by China’s reaction to the call for a revote. The U.S. has time and time again reached out to the PRC yet has received no response, but the PRC was reported to barge into the U.S. cabinet&#8217;s closed session when it was “most convenient for them.” China’s sudden aggression within Taiwan now gives the U.S. reason to believe that there is heavy Chinese involvement, as their own social media platform, Tencent has also been explicitly spreading disinformation that directly influenced the results of the election. </p>



<p>The cabinet has also called upon the UNSC to help with the current issues within Taiwan, specifically the corruption seen within the election and the democracy impeded from within it. Additionally, they have coordinated asking for how the UNSC will choose to move forward with China’s actions as the U.S. government specifically will no longer be contacting the Chinese government due to the “disrespect of sanctity diplomacy.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>An intercepted source has also let us know that China is threatening the U.S. and threatening to get rid of some things that are unknown in regard to the U.S. The U.S. economy also is thriving and has no further need for China. </p>



<p>Furthermore, in an interview with UN Ambassador Linda Thomas Greenfield, “The U.S. is trying their best in order to help Taiwan as the United States has empathy for all and they are heavily focused on the economy to help our citizens. Alongside this, we are arranging a meeting with the U.S. delegation from the Security Council as their input is valuable.”</p>



<p>The response from the UNSC is still being awaited and more developments will continue as debate on the next steps to be taken continue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PRESS CONFERENCE: United States is Shocked China&#8217;s Actions</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/press-conference-united-states-is-shocked-chinas-actions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between the two countries. The U.S. representative has sensed some aggression from China, also shown through how they have allowed themselves to come into meetings with no prior conversation. </p>



<p>The United States has further commentary on the fact that China has said they do not want forgiven involvement at the moment because of any possible influence on their election. Yet, the United States mentioned how the Chinese app, Tencent,  is spreading misinformation and has directly influenced China’s election. Showing that even with no current foreign relations, there are still direct influences on their election via the country’s social media app. Was it really worth it to cut connections with other countries that have not had an influence when you country has had an influence first? </p>



<p>Due to the previous actions that China has taken, the United States feels that China is rejecting any possible diplomatic offers. Furthermore, the U.S. has called upon the United Nations Security Council to help deal with these issues in China and even Taiwan as it is going to be needed to keep international peace between countries. After coordinating with the U.S. Security Council representative, the U.S. is urging the most powerful peacekeeping body in the world to help to deal with China’s actions as quickly and as effectively as possible. Now, the United States will no longer be in contact with the China government because of all the previously mentioned issues and that they have disrespected diplomacy. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China Expresses Discontent With an Article They say is &#8220;Unrepresentative of Our Beliefs&#8221;</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/china-expresses-discontent-with-an-article-they-say-is-unrepresentative-of-our-beliefs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the morning of Dec. 9, 2023, The Times of India published a piece on China recently using it&#8217;s veto power within the United Nations]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On the morning of Dec. 9, 2023, The Times of India published a piece on China recently using it&#8217;s veto power within the United Nations Security Council (UNSC) to vote against providing humanitarian aid for the for the Russia-Ukraine war. &#8220;This is a blatant example of poor press from the Times of India&#8221; says the Chinese delegation.</p>



<p>In interviews with both the Washington Post and Xinhua State News Agency, China explained that the delegation has every right to execute its veto powers in the UNSC whenever the state deems it necessary and that the veto was used in this instance specifically due to China believing that the Security Council should be diverting more of it&#8217;s time to the development of peace talks. In a sense, China seeks to pour more funding into preventing additional conflict between the nations, rather than simply supplying the band-aids to heal those affected by it.</p>



<p>China expressed to the Post directly that it was actually disappointed in the direction that the UNSC has been moving in and that &#8220;the lack of action from the Security Council to even issue a statement requesting peace talks is honesty a tragedy in and of itself and reflects extremely poorly upon the UNSC, especially when aid packages have already been sent before.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China: Humanitarian Aid is a Given</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/china-humanitarian-aid-is-a-given-ready-to-be-published/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As more debate arises in the Security Council on the Russia-Ukraine War, China raises its position on the solution by vetoing the resolution of humanitarian]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As more debate arises in the Security Council on the Russia-Ukraine War, China raises its position on the solution by vetoing the resolution of humanitarian aid in the council.</p>



<p>The reason for this is that China believes through this crisis the Security Council has failed to commit to helping the major crisis going on within Ukraine. If the Security Council cannot commit to the bigger task that was at hand the act for humanitarian aid should be put at a pause.</p>



<p>The Security Council failed to amend a peace talk between Russia and Ukraine and has failed to release any statement on the matter. The representative from China commented, &#8220;it shows a lack of commitment towards ending a War&#8221; and putting funds toward humanitarian aid would be unreasonable due to the lack of commitment the Council has. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNSC: Disappointment Over Veto</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/unsc-disappointment-over-veto/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:01:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=534</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UN Security Council is facing debates over the humanitarian aid paper as China has used its veto power and has vetoed the idea of]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The UN Security Council is facing debates over the humanitarian aid paper as China has used its veto power and has vetoed the idea of humanitarian aid for the Russia-Ukraine war.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The sole purpose of this paper was to help both sides in the conflict, as seen in the proposed paper, by being able to have equal sponsors and aid sent on both sides for the reason of basic human equality. It was supposed to help the millions of civilians living in distress, which now seems a hard goal to reach. </p>



<p>The United States has had very strong opinions regarding this situation as they do not support the use of the veto. The United States is against China’s veto in the humanitarian aid paper as there was perhaps no true basis for China to use its powers. It is also important to note that this humanitarian aid paper was supported by the Russian Federation. </p>



<p>In an interview with the United States, they expressed their deep disappointment, saying, “humanitarian aid was crucial, and support for both eastern and western powers was on this paper. It is disappointing that China has used its veto powers.” </p>



<p>Changes occur rapidly within this conflict and the UNSC’s debate only further stretches out the future of this nation. </p>



<p><br></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Peace Talks&#8221; are Not an Option</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/peace-talks-are-not-an-option/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 03:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The delegations of China and Brazil have proposed peace in the Russia-Ukraine War and it has just been shut down by the Western delegations. Humanitarian]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p> The delegations of China and Brazil have proposed peace in the Russia-Ukraine War and it has just been shut down by the Western delegations. Humanitarian aid is not the problem here; it is the Western bloc of nations in the Security Council refusing to bring peace to the Ukrainian nation. In the republic stance, there were refusals from the council denying any concessions of military aid along with a refusal of ceasefire with Brazil commenting that they thought it would help Russia and save Ukrainian lives which China and Brazil state is &#8220;ridiculous&#8221;.</p>



<p>&#8220;Politics are playing too big of a conflict in this War,&#8221; says China, and Brazil and China are at a neutral stance to the War. Nations have denied peace talks and ceasefire and are assuming the position of Ukrainians in this War. There have also been major refusals to initiate a peace talk with Russia and Ukraine and with the neutrality of Brazil and China, they believe peace could&#8217;ve been the answer. But with many representatives in the Security Council arguing opposing perspectives neutrality is off the table. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Can Climate Change be Stopped?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/how-can-climate-change-be-stopped/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Climate change is not a new problem. It&#8217;s been an ever-growing issue since back in 1988 with the depletion of the ozone layer. It has]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Climate change is not a new problem. It&#8217;s been an ever-growing issue since back in 1988 with the depletion of the ozone layer. It has continued to grow and has had lasting effects on the economy. Some of these effects can be seen through unbalances in weather, and the increase in temperatures throughout the years.</p>



<p>These increasing temperatures have also affected the production of food, which has had an increase in hunger and a decrease in nutrition. Heat can diminish water, which also can lead to droughts, which are creating more deserts and people are facing threats of not having enough water. Along with the talk of water, these temperatures can affect the amount of rainfall, increasing the frequency of storms, landslides, and destroying homes, which is costing billions of dollars to repair. Along with that, climate change is making ice sheets melt, which is making the ocean levels rise, which can be threatening to islands and communities on those islands. </p>



<p>A representative from India shared, “Holding countries accountable and allocating our resources and funds towards combating climate change.” Most countries have their own contributions to climate change, but holding them accountable can help stop this threatening issue. </p>



<p>“All of us have established a climate goal and not all of us are meeting it. That’s an issue.”, the representative from India mentioned. Most countries have brought up the issue of climate change, it is whether or not they actually exceed the standards to actually attempt to stop climate change. </p>



<p>“Seeing why they can’t meet their goals and giving them resources to allow them too,” which was also mentioned by the delegate from India. India is willing to help and wants to make sure that countries, even their own country, has the needed resources to put a stop on climate change. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>War in Ukraine: Viewpoint from the United States</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/war-in-ukraine-viewpoint-from-the-united-states/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The tensions that exist between Ukraine and Russia are far from new. It is something that has existed for many years now, some dating back]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The tensions that exist between Ukraine and Russia are far from new. It is something that has existed for many years now, some dating back to 2014; almost a decade ago. Since then, as of February of 2022, Russia has sent many troops to go and invade Ukraine. Since that time, many civilians have died, mass destruction has occurred, and the continuous attacks do not seem to be dying down. </p>



<p>Many European countries are attempting to help Ukraine and the Ukrainian people, but the United States has also had their fair share of involvement. Including their attempts to provide aid, and spread information about the topic at hand. But, with the information at hand which has been covered by other media outlets, with the U.S. President Joe Biden, as well as coverage seen from the Ukrainian President Volodymyr Zelenskyy. There have been some issues within the United States regarding the spread of misinformation of the issues that have been going on during this conflict between Russia and Ukraine. </p>



<p>The big picture is “the mass amount of disinformation being spread,” which the United States press secretary commented on, and also commented that, “The United States has been working on a solution.” </p>



<p>There was not much to comment on about what the actual solution is that is being worked on currently. This would attempt to stop the spread of misinformation, further allowing the advancement of support for Ukraine, which can be done with truthful information being put out for the public. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Liveblog (Present Day)</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/friday-liveblog-present-day/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael McCarthy, Deputy USG for Media]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:04:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=189</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Security Council must act on Ukraine War: China</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/07/security-council-must-act-on-ukraine-war-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 06:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=94</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Russian-Ukrainian war has been an ongoing crisis since February of 2022, with over 350,000 casualties, which the People&#8217;s Republic of China deems purely unacceptable.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Russian-Ukrainian war has been an ongoing crisis since February of 2022, with over 350,000 casualties, which the People&#8217;s Republic of China deems purely unacceptable. Today, the war is still active and many countries, such as the U.S., have put major sanctions on the Russian Federation. </p>



<p>The representative of the People&#8217;s Republic of China to the Security Council believes that “now is not the time for symbolic grandstanding” and they need to put out real resolutions to end the war. It is not a time to add “fuel to the fire.” </p>



<p>The People&#8217;s Republic of China urges the stance of the Security Council that the war is not a matter to pull political affairs into. There should be laws passed in order to help the people and if any political matter arises within the resolutions China believes politics is not the first option.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
