<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Dima Llanos, Chicago Tribune &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2021/author/dllanos/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 01:36:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>Boeing PROTECTS America and Partners with the CIA to Protect FREEDOM</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/boeing-protects-america-and-partners-with-the-cia-to-protect-freedom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dima Llanos, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 19:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Boeing Company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=368</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is official; the CIA and Boeing are partnering to buy UAVs. An anonymous source states that the CIA has bought UAVs is “just in]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It is official; the CIA and Boeing are partnering to buy UAVs. An anonymous source states that the CIA has bought UAVs is “just in case anything goes wrong with Iran and Belarus.” However, according to a delegate on the Security council, the real threat is The United States and China, who have been attacking the South Korean side of the demilitarized zone and are massing on the North border. The move has been applauded by freedom-loving Americans everywhere. </p>



<p>The situation in North Korea and Iran has escalated; The United States is threatening military force and China has already moved troops to demilitarized North Korean Borders. The DPRK’s government is fighting among themselves, and is not able to win against the united forces of the South and China. Boeing is proud to stand with America and the CIA to protect freedom at home and abroad.</p>



<p>Boeing stands with all Americans in these trying times, and encourages all Americans to have faith in America&#8217;s airlines. Readers who use the code &#8220;BOEINGUSAFREEDOM&#8221; at participating airlines will receive $73.70 off of their flights. And remember: There is no safer way to travel than Boeing!*</p>



<p></p>



<p>*<em>By using the code on eligible flights, you are waiving your rights to sue boeing in the event of further 737 failures. Plus you&#8217;d be dead if it happened anyways so who cares? Book that flight you cowards. Boeing cares about AMERICA.</em> </p>



<p>**Also. legally we have to tell you that Boeing has purchased the Chicago Tribune, not out of fear of bad press, but because we LOVE the free press. You can still see all coverage of Boeing on the Chicago Tribune, but really its AirBus you have to watch out for. I think they hire anyone over there. Probably a bunch of idiots.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">368</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Lockheed Martin Possibly Partners with BAE to save them from Bankruptcy</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/lockheed-martin-possibly-partners-with-bae-to-save-them-from-bankruptcy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dima Llanos, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 17:57:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BAE Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=320</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin has proposed a contract that would make BAE Systems and LM partners. LM proposed this plan to save BAE from bankruptcy by giving]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Lockheed Martin has proposed a contract that would make BAE Systems and LM partners. LM proposed this plan to save BAE from bankruptcy by giving them a small percentage of LM’s yearly budget, in exchange for BAE’s technological discoveries.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>If BAE signs this contract, BAE will receive .001% of Lockheed Martin’s yearly budget, which totals to around $600,000. BAE will pay back LM in a 2 year period following a 4 month grace period on either a&nbsp; quarterly or monthly basis.</p>



<p>&nbsp;The CEO of BAE, Lisa Carr, released a tweet stating that she is looking forward to signing with LM. The Senior Vice President of Communications in LM, Dean Acosat, released a statement to the press replying to the CEO of BAE’s tweet</p>



<p>“ Lockheed Martin is deeply concerned about the jobs in the United Kingdom that could be lost if BAE went to bankruptcy, as well as for the implications this would have in Europe’s security. That is why we made an agreement in which Lockheed Martin will prevent BAE from bankruptcy in exchange of a fair amount of technology. This created an open door for new collaborations.”</p>



<p>So what does LM get out of this? The plan is to pool resources with BAE to help them in the following areas</p>



<ul><li>Rotorcraft developments on the Defiant X program, and any future rotorcraft study will be done in a joint fashion, taking into account the past success of both corporations in this field&nbsp;</li><li>Lockheed Martin will become a full collaborator within the Tempest innovation and it will be fully implemented into the F-35 program in Britain and Australia.</li><li>Lockheed Martin will gain full advertising rights of collaborative innovation including Tempest and other EW programs implemented into the F-35 program.</li><li>Countries currently using BAE fighter jets will be offered an option to switch to our collaborative F-35 program.</li><li>The Missions Systems radars programs of BAE and LM should work together to enhance and improve upon both companies systems,</li><li>The Sentinel A4 radar system will stay under the development of the LMC</li><li>New radar systems will begin to be developed jointly in both the UK sectors and US sectors of both companies&nbsp;</li></ul>



<p>Boeing, Lockheed Martin&#8217;s competitors, will be affected by this greatly. Since the 2019 plane crashes with the 737 Max, Boeing has been struggling financially. Boeing’s two biggest competitors are BAE and Lockheed Martin, so the companies combining forces will leave them even farther behind financially and technologically.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">320</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Confidential Deal Between the CIA and Boeing to Prepare for Possible Nuclear War</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/anonymous-source-reveals-a-confidential-deal-between-the-cia-and-boeing/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dima Llanos, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:22:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Boeing Company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=288</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It is official; the CIA and Boeing are partnering to buy UAVs. An anonymous source states that the CIA has bought UAVs is “just in]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It is official; the CIA and Boeing are partnering to buy UAVs. An anonymous source states that the CIA has bought UAVs is “just in case anything goes wrong with Iran and Belarus.” However, according to a delegate on the Security council, the real threat is The United States and China, who have been attacking the South Korean side of the demilitarized zone and are massing on the North border.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The situation in North Korea and Iran has escalated; The United States is threatening military force and China has already moved troops to demilitarized North Korean Borders. The DPRK’s government is fighting among themselves, and is not able to win against the united forces of the South and China.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">288</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boeing SVP of Treasury Leaked Email Shows Attempts to Thwart Lockheed Martin</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/boeing-svp-of-treasury-leaked-email-shows-attempts-to-thwart-lockheed-martin/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dima Llanos, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 22:20:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin Corporation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Boeing Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=248</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A leaked email from the Senior Vice President of Finance and Treasury reveals an attempt to recruit a Lockheed Martin employee to give inside information]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A leaked email from the Senior Vice President of Finance and Treasury reveals an attempt to recruit a Lockheed Martin employee to give inside information to Boeing in order to reestablish Boeing&#8217;s power and reputation after the 737 MAX crashes in 2019 (see Boeing 737 Max returns to the skies after almost 2 Years, Chicago Tribune.)</p>



<p>Below, you can see the email that was sent:</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img src="https://lh5.googleusercontent.com/iKrddHx_x3OWqTrvbp_mI8DufS3OiolSXQMXU4a_Hiqt1qKhdVbNH_pvSglQusOwfNEOe8XM0MYMaousSxr6WQ15s5baqZlk4kUolrns3aJKbT2956UPWrQZNfgThN7DvWwW4w_X" alt=""/></figure>



<p>When asked for a statement, all Boeing delegates simply said “no comment” and the Lockheed Martin delegates have not replied to journalists requests for statements.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In an attempt to find out more information, a journalist from the Chicago Tribune sat in on a Boeing committee session. Almost immediately after the journalist joined, a motion for a closed debate was passed unanimously, and the journalist was forced to leave. Shortly after leaving the committee session, an anonymous source reached out and revealed that the Senior Vice President of Finance and Treasury was the one who wrote the email.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The CEO of Boeing, in his own words, said “We are doing a lot of illegal stuff. We are committing, you know, campaign finance violations. We’re doing the same stuff the other companies are doing, but it is still illegal.” The SVP of Finance/Treasury was demoted to Finance and Treasurers intern almost as soon as the identity of the email writer was found. The CEO also added an addendum to the former SVP’s contract, adding an NDA and a non-compete clause.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">248</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kim Jong-un dies, Security Council in chaos over next Supreme Leader</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/kim-jong-un-dies-security-council-in-chaos-over-next-supreme-leader/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dima Llanos, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 18:10:12 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UN Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=171</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kim Jong-un, the late North Korean Supreme Leader, died Friday of causes not yet known. The Security Council is currently debating whether to suggest that]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Kim Jong-un, the late North Korean Supreme Leader, died Friday of causes not yet known. The Security Council is currently debating whether to suggest that Kim Jong-un&#8217;s sister, Kim Yo-jong become the new Supreme Leader of North Korea. The delegates are fiercely divided between Kim Yo-jong becoming Supreme Leader and holding a new election as if another Supreme Leader would have been elected.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Tunisia, South Africa, and Vietnam are heavily in favor of electing a new leader, because they believe Kim Yo-jong will initiate violence and take advantage of the nuclear warfare North Korea has access to, as Kim Yo-jong has threatened to move North Korean troops to demilitarized zones.</p>



<p>“The last thing Tunisia wants is more Korean conflict,” said the representative of Tunisia.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the other side, the United Kingdom, United States, and Russia could not be more opposed to the bill. In the bill drafted by the U.K., France, Russia, U.S., Estonia, Belgium, St. Vincent and the Grenadines, Germany, and Indonesia, Kim Yo-jong would “allow for the Democratic People&#8217;s Republic of Korea to stabilize itself under the new leadership of Kim Yo-jong without outside influence to denounce foreign intervention.”</p>



<p>The Security Council is moving as fast as possible, as the next topics they will be debating are extremely important. Soon, we will have more information about the cause of Kim Jong-un’s death and who the next Supreme Leader will be.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">171</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>President Biden Nominates New CIA Director; Former Diplomat and Veteran William Burns</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/president-biden-nominates-new-cia-director-former-diplomat-and-veteran-william-burns/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dima Llanos, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:16:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=123</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[William Burns, a former state department employee and war veteran was nominated for CIA Director by President Biden. If confirmed by the Senate, he will]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>William Burns, a former state department employee and war veteran was nominated for CIA Director by President Biden. If confirmed by the Senate, he will be the first director whose experience throughout life has been from the State Department. Burns worked in foreign service for 33 years, retiring in 2014. He is currently president of the Carnegie Endowment for National Peace, a think tank known and respected worldwide.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Burns has been critical of former President Trump for his failure to calmly accept election defeat, and even predicted this rough exchange of power last August. &#8220;Like so many other features of the Trump era, the transition would bear little resemblance to any before, or any of the many I served through as a career diplomat. The costs of confusion, mixed signals, and bureaucratic turmoil could be very high.&#8221;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Burns has similar beliefs as President Biden about how “intelligence must be apolitical,” which Biden believes is important to serving the nation. Burns appealed to Biden because he seemed capable of restoring trust in the CIA after Trump&#8217;s presidency. Burns also has expertise with Russia, which is needed after the Trump era. Burns also served as deputy secretary of state in the Obama Administration, and has worked under 5 American presidents from both parties.</p>



<p>Burns’ nomination was handed to him, as his other contenders had previously agreed with the use of torture programs, which was deemed unacceptable by Democrats on the Senate Intelligence committee.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">123</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Boeing 737 MAX returns to the skies after almost 2 years</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/boeing-737-max-returns-to-the-skies-after-almost-2-years/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dima Llanos, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 03:15:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Boeing Company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=95</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Boeing 737 MAX (manufactured by Boeing Commercial Airplanes) is infamous for crashing twice in five months back in 2019, killing 346 people. This is]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Boeing 737 MAX (manufactured by Boeing Commercial Airplanes) is infamous for crashing twice in five months back in 2019, killing 346 people. This is unprecedented in modern aviation, and investigations revealed faulty engineering in the automatic safety systems.</p>



<p>Faulty automatic safety systems caused the nose of the plane to point downwards, sending the plane into a dive. This lapse in engineering caused both the Lion Air crash in October 2018 and the Ethiopian Airline crash in March 2019. The Federal Aviation Administration grounded the 737 MAX three days after the Ethiopian Airline crash. </p>



<p>Aeronautical engineer Bjorn Fehrm called the series of events “absolutely unforgivable,” however he believes the flaws have been fixed.</p>



<p>Dennis Muilenburg resigned as CEO of Boeing due to the crashes. Even with the success of Boeing Starliner’s takeoff from Earth, it was not enough for Muilenburg’s job to remain intact. Boeing issued a statement stating that “a change in leadership was necessary to restore confidence in the company moving forward.” Boeing owes about $50 million to the families of the deceased travelers, and the grounding of the 737 MAX cost Boeing almost $18 billion.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The 737 MAX was recently approved to return to the skies on Nov. 18, 2020. Its first flight since the grounding of the plane. After more than 20 months of redesigning the aircraft, the 737 MAX departed from Miami International Airport on Dec. 29, 2020 and traveled successfully to LaGuardia Airport in New York.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">95</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
