<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Akina Souphakdy, O Globo &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/author/asouphakdy/feed/?simply_static_page=1427" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 16:08:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>ExxonMobil to discuss future of fossil fuels</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/exxonmobil-to-discuss-future-of-fossil-fuels/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, O Globo]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 16:10:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=787</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[ExxonMobil finds itself in a position to determine the company&#8217;s post-oil future, and the board is planning to create a renewable energy future, as we]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="300" height="168" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Picture1.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-792"/></figure>



<p>ExxonMobil finds itself in a position to determine the company&#8217;s post-oil future, and the board is planning to create a renewable energy future, as we see them on track to do so. ExxonMobli is set to at least talk about ways to create sustainable solutions to meet our societies evolving needs, But have also been seen to doubt the power of consumers. </p>



<p>The president of ExxonMobil is quoted saying that people, “pay a high price.” We see they have goals of being pro net zero, as stated in the ExxonMobil Climate Solutions Plans. </p>



<p>ExxonMobil’s motto is previously stated as, “[being] committed towards providing clean and safe energy for everyone, wherever they live and wherever they need to go.” ExxonMobil is claiming to meet expectations of consumers by decreasing carbon emissions, but also saying that they still want to count on oil and natural gasses in the future.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As gas and oil prices increase, the call for affordable clean energy rises. In a CNBC interview with the CEO of ExxonMobil, Darren Woods, says he fully predicts ExxonMobil will continue to use current energy methods for their company, and will continue to use oil and gas in the future. The ExxonMobil Board is on track to plan the future of ExxonMobil along with their future climate change contributions, which will undoubtedly influence the future of the company in these uncertain times.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
