<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Top Stories &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/top-articles/feed/?simply_static_page=1298" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:34:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Iran accused of misconduct in Iran-Iraq War</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/iran-accused-of-misconduct-in-iran-iraq-war/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hongtao Hu, The Sun]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 23:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of Iraq (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hot off of accusations that its ally Syria is engaging in chemical warfare, the USSR is pressuring Iran to cede the territories of Golestan, North]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="396" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/President_Ali_Khamenei_in_Iran-Iraq_War.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1709" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/President_Ali_Khamenei_in_Iran-Iraq_War.jpg 600w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/President_Ali_Khamenei_in_Iran-Iraq_War-300x198.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">President Ali Khamenei visiting soldiers during the Iran-Iraq War. (Source: Wikipedia Commons)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Hot off of accusations that its ally Syria is engaging in chemical warfare, the USSR is pressuring Iran to cede the territories of Golestan, North Khorasan, and Razavo Khorasan due to claims of civilian killings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The USSR has accused Iran of killing USSR civilians in its northeastern provinces, stating that Iran has “endangered and already killed thousands of innocent civilians” in the provinces of Golestan, North Khorasan, and Razavi Khorasan, and thus requests to occupy said provinces.</p>



<p>It is important to note that the war between Iraq and Iran is occurring along the western border of Iran, with Iraq fighting a 2-front war between Syria to the west and Iran to the east.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/8Q0ML2L8YV6PJB1ns9_ei-8aPrTmBsafGE9ML_2u1fv03Mq-BtncbE6qFcvsGDmCHG8JfOsR1kmmi_F-u5DnUN3JpT8otN5tMXuctYK7ArI4RmvZj5pQ0F_nGrYKmNkXb-zA7ZFSjZ3gY0MRhJDG6Q0" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Iran has asserted that the war is occurring nowhere close to possible USSR civilians, claiming that the USSR is threatening Iran with military action.</p>



<p>The Iranian Minister of Petroleum states that “it seems like the USSR has the worst intentions for the Middle East” and is beginning to establish a demilitarized zone within the provinces, along with seeking diplomatic negotiations with the USSR.</p>



<p>The Minister of Petroleum is also requesting the international community to take notice, stressing that “we hope the international community and especially the U.S. can recognize the severity of the USSR’s deception and their threat at this moment.”</p>



<p>Additionally, the Iraqi cabinet has accused Iran’s ally Syria of using chemical warfare and thus violating the Geneva Convention during its incursion into the western borders of Iraq.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Minister of Foreign Affairs from Iraq calls upon the Arab League to take action against Iran, stating: “There’s a great importance that the Arab League applies trade sanctions against Iran so that the Iranian and Syrian treachery can near an end.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iran states that it’s currently looking into the accusations of chemical warfare and reconsidering its relationship with Syria, however, they are still allying with them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>USSR captures Afghan government</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/ussr-captures-afghan-government/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 19:56:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Soviet Union (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1540</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the winter of 1979, the Soviet Union invaded Afghanistan to induct a new regime to solidify Afghanistan as an ally on the southern border,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="538" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-18-1024x538.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1548" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-18-1024x538.png 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-18-300x158.png 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-18-768x403.png 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-18.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">USSR militarily invades Afghanistan</figcaption></figure>



<p>In the winter of 1979, the Soviet Union invaded Afghanistan to induct a new regime to solidify Afghanistan as an ally on the southern border, this action did not come without controversy. The United States of America was a main proponent of objecting to this invasion, by supporting a collection of Muslim rebels, the Mujahideen, to rise against the nation. Conflict consumed Afghanistan resulting in numerous civilian deaths and an enormous refugee crisis, and the future remains uncertain.</p>



<p>The USSR Cabinet told reporters explicitly that focusing inward on the USSR is more important than international conflicts. The secretaries said that the cabinet recently passed a directive that emphasizes internal infrastructure. The USSR is highlighting general education, due to the struggles of getting equal access to quality education, as well as emphasizing the multiculturality of the USSR and discussing plans on how to support and preserve these cultures. However, all this talk of bettering the USSR is a lie, the USSR is using this as a disguise to seize the nation of Afghanistan and control their government.</p>



<p>When Le Monde informed the U.S. cabinet of the extreme action taken by the Soviets the cabinet&#8217;s response was underwhelming at best. The U.S. Cabinet was consumed with the attempted assassination of President Reagan, who remains in critical condition, and spent their time picking our flowers for the president, instead of the obvious pressing issue, the dominance of communism in the east. The USSR&#8217;s invasion of Afghanistan and control of their government secures another communist nation, tipping the scales closer to the USSR&#8217;s communist world instead of the U.S.&#8217;s democratic fantasy.</p>



<p>The U.S. cabinet is struggling to handle more than one issue at a time, leading to the question is the cabinet competent enough to handle international affairs, especially in regard to the USSR? The blatant power grab by the USSR should not go unnoticed or unpunished, by invalidating the former Afghan government, the Middle East may descend into instability or worse communism. How will the world respond to a sleeping United States and a dominating USSR?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A house divided</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/a-house-divided/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hongtao Hu, The Sun]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 07:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of Iraq (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran-Iraq War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Sun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the Iran-Iraq war continuing for over a year, Iran, Iraq, and Russia are divided &#8212; not only against each other, but among themselves. However,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="819" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-1024x819.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-1359" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-1024x819.jpeg 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-300x240.jpeg 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-768x615.jpeg 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D.jpeg 1431w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>With the Iran-Iraq war continuing for over a year, Iran, Iraq, and Russia are divided &#8212; not only against each other, but among themselves.</p>



<p>However, one faction has joined forces: the USSR and Iraq.</p>



<p>While notorious for secrecy, The Sun has received an anonymous report about a meeting between the USSR and Iraq, where a member of the USSR cabinet was reportedly heard saying to Iraq: “our house is your house.” </p>



<p>However, the USSR is burdened with the loss of a member of its cabinet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this meeting, the USSR stated that the recently deceased Finance Minister of the USSR was discovered to be colluding with members of the Iranian cabinet.</p>



<p>Could the USSR have “disappeared” the Minister of Finance for political purposes? Is the USSR providing nuclear resources to Iraq? Only time will tell.</p>



<p>In other news, Iraq is experiencing internal turmoil along its southern border, incited by Ayatollah Khomeini’s words: “to our brothers in Iraq especially, I turn to you now. You know in your hearts that the mongrel demon-spawn of the greater Satan Saddam Hussein will never care for you…now it is time for you to be freed of your oppressor in accordance with the wishes of the Muslim people, and the true Sharia!”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Such words have invoked the “righteous” fervor of Iraqi citizens and have led to several civilian arrests in Iraq.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In response, the Ambassador to the United Nations for Iraq offered a “sneak peek” of a future directive to The Sun, hinting at creating literacy programs and actions to reduce hunger in the population.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Iran, after discovering the news of a collaboration between the deceased Finance Minister of the USSR and a member of their cabinet, accusations went flying about a possible “traitor” in their midst.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With the Iran-Iraq war in the midst of its first year, both sides of the conflict are experiencing similar troubles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>US, Chinese Leaders Conflict on Relationships Between Free Media and Oil </title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/us-chinese-leaders-conflict-on-relationships-between-free-media-and-oil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 19:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 3, the United States Cabinet and the ExxonMobil Board of Directors held an open door meeting to discuss expansion of oil drilling to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On February 3, the United States Cabinet and the ExxonMobil Board of Directors held an open door meeting to discuss expansion of oil drilling to global markets. At the same time, Chinese leaders discussed dealing with their oil crisis caused by the Russo-Ukrainian War. However, the nations’ approaches to dealing with opposition have starkly differed.</p>



<p>An ExxonMobil executive who wished to remain anonymous acknowledged that protests over the private deal may erupt. “We can’t stop protests from happening,” said the executive. “So we need to address the volatility of them by working with their demands.” American secretaries have also discussed how they will address protests. “We do not want to create a monopoly with our deal,” said the CIA Director. “So if protests erupt, we’ll need to address that.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>While Chinese leaders have openly welcomed protests, they have explained mass arrests of protestors. “We have no knowledge of unjust detaining,” said Finance Minister Liu Kun. “The only reason protestors were arrested was for sedition and treason, and we want to speak to the leaders directly.” Culture and Tourism Minister Hu Heping also outlined her concern with free press reporting on the protests. “There is a massive security issue with private press,” she said. “Government owned does not mean unfree.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>ExxonMobil secretaries admitted their frustration with protests nonetheless. “Protestors don’t know what they want from ExxonMobil,” said the anonymous secretary. “We know what we want.” Various Cabinet members discussed how ExxonMobil will expand drilling in untapped markets with a goal of making American markets more competitive than Russian and Chinese markets. The executive further discussed his wishes to achieve what the public desires, a sentiment echoed by executive LD DuCharme. “We want to also invest into biofuels,” she said.</p>



<p>In the meeting between the US government and ExxonMobil, the Treasury Secretary specifically mentioned ExxonMobil’s commitment to sustainability as the reason for working with them. “We need to keep competition up,” said the Secretary. “If Exxon violates our deal or US laws, the deal is over.”</p>



<p>Chinese officials have remained mum on expanding oil drilling amongst mass protests in the country. Finance minister Liu Kun explained his hesitancy on action. “We want to keep our neutrality,” he explained. “So it’s difficult to say where our oil will come from.” However, the United States Treasury Secretary was clear. “Nothing is more valuable to the US than oil,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Tensions Rise in the House of Commons</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/tensions-rise-in-the-house-of-commons/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 17:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=957</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The House of Commons is invested in finding the best way to support the economy and how to deal with the power grab of unions,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The House of Commons is invested in finding the best way to support the economy and how to deal with the power grab of unions, ignoring the Falkland Islands crisis. Several Parliamentary members including Winston Churchill believed that the best way to support the British economy is to “increase interest value to decrease inflation.” Churchill fears that the UK is at risk of an economic depression. Churchill then questioned the prime minister about economic diversity, however, the Prime minister was unable to answer the question in full, leading to the question if the Prime Minister feels confident in their solutions to the economic crisis.</p>



<p><br>The Prime Minister is steering the committee into valuing workers&#8217; rights whilst warning parliamentary members that unions don’t support human rights and that union bosses are motivated solely by greed and selfishness. A parliamentary member emphasizes that human rights are stifled by unions.<br>The House of Commons is working towards deregulations in the British economy to let economies function to the best of their ability without unions undermining the effort.</p>



<p><br>Furthermore, the conservative party has split into factions. Half of the party aimed solely at ousting Margaret Thatcher from her position as Prime Minister, despite being a strong member of the conservative party. This divide has caused confusion about the other branch of the conservative party whose goal is to support workers&#8217; rights by restricting British unions.</p>



<p><br>The House of Commons is a tense, evolving situation that needs to be monitored closely as the split could cause emotions and a faction between the conservative party, leading to the labour party taking control of the House for the first time in years.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>US Secretary of Defense asks Europe to do more in Russia-Ukraine War</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/us-secretary-of-defense-asks-europe-to-do-more-in-russia-ukraine-war/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 23:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Did you know that Lloyd Austin has been first in five different categories? He was the first Black secretary of defense, the first Black vice]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1000" height="600" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/fea-when-will-war-in-ukraine-end.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-813" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/fea-when-will-war-in-ukraine-end.jpg 1000w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/fea-when-will-war-in-ukraine-end-300x180.jpg 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/fea-when-will-war-in-ukraine-end-768x461.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">HOSTOMEL, UKRAINE &#8211; APRIL 08: Ukrainian soldier waves Ukrainian national flag while standing on top of an armoured personnel carrier (APC) on April 8, 2022 in Hostomel, Ukraine. After more than five weeks of war, Russia appears to have abandoned its goal of encircling the Ukrainian capital. However, Ukraine expects a renewed fight in the east and south. (Photo by Alexey Furman/Getty Images)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Did you know that Lloyd Austin has been first in five different categories? He was the first Black secretary of defense, the first Black vice chief of staff of the Army, the first Black person to lead U.S. Central Command, the first Black person to lead an Army corps in combat, and the first Black commanding general of a U.S. Army Division. However, during his latest speech, Secretary of Defense Austin explained why governments should care about Ukraine and why they should help.</p>



<p>“Stability and prosperity on both sides of the Atlantic are at stake. You know, the U.S. trading relationship with the European Union is the largest in the world. So when an aggressor manufactures a huge security crisis in Europe, it hits home for everyday Americans and Canadians,” Austin remarked.</p>



<p>The secretary of defense&#8217;s speech at the Halifax International Security Forum brings up how the situation in Russia and Ukraine started and how everyone is reacting to this situation. </p>



<p>To give some background of this major event. On Feb. 24, 2022, Russia invaded Ukraine, causing huge tensions throughout Europe for allies of Ukraine and allies of Russia. As of now, there have been more than 40,000 fatalities in the country. </p>



<p>Secretary Austin has accomplished many things in his lifetime, but when trying to resolve the argument on the use of tanks in Ukraine, he failed. He also had little to no support on this matter. The reason why he failed was because every country in NATO believes they are doing enough. When the question of if Germany was doing enough, he responded, “Yes, but we can all do more.” That must be the main reason why it did not pass, countries assumed they were doing enough.</p>



<p>Are countries doing enough? Can the secretary of defense solve this issue? </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
