<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Nathan Zhang, The Korea Herald &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2021/author/nzhang/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 01:56:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>South Korean tensions escalate with China and North Korea.</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/south-korean-tensions-escalate-with-china-and-north-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Zhang, The Korea Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 01:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=313</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Political and militaristic tensions have reached a breaking point as China and the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea face off against South Korea and its]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Political and militaristic tensions have reached a breaking point as China and the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea face off against South Korea and its allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Earlier today, China and Russia officially recognized Choe Ryong-hae, Kim Jong Un&#8217;s former Head of State.</p>



<p>South Korea, Japan, and India, backed by the United States, recognized the North Korean People&#8217;s Liberation Front (PLF) as the legitimate government of Korea. The PLF is a group of military defectors from North Korea that support the reunification of the Korean Peninsula. While political tensions rise, militaristic tensions follow. According to a recent leak, Chinese aircraft have fired upon South Korean soldiers at the 38th parallel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although the Cabinet of South Korea has not made action yet, action may be taken against The People’s Republic of China.&nbsp; After the recent encounter with China, it may be reasonable that the two countries will enter war against each other.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If war is to occur, nuclear arms may be involved. Foreshadowing this today, Iran released a statement that “western nations do not have power over other countries, like Iran and North Korea” after conducting a successful nuclear test. This may suggest that North Korea will go to extreme means if South Korea were to invade the DPRK.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>Whether the South Korean government will go to war is unknown, but tomorrow, the world will find out whether the tensions between China and the Korean peninsula will deescalate.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">313</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Nuking North Korea” would not affect South Korea “too much”: Singapore officials</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/nuking-north-korea-would-not-affect-south-korea-too-much-singapore-officials/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Zhang, The Korea Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Association of Southeast Asian Nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China and Laos have pushed for diplomatic solutions to solve dangerous nuclear instability within North Korea. A statement from the South Korean delegates has also]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>China and Laos have pushed for diplomatic solutions to solve dangerous nuclear instability within North Korea.</p>



<p>A statement from the South Korean delegates has also been released. “South Korea should maintain peace, until or unless threatened by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) [North Korea]. North Korea has continued to provoke the delegation of South Korea, and we would like to not act on a whim.”</p>



<p>The consensus is currently that continuing to be diplomatic is the best way to move forward. Still, some delegates oppose this.</p>



<p>‘Diplomatic action is not the best action” said the representative from Singapore Saturday evening.</p>



<p>The delegation from Singapore called for military pressure, believing that the European Union and the United States would support them.</p>



<p>“South Korea would not be affected too much, if we dropped one on (DPRK)” they reiterated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Clearly, some countries do not have civilians and general welfare in mind.&nbsp;</p>



<p>ASEAN will continue to achieve a resolution to bring peace to the world and the Korean peninsula.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">292</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNGA Comes Together to Deal with Nuclear Arms in DPRK after Kim Jong Un&#8217;s Death</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/unga-comes-together-to-deal-with-nuclear-arms-in-dprk-after-kim-jong-uns-death/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Zhang, The Korea Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 19:23:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UN General Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=184</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Due to the death of Kim Jong Un and to avoid potential instability, the United Nations General Assembly is currently working to find a solution]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Due to the death of Kim Jong Un and to avoid potential instability, the United Nations General Assembly is currently working to find a solution on denuclearizing North Korea.</p>



<p>As of now, the United Nations General Assembly has recognized Kim Yo-Jong as the new successor of the DPRK.</p>



<p>On Feb. 6th, the committee comes together to work on a solution to the possible denuclearization of the state. Two blocs have been formed, one for denuclearization and another that believes that denuclearization is unachievable. </p>



<p>South Korea, Poland, Russia, Rwanda, Nigeria, and others are for denuclearization.&nbsp; As a solution, the bloc calls for a three phase plan to limit the country’s nuclear power.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Phase 1 begins with a pause on all development and testing on arms.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Phase 2 terminates all production of enriched uranium and plutonium. They also call for the dismantling of nuclear processing infrastructure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Phase 3 removes all existing warheads and fissile materials.</p>



<p>The bloc has also proposed to create a Euroasian energy and transportation link. They also wish to safely dispose of the nuclear weapons from the DPRK.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the other end, there are many other&nbsp; countries who do not believe that denuclearization is achievable under Kim Yo Jong.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Denuclearization is not possible under the regime of Kim Yo Jung. She has proven to be an ambitious leader who cracks down with brutality. Suggesting denuclearization will be viewed as a threat and taken with hostilities. Kim Yo Jung is an isolationist who will not work for the benefit of international peace.”, stated the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>There is a clear divide within the General Assembly right now but as the meeting progresses, the delegates will continue to work on a solution to find peace.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">184</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North Korean leader Kim Jong-un hospitalized</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/north-korean-leader-kim-jong-un-hospitalized/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Zhang, The Korea Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Association of Southeast Asian Nations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kim Jong-un, North Korea’s leader, was recently hospitalized for potentially severe reasons. The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) will be coming together to discuss]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Kim Jong-un, North Korea’s leader, was recently hospitalized for potentially severe reasons. The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) will be coming together to discuss potential protocol if the leader were to pass away.</p>



<p>There would be many effects of Kim Jong-un’s death. One could be civil unrest and instability within the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK), a state in an important geopolitical position situated between China and South Korea with nuclear arms and a military. ASEAN will be debating whether outside involvement should be used to prevent and or contain conflict within the DPRK.</p>



<p>Although South Korea’s close proximity calls for prevention of conflict, due to the close proximity, others do not agree. “Intervention, whether politically or militarily will only lead to unnecessary bloodshed, loss, and ignition of global tensions between major world powers” the representative from Laos said.</p>



<p>The issue at hand may also escalate China-U.S. competition due to China’s close connections to the Korean peninsula. This situation could also move into diplomatic and military committees at the United Nations.</p>



<p>In February, ASEAN will face the difficult challenge of setting aside differences in creating unity. The delegates from their respective countries will discuss the outcome of the state of the DPRK.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">132</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
