<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Historical Committees &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/historical-committees/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 05:58:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>UN will not allocate military or humanitarian resources to India</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/13/un-will-not-allocate-military-or-humanitarian-resources-to-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 04:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=648</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amidst the unbelievable drama surrounding the Sino-Indian conflict, everyone is left wondering what will happen next. Following a visit to the United Nations Security Council,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Amidst the unbelievable drama surrounding the Sino-Indian conflict, everyone is left wondering what will happen next. Following a visit to the United Nations Security Council, a vote among all members resulted in only one representative voting to give military resources to India while all 10 others voted no. Consequentially, a nearly unanimous vote to send humanitarian aid to India has been vetoed by the Republic of China, resulting in the U.N. not reserving any resources to the Indian Council. </p>



<p>The Republic of China, independent from the People&#8217;s Republic of China and which does not have U.N. representation, accepted an interview where they shared some important information about how the cabinet has been acting on the issue. Both nations China and India continue to be shocked by each other&#8217;s actions with their militaries and hatred towards both sides is building up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The U.S. Senate: Senator William Proxmire Sepaks on Behalf of the Senate</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/10/the-u-s-senate-senator-william-proxmire-sepaks-on-behalf-of-the-senate-ready-for-edit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 10 Dec 2023 16:04:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=658</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the most recent press conference, Sen. Proxmire represented the U.S. Senate and started with his condolences for the loss of Eleanor Roosevelt. He continued]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the most recent press conference, Sen. Proxmire represented the U.S. Senate and started with his condolences for the loss of Eleanor Roosevelt. He continued to express that as they dealt with the Cuban Missile Crisis, they felt that it was important to discuss the civil rights issue within the nation, specifically women’s rights.&nbsp;</p>



<p><strong>In an interview with Senator Proxmire, he stated many things not only on behalf of himself, but speaking overall for the U.S. Senate.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>The Cuban missile crisis has impacted many and caused chaos, and the U.S. Senate reassures their unity and doing “not only what is in our best interest, but in the best interest of the American people.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Senate attempted solutions to help de-escalate the situation in Cuba, and at the same time protect the U.S. and its public as a whole, ensuring the safety of all Americans.&nbsp;</p>



<p>On the topic of the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women, Sen. Proxmire said, “we understand women’s rights and civil rights are an issue that requires prioritization, and they are the most important thing to the Senate. Currently, we are working on solutions to try and implement more education, as well as other social reforms which are in the process.” </p>



<p><strong>“As a senator that wants every American to know the truth, I wish all of you to know that we are trying to do the best for all American people, and I acknowledge the discontent with us, but rest assured we are using our power to ensure the happiness and great state of the U.S.A.”</strong></p>



<p>Overall not only as a senator, but a representative of our government, Sen. Proxmire and the rest of the U.S. Senate want the American people to rest assured knowing they are working on solutions to help with women’s rights, civil rights, and the overall safety of the nation, which will further unveil as debates and bills continue to develop. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PCSW Appeals to US Cabinet and Senate in Interest of Advocating for Women</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/pcsw-appeals-to-us-cabinet-and-senate-in-interest-of-advocating-for-women/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Swadha Garnaik, BBC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 23:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the aftermath of the intense discussions with the U.S. Senate and Cabinet, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) convened to reflect]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the aftermath of the intense discussions with the U.S. Senate and Cabinet, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) convened to reflect on the progress made and the challenges ahead. The post-Senate meeting interview with Jessica Weis and Dr. Henry David shed light on the Senate&#8217;s acknowledgment of their concerns, particularly regarding Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson&#8217;s letter. Weis added her perspective, saying, &#8220;The questions that they posed were very good. And I&#8217;m very happy that they mentioned that they passed a bill that brought up women and protections for them.&#8221; Despite the challenges, there seems to be a newfound dialogue between the PCSW and the Senate, hinting at the possibility of improved collaboration. The committee members expressed satisfaction with the Senate&#8217;s responsiveness and hoped for improved communication on resolutions and bills.</p>



<p>Following the cabinet meeting, Marguerite Rawalt and Honorable John Macy, Jr. highlighted the positive strides made in addressing issues related to women&#8217;s roles in the military and workforce. They emphasized the importance of promoting women&#8217;s contributions, especially in times of crisis such as the Cuban Missile Crisis. The committee members remained professional, advocating for women&#8217;s relevance to national security without succumbing to individual anger.</p>



<p>However, the committee&#8217;s optimism was tempered by a press conference where U.S. Cabinet representative John McCone claimed that the status of women was a low priority amid the pressing matters facing the government. The official asserted, &#8220;As we have a lot going right now, the status of women is at a low priority at the moment.&#8221; This disappointing declaration underscored the uphill battle the PCSW faces in securing recognition for women&#8217;s issues in the current political climate. The committee questions how America could be a powerhouse if women were marginalized and thus immobilized. This blow marks the second occasion where the U.S. government seemingly disregarded the PCSW.</p>



<p>The Presidential Committee on the Status of Women has released a press statement in response to the blatant disrespect of the Cabinet. &#8220;The Presidential Commission on the Status of Women condemns the actions of the US Cabinet and the statement made by the Director of the CIA. Director John McCone outwardly expressed the Cabinet’s disinterest in the rights of American women. During a press conference with the PCSW and US Senate, McCone stated that on the list of their priorities, our directives were very low. These directives detailed plans for empowering women in regards to the current state of our nation given the Cuban Missile Crisis. The PCSW would like to express their disappointment in our US Cabinet for not giving their support for half of the US population.&#8221;</p>



<p>The PCSW remains determined to uphold Eleanor Roosevelt&#8217;s legacy, urging the government to recognize and prioritize the contributions of women to the nation&#8217;s well-being.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LATEST FROM THE POST: Southern Democratic Senators Double Down on Their Stance and Address the Nation</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/latest-from-the-post-southern-democratic-senators-double-down-on-their-stance-and-address-the-nation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=659</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an exclusive interview with the Washington Post, Democratic Senator Olin D. Johnston and his colleauges wished to provide us with a message for the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In an exclusive interview with the Washington Post, Democratic Senator Olin D. Johnston and his colleauges wished to provide us with a message for the nation. The address reads as follows: </p>



<p>&#8220;Today I, Senator Olin D. Johnston, stand before members of the Press to address a very important matter. John Locke contended that if the government the people created in the state of nature violated the rights of the citizens and the set laws of the land, the right of revolution would entitle the people to use force to punish that government and depose its rulers. Today, In light of the drastic motions and efforts of the United States Federal Government related to the infringement of state’s rights, it is time that YOU, the people take initiative today, putting the power back in your hands.&nbsp;In accordance with the Second Southern Manifesto, and the Federal Government’s complete disregard of the statements within that document, the people must adhere to those same words of John Locke and impose the &#8216;right of revolution&#8217;. Align yourselves, and make your voices heard by marching to THE CAPITOL. If the United States Government isn’t willing to listen to the representatives of the people, let them hear from the people themselves. “</p>



<p>The colleagues supporting this address are senators Allen J. Ellender, Richard Russell Jr., Harry F. Byrd, Robert Byrd, and Herman Talmadge</p>



<p>The implications of this incitement of revolt are yet to be seen, and the Washington Post advises all Americans to stay alert as the situation develops.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Missile crisis brings positive changes for women in war-related industries</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/missile-crisis-brings-positive-changes-for-women-in-war-related-industries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Though the unfortunate crisis involving the U.S. and USSR in Cuba has raised tensions and concerns of war, there are also many American domestic concerns]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Though the unfortunate crisis involving the U.S. and USSR in Cuba has raised tensions and concerns of war, there are also many American domestic concerns that could be revolutionary in women&#8217;s rights. The war effort is supported by women which is reflected by the growing number of women in the workplace aiding in war efforts. Not only does this benefit the factory industry and war production, but also boosts the domestic economy, advancing and building the nation. As for opportunities for women, the current crisis has been evidenced in women&#8217;s abilities and aspirations. </p>



<p>The press representative for the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women commented saying, &#8220;Additionally, our commission has been working towards creating legislative reforms that focus on educational opportunities&#8230;to ensure that these women are starting off with the right skill set.&#8221; </p>



<p>Women will have opportunities to be business owners and entrepreneurs unlike ever before. This crisis has brought on the guarantee of women in the workplace and to have equal freedoms.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chinese cabinet member claims Indian communications representative threatened him at press conference</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/chinese-cabinet-member-claims-indian-communications-representative-threatened-him-at-press-conference/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ari Ramjit, Pan African News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:15:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=607</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the latest press conference, a representative from the cabinet of the People&#8217;s Republic of China spoke out about the war still happening between China]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>During the latest press conference, a representative from the cabinet of the People&#8217;s Republic of China spoke out about the war still happening between China and India.</p>



<p>&#8220;Not that long ago, the Indian communications minster threatened me at a press conference. He said to me: &#8216;Do you want war? Do you want war? Minister you have your war,'&#8221; the representative from China said. </p>



<p>&#8220;China&#8217;s military position is strong. Our offense and defense are firm and unwavering. Despite this strong position and our previous experience with radical Indian cabinet, China will once again graciously offer the diplomatic solution.&#8221; </p>



<p>&#8220;Firstly, an immediate removal of all Indian troops from rightfully Chinese territory,&#8221; he continued. &#8220;Second, economic reparations for all the damages India has caused China. Third, India&#8217;s support for China becoming a full member of the United Nation&#8217;s General Assembly. Fourth, India returning all seized territory that are rightfully Chinese. China is choosing to fight fire with diplomacy. We want this war to end, but if India wants to worsen this conflict and let more innocent Chinese and Indian civilians die, China&#8217;s hands are tied.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Foreshadowing Events to the People&#8217;s Republic of China and India Conflict</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/the-foreshadowing-events-to-the-pr-china-and-india-conflict-ready-for-edit/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:08:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=368</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After the early morning crisis update of the war starting on the border, the side is at fault is still in question. The previous status]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After the early morning crisis update of the war starting on the border, the side is at fault is still in question. The previous status of peace between India and China on the border dispute seems to be a stand-still, as both parties claim contrasting perspectives. It has been on record that the two nations appeared to be coming to terms and possibly end the dispute once and for all, up until the yesterday&#8217;s press conference where a press representative for each the China cabinet and Indian Council shared the conflicting accounts of the relations.</p>



<p>Yesterday, the Indian council made it known during the press conference that they intend not to move on the border and has claimed in the past that expanding borders is not in their interests either. At a press release in the Council yesterday , the Director of Intelligence commented on the matter describing how the Chinese government have been negligent of their offers of diplomatic relations, furthermore the Chinese are the aggressors in this conflict. According to the council, China has been violent and have killed many Indian citizens on the border. </p>



<p>At the very same press conference yesterday evening, the press representative for the People&#8217;s Republic of China stated, &#8220;India, wrongly claiming Chinese territory as its own has blatantly denied every Chinese attempt at reconciliation. China does not want violence. It wants the people of China to be safe, protected, and well fed, but Nehru has refused a trade deal, reused collaboration on scientific endeavors, refused to engage on our shared ties of decolonization.&#8221; All the while, China was also occupied with internal struggles and growth as they try to recover from the tragic event of the Banqiao Dam collapsing and crude accusations of being involved in the disappearance of the beloved Dalai Lama.</p>



<p>Now with the ongoing hostilities and violence between the two it begs the question; &#8220;Who is the real aggressor?&#8221; Both parties claim war is not wanted and have the similar resolution method of communication if the other party is willing. The issue of disinformation being spread threatened the situation and rose tensions, undoubtedly leading us to where we are today in the dispute. Going forward, it seems tensions are only rising and the two Asian nations are on the brink of war. More on this ongoing conflict coming soon in the future.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Guerrilla fighters at the Sino-Indian border</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/guerrilla-fighters-at-the-sino-indian-border/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In recent updates there have been news of Indian guerrilla fighters at the border with China in response to the growing India and China border]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In recent updates there have been news of Indian guerrilla fighters at the border with China in response to the growing India and China border conflict. Guerrilla fighters may include armed civilians and non-professional paramilitary groups, even children.</p>



<p>Although the council claimed that safety of their people was the biggest concern, these fighters at the high risk Indian border raise many concerns about this. This also brings into question the preparedness of the nation as the border troops are not high-ranking military but civilians who are not trained and are at high risk facing the strong Chinese army.</p>



<p>In today&#8217;s press conference, the Indian Minister of Communications responded claiming, &#8220;&#8230;in our last press conference we did mention that we were confident in winning this war and that we believed we had the military strength to really support it.&#8221; This claim seems to falsify their reinforcing statement on the safety of Indian citizens as their &#8220;military strength&#8221; is made up of untrained citizens and possibly children, and ultimately contrasts the recent developments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is the Senate being shut out, or are they separating themselves?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/is-the-senate-being-shut-out-or-are-they-separating-themselves/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 21:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Concerns have arisen as multiple senators express their displeasure with the lack of communication between branches of the United States government. Several new resolutions presented]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Concerns have arisen as multiple senators express their displeasure with the lack of communication between branches of the United States government. Several new resolutions presented before the Senate emphasize better and more frequent levels of communication between the executive and legislative branches, but also dart between numerous topics.</p>



<p>The U.S. Senate has struggled to come to conclusions on major topics as the subject of debate shifts continuously, but valuable arguments are still being made. Civil rights and checks and balances float around the room while Senators talk about what is most important for the country. However, the consensus proves to be that immediate action needs to be taken on the rights of women and all people of color. Even then, the two groups in desperate need of civil rights protections cannot seem to be agreed upon.</p>



<p>Cooperation seems to be absent and agreement is rarely occurring in any part of the debate, even though nearly all senators share the view of the vitality of the topics. The priorities of the Senate remain questionable seeing that conversations within the chamber have no majorly effective results. As stated by more than one Senator, the allocation and protection of these rights to minority groups is imperative, and it is clear that the Senate, while indecisive, is determined to create conclusions. The future of social inequality remains anticipated yet uncertain.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>U.S. Sen. James Pearson expresses his disappointment</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/u-s-sen-james-pearson-expresses-his-disappointment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:41:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=556</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. Senate has officially passed many resolutions regarding the Cuban Missile Crisis, including plans regarding the U.S. Presidential Cabinet.&#160; With this, one of the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. Senate has officially passed many resolutions regarding the Cuban Missile Crisis, including plans regarding the U.S. Presidential Cabinet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With this, one of the papers not passed was the RULE paper, sponsored in part by Republican Sen. James Pearson from Kansas. This paper essentially planned on making sure that the executive branch would inform Congress of any military action to keep Congress updated and they would be able to move forward or not with the actions after 30 days. Sen. Pearson was disheartened and shared his sentiments on this matter by expressing how he felt strongly regarding the resolutions passed, as well as his resolution. </p>



<p>In an interview with Sen. Pearson, he expressed how “the cabinet has not been informing the senate of practically anything that has been going on with Cuba.”&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Regarding the failure of his paper he has stated the reason behind this is due to “a few people who were very much like ‘this is too much bureaucracy, this is raising tensions between the executive and legislative branch.'&#8221; </p>



<p>He further explained how the reasons for not passing his paper seem hypocritical due to his fellow senators having a similar resolution where the president would be in power for no more than 30 days with the military to protect the country. </p>



<p>He finished by explaining how “this is just quite frankly ridiculous that the senate passed this because again, it just increases tensions between the executive and legislative branch” and how on day 31 of a conflict, “we are out of luck.”  Even after coming up with solutions, they do not seem to be solving the issue at hand, but rather creating possible internal resentment within the senate.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
