<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Paula Rosillon, Le Monde &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2022/author/prosillon/feed/?simply_static_page=267" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2022</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 23:16:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>COVAX: Will it benefit the citizens or the nations?</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/covax-will-it-benefit-the-citizens-or-the-nations/</link>
					<comments>/archive/2022/covax-will-it-benefit-the-citizens-or-the-nations/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Paula Rosillon, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:33:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[World Health Organization (WHO)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=459</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Multiple nations have joined in a World Health Organization conference Friday, in the hopes of coming to an agreement on the distribution and rollout of]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Multiple nations have joined in a World Health Organization conference Friday, in the hopes of coming to an agreement on the distribution and rollout of the COVID-19 vaccine. However, there seems to be a division in ideas, with multiple working papers being created and nations switching from one to another.</p>



<p>The first working paper was being sponsored by Israel, Cuba, New Zealand, and UAE. As of today, UAE has left the paper altogether, with Turkey taking its spot as a sponsor. Some of the countries that have supported the idea from the beginning include Trinidad and Tobago, Paraguay, Pakistan, and Vietnam. An anonymous source theorizes that although the efforts are disguised as innocent, the entire situation is being manipulated by Israel to benefit economically only those that sponsor or sign the paper.</p>



<p>However, though, other countries have created their own proposals. Namely Colombia, who created a detailed plan supposed to ensure accessibility to both the vaccine and information surrounding it.</p>



<p>There is also a third paper, sponsored by Egypt, Lebanon, Portugal, Taiwan, and Thailand. Countries such as Turkey and Senegal have signed this paper, despite them simultaneously showing support toward others. Despite the large amount of countries supporting this paper, an anonymous source claims that ”Lebanon is recurring to insulting other nation’s work because they know that their plan was flawed from the beginning.”</p>



<p>It is because of the constant butting heads that the nations have not been able to agree on one single solution. It seems that the conference has deviated from the original point, the distribution of the vaccine, and has rather become a competition meant to benefit countries rather than citizens.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/archive/2022/covax-will-it-benefit-the-citizens-or-the-nations/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The rocky relationship between Russia and Belarus</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/the-rocky-relationship-between-russia-and-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Paula Rosillon, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 20:34:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=520</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Russia and Belarus are known to be official allies since 1995, but in light of recent events, the relationship between the two seems to have]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Russia and Belarus are known to be official allies since 1995, but in light of recent events, the relationship between the two seems to have taken a rocky turn. Belarus is currently in the middle of a migratory problem, with numerous emigrants from Syria being denied entrance to the European Union. As a solution, Russia came up with the idea to invite said emigrants into the country. Russia believes that in doing this, their economy might be benefited and the perception of them the international committee has might be positively improved. However, Russia isn’t taking into account that in doing this, it is risking the country going into crisis.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large" datatext=""><img decoding="async" src="https://upload.wikimedia.org/wikipedia/commons/0/0b/Location_Belarus_Europe.png" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Belarus does not seem fond of the idea either, as they consider it a back-handed move from Russia. President of Belarus, Aleksandr Lukashenko, sent a letter to the Russian cabinet expressing his disapproval. He accused Russia of treason, and stated that he expected more understanding towards the intentions Belarusian people have. Belarus wanted to pressure the European Union into accepting Syrians into their territory, and claimed that if Russia took the emigrants in, Belarus would loose its leverage. This resulted in Belarus stating that ”Not only will [they] block [Russia’s] efforts to withdraw refugees from the border, but [they] will also reconsider [their] relationship from this point moving forward”.</p>



<p>In response, Russia wrote a letter back to the Belarusian government&#8217; in which they stated that they hoped to put the misunderstanding behind them. Having been allies for a large amount of time, Russia claimed that maintaining an amicable relationship with Belarus was of utmost importance to the nation. As of right now, Belarus is yet to issue any response.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
