<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/historical-committees/presidential-commission-on-the-status-of-women-1962/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 23:05:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>PCSW Appeals to US Cabinet and Senate in Interest of Advocating for Women</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/pcsw-appeals-to-us-cabinet-and-senate-in-interest-of-advocating-for-women/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Swadha Garnaik, BBC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 23:05:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=573</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the aftermath of the intense discussions with the U.S. Senate and Cabinet, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) convened to reflect]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the aftermath of the intense discussions with the U.S. Senate and Cabinet, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) convened to reflect on the progress made and the challenges ahead. The post-Senate meeting interview with Jessica Weis and Dr. Henry David shed light on the Senate&#8217;s acknowledgment of their concerns, particularly regarding Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson&#8217;s letter. Weis added her perspective, saying, &#8220;The questions that they posed were very good. And I&#8217;m very happy that they mentioned that they passed a bill that brought up women and protections for them.&#8221; Despite the challenges, there seems to be a newfound dialogue between the PCSW and the Senate, hinting at the possibility of improved collaboration. The committee members expressed satisfaction with the Senate&#8217;s responsiveness and hoped for improved communication on resolutions and bills.</p>



<p>Following the cabinet meeting, Marguerite Rawalt and Honorable John Macy, Jr. highlighted the positive strides made in addressing issues related to women&#8217;s roles in the military and workforce. They emphasized the importance of promoting women&#8217;s contributions, especially in times of crisis such as the Cuban Missile Crisis. The committee members remained professional, advocating for women&#8217;s relevance to national security without succumbing to individual anger.</p>



<p>However, the committee&#8217;s optimism was tempered by a press conference where U.S. Cabinet representative John McCone claimed that the status of women was a low priority amid the pressing matters facing the government. The official asserted, &#8220;As we have a lot going right now, the status of women is at a low priority at the moment.&#8221; This disappointing declaration underscored the uphill battle the PCSW faces in securing recognition for women&#8217;s issues in the current political climate. The committee questions how America could be a powerhouse if women were marginalized and thus immobilized. This blow marks the second occasion where the U.S. government seemingly disregarded the PCSW.</p>



<p>The Presidential Committee on the Status of Women has released a press statement in response to the blatant disrespect of the Cabinet. &#8220;The Presidential Commission on the Status of Women condemns the actions of the US Cabinet and the statement made by the Director of the CIA. Director John McCone outwardly expressed the Cabinet’s disinterest in the rights of American women. During a press conference with the PCSW and US Senate, McCone stated that on the list of their priorities, our directives were very low. These directives detailed plans for empowering women in regards to the current state of our nation given the Cuban Missile Crisis. The PCSW would like to express their disappointment in our US Cabinet for not giving their support for half of the US population.&#8221;</p>



<p>The PCSW remains determined to uphold Eleanor Roosevelt&#8217;s legacy, urging the government to recognize and prioritize the contributions of women to the nation&#8217;s well-being.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Missile crisis brings positive changes for women in war-related industries</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/missile-crisis-brings-positive-changes-for-women-in-war-related-industries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:43:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Though the unfortunate crisis involving the U.S. and USSR in Cuba has raised tensions and concerns of war, there are also many American domestic concerns]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Though the unfortunate crisis involving the U.S. and USSR in Cuba has raised tensions and concerns of war, there are also many American domestic concerns that could be revolutionary in women&#8217;s rights. The war effort is supported by women which is reflected by the growing number of women in the workplace aiding in war efforts. Not only does this benefit the factory industry and war production, but also boosts the domestic economy, advancing and building the nation. As for opportunities for women, the current crisis has been evidenced in women&#8217;s abilities and aspirations. </p>



<p>The press representative for the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women commented saying, &#8220;Additionally, our commission has been working towards creating legislative reforms that focus on educational opportunities&#8230;to ensure that these women are starting off with the right skill set.&#8221; </p>



<p>Women will have opportunities to be business owners and entrepreneurs unlike ever before. This crisis has brought on the guarantee of women in the workplace and to have equal freedoms.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BREAKING NEWS: Classified US Government Documents released to the Public</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/breaking-news-classified-us-government-documents-released-to-the-public/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To our fellow Americans,&#160; This letter was drafted by Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson depicts the status of women in the eyes of the U.S.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To our fellow Americans,&nbsp;</p>



<p>This letter was drafted by Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson depicts the status of women in the eyes of the U.S. Cabinet and Vice President. This letter was in response to the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women after they proposed multiple resolutions to address the labor standards of women, women&#8217;s civic engagement, and women’s engagement in the ongoing Missile Crisis in Cuba. To highlight some of his sentiments, he stated that the sentiments of the PCSW were not priorities, and the administration does not have the time to address any of these issues.</p>



<p>The women in America should not take elements of this letter and be content. The women in America should take this letter as an opportunity to prove to their governmental representatives that their contributions to the public sphere are still relevant to embody the capitalist values of our society.</p>



<p><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/k2LLD4vH6iG_JblqhSpS7QsFl6lsj-xA1Nq8CGOue96ary85kG9YWrti95zeUa6wg-fztL4HtSOOYSDmge2APDOfS56tYtsynR3JC_DMGzOxAPsU6RjT2FKPo9LubOa6dkEjcORgJqsKT6JUqrZ9Obi98ZavgddFmkZIYNaOczrI3aFtS7hyuom5QlUSKg" width="93" height="93"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/9NG4gKNdsHHLkjYuYZtZWGnZdQI03dXQybaSSuIXeeYcNA_usYSBVFcvxgO8NW6CVW0gGiuxV6Iz5rU8EJyVO_aVxx3I1oSQ3VPCuDLORUw8Gq6rZ6otpPz0L8FXCl-eHAi-PV-AXTsq-h1zW6OCxhm7rFB-qqWKgvvxINpdOp6-38nkewZyZdMsdC0oWQ" width="160" height="84"></p>



<p>Letter from LBJ</p>



<p>Office of President John F. Kennedy</p>



<p>Washington D.C.<br>October 1962</p>



<p>_____________________________________________________________________________</p>



<p>October 1962, Washington D.C. &#8211;</p>



<p>While your input on policy has been appreciated previously. I have the unfortunate task of informing your commission that we currently cannot pursue your policies regarding women in the workplace. They may have some potential, but because of the events occurring in Cuba, the President does not have the time to review them.</p>



<p>Your commitment to our nation is admirable, and I have nothing but respect for Mrs. Roosevelt. However, while we struggle with a response to this crisis, we cannot spare any time to review this report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Office of the Vice President of the United States of America</p>



<p>Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson</p>



<p>The letter, when delivered to Mrs. Roosevelt, the former first lady,&nbsp; <em>may</em> have contributed to her death, it seemed to have caused her weak heart to give out. Unfortunately, she passed away later that night, and America lost a national treasure. Now the American people are faced with a decision, will we tolerate her death? Will we let Mr. Vice President Lyndon B Johnson gets away with his disregard for women or will we stand up to him? <strong>America stands true today, and America will stand strong tomorrow, with women behind it.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Concerned American Citizen</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What, if any, Roles can Women Play in Society?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/what-if-any-roles-can-women-play-in-society/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 1962, the role of women in society is becoming more important. It is becoming more than just cooking, cleaning, and watching the children. The]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In 1962, the role of women in society is becoming more important. It is becoming more than just cooking, cleaning, and watching the children. The role that they can play in society is now more important than it has been before. </p>



<p>Hon. Orville Freeman mentions how women can play a significant role in the Cold War between America and Cuba. We have men who are standing with women to want to help them become more active in American society. Working with other powerful women and men can help everyone achieve a common goal that they want, which is for women to have more roles within society. </p>



<p>As a group, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women are working to see if they can introduce more women into the medical field, as well as the serving in the war if they so please. This would allow more empowerment within women, allowing them to be more confident to share their ideas; a critical perspective when considering the development of America. </p>



<p>Freeman also mentioned in an interview, “We believe that providing loans to women in entrepreneurship would enhance network and collaboration between women and those collaborations could be channeled into civic duties.”</p>



<p>Providing loans to allow women to be able to experience different professions will allow them to want to be more active in society. This is important because whether or not you need people to be more active in society, if they are not willing to do it, less people will want to be active in society. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PCSW Determined to Stand Strong in the Wake of Eleanor Roosevelt&#8217;s Death</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/pcsw-determined-to-stand-strong-in-the-wake-of-eleanor-roosevelts-death/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Swadha Garnaik, BBC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 05:03:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=435</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Presidential Commission on the Status of Women is reeling from the shocking demise of First Lady Eleanor Roosevelt. A prominent figure in the fight]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Presidential Commission on the Status of Women is reeling from the shocking demise of First Lady Eleanor Roosevelt. A prominent figure in the fight for women&#8217;s rights and the Honorable Chair of their committee, passed away as a letter sent by Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson caused complications with the former First Lady&#8217;s weak heart and eventually led to her passing. The contents of the letter exposed a dismissive attitude toward the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW), Roosevelt&#8217;s passion and life&#8217;s work, and that the Kennedy administration had chosen to overlook the hard work undertaken by the committee. </p>



<p>Mary Bunting, recognizing the need for a decisive response, urged her fellow members to &#8220;put their foot down&#8221; and &#8220;take an assertive stance&#8221;. Despite the emotional toll of Eleanor Roosevelt&#8217;s death, the committee recognizes the need to remain professional and strategic. Key committee member John Macy Jr. emphasized the importance of honoring Eleanor&#8217;s legacy by continuing her life&#8217;s work and remaining diligent to create change for women&#8217;s rights. </p>



<p>The PCSW, determined not to give up on the progress Eleanor Roosevelt had fought for, stands united in their quest for justice and equal rights.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ELEANOR ROOSEVELT DEAD</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/eleanor-roosevelt-dead/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:05:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=433</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women: The Head Chairman, an important, influential woman who was a friend to many, Eleanor Roosevelt was abruptly injured.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Presidential Commission on the Status of Women: The Head Chairman, an important, influential woman who was a friend to many, Eleanor Roosevelt was abruptly injured. It was later informed that Miss Rosevelt has passed away, due to the impact of a letter, more information to come soon!!!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Empowering Women: The Presidential Commission&#8217;s Drive For Gender Equality</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/empowering-women-the-presidential-commissions-drive-for-gender-equality/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Swadha Garnaik, BBC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 03:13:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=204</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) has embarked on a historic mission to enhance the conditions of women in the United States.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) has embarked on a historic mission to enhance the conditions of women in the United States. Miss Dorothy Height, President of the National Council of Black Women of America, provided a poignant perspective on the Commission&#8217;s dedicated efforts, particularly in addressing the unique challenges faced by black women in the workforce.</p>



<p>Miss Height emphasized the need to raise global awareness about the plight of black women, focusing on their struggles in the American labor force. Miss Height emphasized the Commission&#8217;s stance on empowering women, stating, &#8220;I would like to call upon all governments everywhere to notice a black woman of your country and uplift them, do not discriminate. Incorporate them into all sectors of society, make sure they are advocated, and that they are valued as they should be.&#8221;</p>



<p>Advocating for herself, Miss Height highlighted her valuable perspective as a black woman, aiming to ensure that the voices of black women were heard in high-level government discussions. The Commission&#8217;s strategy reflected a commitment to inclusivity and a recognition of the distinct challenges faced by black women.</p>



<p>The Senate and PCSW have been collaborating in an effort to improve the condition of women. Recognizing that motherly duties often hindered women&#8217;s progress, the Commission proposed universal daycare and preschool to strengthen the workforce and enable women&#8217;s education. Dr. Richard Lester, Chairman of the Economics Department at Princeton University, discussed the resolution&#8217;s impact on gender disparities, particularly the wage gap. In addition, New York representative Jessica Weis discussed how the Commission aims to encourage the establishment of an Equal Pay Act and anti-discrimination laws covering both gender and race.</p>



<p>While the Commission primarily has corresponded with the President through letters, their endorsement of policy changes marks a pivotal step toward gender equality. The comprehensive approach taken by the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women in 1962 is laying the foundation for subsequent advancements in women&#8217;s rights, recognizing women as a powerful force for national prosperity.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Liveblog (Historical)</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/friday-liveblog-historical/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael McCarthy, Deputy USG for Media]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Presidential commission aims to improve conditions for women</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/07/presidential-commission-aims-to-improve-conditions-for-women/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Swadha Garnaik, BBC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 05:43:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=116</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a renewed effort to address the enduring discrimination faced by women in the United States, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW)]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a renewed effort to address the enduring discrimination faced by women in the United States, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (PCSW) is gearing up to suggest impactful ideas to the 1962 administration. The bipartisan organization of 26 members was originally founded by President John F. Kennedy and led by the indomitable Eleanor Roosevelt. The committee, focused on issues ranging from education to insurance and employment, aims to bring changes to existing legislation and provide unwavering support to women in achieving their aspirations. The committee&#8217;s mission revolves around advocating for women&#8217;s rights while considering the evolving societal expectations of the era.</p>



<p>When questioned about his approach to the problem, Dr. Richard Lester, esteemed Chairman of the Economics Department at Princeton University, expressed his commitment to developing solutions that best serve the interests of all women, taking into account the diversity of their experiences and challenges. &#8220;We are here to support women in whatever they aspire to achieve,&#8221; he said. &#8220;Our goal is to create an environment where women can thrive in every aspect of their lives.&#8221;</p>



<p>The primary objectives of this effort include the establishment of robust labor standards<br>for women, promoting civic empowerment, and extending support to mothers and homemakers. With a notable emphasis on labor standards, as Lester is driven by his expertise as a labor economics professor, he aims to address issues related to workplace inequality and gender-based wage gaps. &#8220;We want to see real change in the lives of American women. This includes pushing for the Equal Pay/Wages Acts and reaching a consensus on decisions that will truly benefit all women across the nation,&#8221; commented the passionate committee member.</p>



<p>As the PCSW prepares to present its proposals to the President, their hopes are high for a future where women are empowered, protected, and provided with equal opportunities in every aspect of American life. With a legacy rooted in the ideals of justice and equality, this organization is poised to make a significant impact on the lives of women throughout the nation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interview with the Secretary of Agriculture in the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/07/interview-with-the-secretary-of-agriculture-in-the-presidential-commission-on-the-status-of-women/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 03:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=84</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-video"><video controls src="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Caleb-Renner-interview-first-assignment.mov"></video></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Caleb-Renner-interview-first-assignment.mov" length="88715318" type="video/quicktime" />

			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
