<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Opinion &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/opinion/feed/?simply_static_page=1498" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 19:52:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The U.K. conquers Argentinian Falklands territory</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/the-u-k-conquers-argentinian-falklands-territory/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dia Murali, Buenos Aires Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 16:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Britain&#8217;s brutalization of Argentinian forces over the occupation of the Falklands seems to have inflated the egos of House of Commons representatives. They callously deem]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Britain&#8217;s brutalization of Argentinian forces over the occupation of the Falklands seems to have inflated the egos of House of Commons representatives. They callously deem this conflict as an &#8220;economic opportunity&#8221; and discuss plans to initiate a war with Argentina. The consensus of the body establishes that &#8220;war is imminent&#8221; and slanders Argentina by deeming the country as &#8220;aggressors.&#8221;</p>



<p>It is confirmed by a House of Commons member that the U.K. is working to &#8220;preemptively&#8221; attack Argentina. The only justification for this is Argentina&#8217;s supposed antagonizing of the U.K., which was merely a question of Argentina defending their rightful territory. This proposition of extreme violence serves as a statement to establish that the U.K. is &#8220;the greatest country in the world&#8221; and that &#8220;if war is what it takes to prove it, so be it.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Conservative Party in the House is working on a paper named &#8220;Beating Argentina Badly Efficiently&#8221; to begin militarizing the Falklands in an attempt to intimidate and bombard Argentina. The aggressively named paper is being kept under wraps to avoid attention from other nations—especially the U.S. The U.K. is looking to convert current residents of the Falklands to British citizens and extend U.K. infrastructure. Establishing a 45,000 strong military presence in the Falklands will serve to help Britain maintain its dictator-like control over the islands. The paper goes so far as to condone lethal violence and &#8220;extermination&#8221; against those &#8220;invaders&#8221; who oppose their reign.</p>



<p> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>No objective news will come out of Al Jazeera until it cuts off Qatar</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/no-objective-news-will-come-out-of-al-jazeera-until-it-cuts-off-qatar/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 16:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Al Jazeera Editorial Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the minutes after the Qatari minister of transportation threatened to cut off Al Jazeera and hold its journalists accountable, the network began discussing new]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the minutes after the Qatari minister of transportation threatened to cut off Al Jazeera and hold its journalists accountable, the network began discussing new plans to please the Qatari government. In the SLAY working paper, Al Jazeera discussed plans to change their coverage and portray Qatar in a more positive light.</p>



<p>One of the clauses in the paper involves Al Jazeera hiring an economist from the greater Middle East to speak about why Qatar is an ideal nation to move to because of its strong resources. They also hope to create a project to tell stories and traditions from Qatar to ensure its history is portrayed in the best light possible.</p>



<p>All after the government threatened to fire the Board of Directors and hold them hostage.</p>



<p>The editorial opinion of the Moscow Times is that when dictatorships begin threatening the well-being of journalists, the journalists’ lives take precedence over adherence to the truth. Al Jazeera has implemented some workarounds to ensure journalistic integrity, such as company-wide surveys to identify points of reform in stories, such as impartiality and bias. However, these workarounds are anonymous and could easily be manipulated by the Qatari government. Furthermore, describing investment opportunities in Qatar may enrich the government to further suppress the views of journalists.</p>



<p>In another working paper, titled “We Address Takeover Evacuation” (We ATE), Al Jazeera has laid out plans to leave the country in case the government attempts to falsely imprison or harm the journalists. However, the Moscow Times believes that this must be the action taken if Qatar’s money continues to suppress the voice of journalists. Censorship naturally degrades reporting; the Balkans Director even questioned, “have we defined journalistic standards for hiring?” If Al Jazeera hopes to maintain serious coverage and be considered a voice of the Arab World, it must have the courage to leave Qatar and establish its own independence as a network.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
