<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Olivya Lang, MTV &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/author/olang/feed/?simply_static_page=1319" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:44:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>After The Janes Press Conference Fiasco, Members Speak Out</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/after-the-janes-press-conference-fiasco-members-speak-out/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 06:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Janes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1664</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As you all have heard, something huge has happened in the Janes. During the press conference, an argument ensured between two members, and the press]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As you all have heard, something huge has happened in the Janes. During the press conference, an argument ensured between two members, and the press heard something about getting arrested. Here&#8217;s the video of the argument.</p>



<p></p>



<p>A group has split apart from the Janes. The organization has been spilt into one group of the 7 original members &#8220;The Janes&#8221; and The other three members are now a part of an unknown organization called &#8220;The Does&#8221;. </p>



<p>MTV was privileged to get a statement from two members of &#8220;The Janes&#8221;, The Director of Public Policy and the Director of Communications. </p>



<p>&#8220;We are the Janes collective. A collective is founded on togetherness. the Janes are incredibly hurt and betrayed by the treason of former Janes&#8217; member Gabriela Vasquez AKA Gabby. One of the most discussed values the Janes value is loyalty. A person seeking abortion needs to trust the abortion clinic and clinician. Thus we cannot support Gabriela, and we will be investigating the situation and plan to sue her. Following Gabriela, the Lead Activist is the Directory of Community Relations and the Founder.&#8221;</p>



<p>On the other hand, anonymous source told MTV that they do not plan to follow through with the legal actions presented by the Directors of Public Policy and Communications. </p>



<p>There was a second leak relating to the Janes partnership with ExxonMobil. ExxonMobil gave &#8220;The Janes&#8221; $500K for funds. What they don&#8217;t know is that the money is being laundered to the underground group &#8220;The Does&#8221;, and they are using this money to do more embezzlement. This is why &#8220;The Janes&#8221; was split in the first place. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>ExxonMobil is making a playlist for Reception Tonight?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/exxonmobil-is-making-a-playlist-for-reception-tonight/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 21:22:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1611</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[MTV just listened to ExxonMobil Board of Directors was asked to add some songs to a playlist for our Reception tonight, and boy it&#8217;s a]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>MTV just listened to ExxonMobil Board of Directors was asked to add some songs to a playlist for our Reception tonight, and boy it&#8217;s a good one!  The reason why MTV was invited was that the CEO of ExxonMobil told MTV, “We are all on fire. It is time to turn this ship around.” </p>



<p>Here is the Link to all of the Songs &#8211; <a href="https://open.spotify.com/playlist/5i110Ukju6zKUmHy7CKrFf?si=EWdn6qcKTU6Fsw5tsTI4IA">https://open.spotify.com/playlist/5i110Ukju6zKUmHy7CKrFf?si=EWdn6qcKTU6Fsw5tsTI4IA</a></p>



<p>The first song brought up was <strong>Eraser by Ed Sheeran.</strong> This song had absolutely no explanation and no significance, it failed 2 to 4. </p>



<p>The next song that was brought up was <strong>Mo Bamba by Sheck West</strong> But, alas, they choose to use the clean one. Their reason was for giggles because it doesn&#8217;t sound like the original. Hence, why it passed Unanimously! </p>



<p>Calling all Swifties! The next song is <strong>You Belong with Me by the Queen of Pop, T-Swift</strong>! This song was suggested by the VP of Corporate Strategic Planning. “The citizens on the tanker belong in our hearts.”</p>



<p>This next song was the biggest Party song (Pun intended) in the 2010s. <strong>Party in the U.S.A by Miley Cyrus. </strong>There was no exact reason why it was mentioned but none the matter. It passed unanimously.</p>



<p>This next song is very controversial, but nonetheless, it was mentioned. The song is <strong>Touch the Sky by Kanye West</strong>. The Board of Directors did a one-for and one-against debate for this song. The Director for this song was the VP of Public and Government Affairs. &#8220;It&#8217;s Musical genius! It’s just one song, it&#8217;s insane!” The director that was against the song was the VP of Corporate Strategic Planning. He said that &#8220;With everything going on with Kayne, do we want our public image to show we support Kayne? With everything against him, this could affect our image. This is your (VP of Public and Government Affairs) job and your reputation on the line.&#8221; Despite the VP of Public and Government Affairs speaking for this song, it failed unanimously. </p>



<p>This next song did the opposite of the Kayne song, it passed unanimously! This song is <strong>Runaway Baby by Bruno Mars</strong>. They also didn&#8217;t give me a reason why but it is a good song though!</p>



<p>The final song that was voted on failed. With 2 votes for and 4 votes against, was the song <strong>Butter by BTS</strong>. Even though they&#8217;re being enlisted into the army, they still are loved in people&#8217;s hearts. The now-former VP of Public and Government Affairs&#8217; explanation was butter equals oil in cooking, and ExxonMobil stands for oil. </p>



<p>The Board is very excited about the reception and can&#8217;t wait for the participants to hear the tunes playlist. If you have any suggestions for songs to add to the list, click the link below to add songs to the potential list!</p>



<p><a href="https://forms.gle/eu9nyhPhXTn4QeBx5">https://forms.gle/eu9nyhPhXTn4QeBx5</a></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exxon Mobil&#8217;s plan to resolve their detained tanker</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/exxon-mobils-plan-to-resolve-their-detained-tanker/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 08:30:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1391</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With this late-night crisis in full swing. The Exxon Mobile Board of Directors are hard at work creating solutions to get their tanker ship back]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With this late-night crisis in full swing. The Exxon Mobile Board of Directors are hard at work creating solutions to get their tanker ship back into their control. </p>



<p>For some background on the issue, Russia has taken captive one of their tanker ships, filled with precious oil as well as Exxon Employees.</p>



<p>Currently, their main priority is the safety of the hostages and getting their ship back. Some solutions may include but are not limited to. Tracing the ship, since it&#8217;s filled with technology, there got to be a way to trace it! Contact tracing, we did it during the COVID-19 pandemic, how hard could it be? They would just be using the route they have, and see where the ship was when they last had contact with it. </p>



<p>As for the future, they plan on making sure this never happens again. One way to avoid it is to avoid Russian Territories. The only reason why they are in this mess is that they were in Russian territory. </p>



<p>At this moment, their main priority is getting the people taken hostage home safely. Our thoughts and prayers are going to Exxon Mobile. </p>



<p></p>



<p>Good Night and see you all when the sun shines. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Exxon Mobile Board of Directors are Alive!</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/exxon-mobile-board-of-directors-are-alive/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 01:27:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1206</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The last committee session for Exxon Mobile was a closed session, but they are now open to the public in the latest session. MTV was]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-audio"><audio controls src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/20230203_190257.mp3"></audio></figure>



<p>The last committee session for Exxon Mobile was a closed session, but they are now open to the public in the latest session. MTV was fortunate enough to talk with Exxon Mobil&#8217;s President, Tom Gibbs, you may listen to the interview above.</p>



<p>Gibbs stated that they are currently working hard on their directives and once they are finished, they will change the world, one step at a time. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>US Secretary of Defense asks Europe to do more in Russia-Ukraine War</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/us-secretary-of-defense-asks-europe-to-do-more-in-russia-ukraine-war/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 01 Feb 2023 23:47:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=783</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Did you know that Lloyd Austin has been first in five different categories? He was the first Black secretary of defense, the first Black vice]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="1000" height="600" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/fea-when-will-war-in-ukraine-end.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-813" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/fea-when-will-war-in-ukraine-end.jpg 1000w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/fea-when-will-war-in-ukraine-end-300x180.jpg 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/fea-when-will-war-in-ukraine-end-768x461.jpg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1000px) 100vw, 1000px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">HOSTOMEL, UKRAINE &#8211; APRIL 08: Ukrainian soldier waves Ukrainian national flag while standing on top of an armoured personnel carrier (APC) on April 8, 2022 in Hostomel, Ukraine. After more than five weeks of war, Russia appears to have abandoned its goal of encircling the Ukrainian capital. However, Ukraine expects a renewed fight in the east and south. (Photo by Alexey Furman/Getty Images)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Did you know that Lloyd Austin has been first in five different categories? He was the first Black secretary of defense, the first Black vice chief of staff of the Army, the first Black person to lead U.S. Central Command, the first Black person to lead an Army corps in combat, and the first Black commanding general of a U.S. Army Division. However, during his latest speech, Secretary of Defense Austin explained why governments should care about Ukraine and why they should help.</p>



<p>“Stability and prosperity on both sides of the Atlantic are at stake. You know, the U.S. trading relationship with the European Union is the largest in the world. So when an aggressor manufactures a huge security crisis in Europe, it hits home for everyday Americans and Canadians,” Austin remarked.</p>



<p>The secretary of defense&#8217;s speech at the Halifax International Security Forum brings up how the situation in Russia and Ukraine started and how everyone is reacting to this situation. </p>



<p>To give some background of this major event. On Feb. 24, 2022, Russia invaded Ukraine, causing huge tensions throughout Europe for allies of Ukraine and allies of Russia. As of now, there have been more than 40,000 fatalities in the country. </p>



<p>Secretary Austin has accomplished many things in his lifetime, but when trying to resolve the argument on the use of tanks in Ukraine, he failed. He also had little to no support on this matter. The reason why he failed was because every country in NATO believes they are doing enough. When the question of if Germany was doing enough, he responded, “Yes, but we can all do more.” That must be the main reason why it did not pass, countries assumed they were doing enough.</p>



<p>Are countries doing enough? Can the secretary of defense solve this issue? </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
