<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Bluebird Aero Systems &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/archive/2021/category/bluebird-aero-systems/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 01:18:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>Major Movements Made By Bluebird Aero Systems</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/major-movements-made-by-bluebird-aero-systems/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bluebird Aero Systems]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The executives of Bluebird Aero Systems, the fast-growing Israeli technology company, have sparred over a wide variety of ideas for expansion of their services. A]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The executives of Bluebird Aero Systems, the fast-growing Israeli technology company, have sparred over a wide variety of ideas for expansion of their services. A general consensus was reached regarding the benefits of partnering with global governments, with executives showing significant desire to establish more formal ties with the United States government for both civilian and defense-related technology sales. Upon request for comment, Bluebird’s Vice President of Government Affairs stated that, “Bluebird would positively regard a partnership with a foreign nation,” although no specific nations were mentioned. Expansion is also being considered into states with the potential for high use of these aircraft, with the potential for future contracts existing with India and many Middle Eastern nations, while demonstrated animosity exists towards the idea of a contracted partnership with Russia.</p>



<p>Reportedly, a few members of the executive board have also expressed interest in joining the Israeli Defense Fund, a step that would tie the corporation even more closely to the Israeli government and provide increased linkage with foreign partners, including the United States. This push has been spearheaded by Bluebird’s Chief of Operations, who has emphasized the importance of international cooperation. While a directive has been drafted in this matter, its status is unknown as of press time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As of Sunday morning, Bluebird has passed a directive proposing a formal partnership with Boeing after extensive discussions. This partnership will be a collaboration between the two businesses in order to develop more advanced technologies, including aeronautics systems, and progress a joint green initiative. Boeing has not yet formally agreed to the partnership, and updates will be provided as the partnership is formalized.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Belarus Confirms Deal with Northrop Grumman Harris III</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/belarus-confirms-deal-with-northrop-grumman-harris-iii/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Fatimah Moe, Miami Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 22:27:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BAE Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bluebird Aero Systems]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=251</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[President of Belarus and Chairman of the State Military-Industrial Committee, Svetlana Tikhanovskaya, reached out to Northrop G Harris III to accept a deal with the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>President of Belarus and Chairman of the State Military-Industrial Committee, Svetlana Tikhanovskaya, reached out to Northrop G Harris III to accept a deal with the company. In a letter to Northrop G Hariss III, Tikhanovskaya expresses concern over the intentions of other corporations stating they might attempt to “undercut our relationship”. Tikhanovskaya believes that publicly discussing their partnership would put Belarus and the US Government on “unfavorable terms.” She wishes for more private communication with Northrop G Harris III.</p>



<p>This is just another instance of the media black out that is occuring. Defense companies around the world are holding closed meetings &#8211; turning away reporters and press. BAE systems faced internal scandal with one of their executives and Lockheed Martin has refused any statement. Bluebird Aero systems has turned down most press interference, until their recent press statement, denying any legitimate part in the misuse of their equipment in Belarus.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The CIA and DOD have also refused any meetings with the press.</p>



<p>While Many companies remain cryptic, Northrop G Harris III has remained fairly forthcoming with information. But only time will tell if they follow suit with the other defense companies.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">251</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bluebird Aero to Sell drones to new Belarus Government</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/bluebird-aero-to-sell-drones-to-new-belarus-government/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 20:58:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Bluebird Aero Systems]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=207</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An excerpt from a new directive from the Board of the Israeli-based Bluebird Aero Systems: Sells drones to Belarus Unrestricted line of sales to Belarus]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>An excerpt from a new directive from the Board of the Israeli-based Bluebird Aero Systems:</p>



<ul><li>Sells drones to Belarus</li><li>Unrestricted line of sales to Belarus</li></ul>



<ol><li>Sells the new Belarusian government under Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya the requested combat drones as part of its widespread reform of the military.</li><li>Offers an unrestricted line of access to the Belarusian government to purchase more products from Bluebird</li></ol>



<p>This story is developing.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">207</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bluebird Aero Systems Directors To Convene, Considering Expansion</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/bluebird-aero-systems-directors-to-convene-considering-expansion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 16:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bluebird Aero Systems]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Jan. 5, 2021, the Board of Directors of the Bluebird Aero Systems Corporation are scheduled to convene. They will likely discuss the opportunity to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On Jan. 5, 2021, the Board of Directors of the Bluebird Aero Systems Corporation are scheduled to convene. They will likely discuss the opportunity to expand global use of the&nbsp; Unmanned Aircraft Systems (UAS) and Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) technologies. The UAS and the UAV&nbsp; have the potential to drastically change the way many technologies are used by the military and civilians.</p>



<p>Bluebird Aero is an up-and-coming company, which was founded in 2002. The company develops and sells UAS and UAV technology, which they say have a variety of military and civilian uses. Some being: military surveillance missions, weather tracking, and cargo deliveries. These technologies are becoming increasingly relevant, with a recent large purchase of stock by the Israeli government bringing global attention to the corporation. UAS and UAV technology could be valuable advancements in the many conflicts in which the Israeli government currently has a stake and are being utilized by several governments, including India.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Directors are expected to address the growth of the company, among other things, raising questions regarding executive plans surrounding research and development, governmental cooperation, and use in a growing number of contexts. Either way, the decisions made at the upcoming meetings may be incredibly consequential.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">105</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
