<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Sebastian Marquez, Der Speigel &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/author/smarquez/feed/?simply_static_page=1389" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:53:12 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>US and Exxon Mobil expanding horizons for competitive yet sustainable energy</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/us-and-exxon-mobil-expanding-horizons-for-competitive-yet-sustainable-energy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Marquez, Der Speigel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 19:10:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1002</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The US Cabinet recently held a meeting with key Exxon Mobil executives to discuss the details of deal between the two bodies. This deal holds]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The US Cabinet recently held a meeting with key Exxon Mobil executives to discuss the details of deal between the two bodies. This deal holds great promise for a future built on the foundations of affordable and competitive renewable energy sources available to the masses. </p>



<p>In their meeting earlier today, the US cabinet proposed a groundbreaking $1.5 billion in subsidies to be dispersed to the oil giant over the next 5 years. This sum of money will ensure that Exxon has adequate funding to research and develop renewable energy sources and lower the price of oil to be more competitive with foreign nations’ prices. Exxon Mobil has already pledged $500 million of their own to research and develop biofuel, EVs, and carbon captures and plans to review their progress every six months to ensure they are “getting their money’s worth,” according to the company’s press secretary, with a possibility of renewing or increasing funding at the end of the review period. </p>



<p>Everyone involved in the meeting appeared to be quite thrilled to be negotiating a deal with the other party, with the US Secretary of the Treasury proudly remarking “There’s nothing more attractive than oil!” Perhaps another reason for everyone’s joyful demeanors lies in the fact that The US government will be providing subsidies to decrease the price of oil per barrel from approximately $74 per barrel, according to Markets Insider at the time of publication, to below Russia’s cost of $71 per barrel and then slowly decrease to a goal of $65 per barrel over the five-year period. This deal allows Exxon to expand its presence into numerous other European markets, and even China, at a more affordable price than Russian oil which many nations are still forced to purchase over American oil due to its higher price and accomplishes the US’s goal of cutting Russia out of the global economy and lowering the price of oil and gasoline domestically. </p>



<p>This is all great news, for Americans, not so much Russians and their secret allies, however, one member of the US cabinet made it clear that the deal’s emphasis isn’t on sustainability but won’t harm sustainability either, a confusing statement considering where the US government is planning Exxon to employ their subsidies, leaving room to wonder if there will be alternative machinations planned between Exxon and the US government.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The cancerous corrosion of coral environments</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/the-cancerous-corrosion-of-coral-environments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Sebastian Marquez, Der Speigel]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:38:10 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=835</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Climate change has already wreaked havoc on the world’s populations and environments, and its damages will only further escalate with time. Humanity has accomplished countless]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Climate change has already wreaked  havoc on the world’s populations and environments, and its damages will only further escalate with time. Humanity has accomplished countless impressive feats in fields of education, innovation, sports, physical performance, philosophy, and wisdom. Yet, despite all our time on this beloved planet, so little effort has been directed towards sustaining the planet that has provided so much. Nature contains immensely beautiful landscapes, habitats, and environments that oftentimes play second fiddle to the interest of advancement, whether directly through actions including deforestation to make room for factories or indirectly through those same factories spewing out boundless and unchecked pollution. The world simply needs to start taking better care of the planet or we will tear it apart until the once gorgeous and abundant world we once knew vanishes before our very eyes.</p>



<p> It is so easy for anyone with a laptop to write about the horridness of climate change crisis but offer no further explanation, guidance, or commentary on the issue. When facing any giant problem, it remains wise to break the issue down into more manageable and approachable issues, such as issues about climate/environmental changes that lie in coral reefs. Coral environments are crucial to marine life across the globe and support many oceanic communities and even nations. When asked about the significance of coral reefs to an island nation’s cultural identity and economy, the representative from New Zealand said, “It is important to maintain coral and reef habitats because they are the crutch on which so many ecosystems rely. These reefs are home to numerous species of small fish who in turn, feed and nourish the predator fish who are consumed by the nearby populaces for food. If the reefs disappear, so will the fish we eat. With societies polluting and overfishing, people really aren&#8217;t making it easy for the oceanic ecosystems to keep up with this outrageous pace.” Unfortunately, many individuals live in areas of the world where the effects of climate change are so visible as they are in a nation such as New Zealand that faces the devastating reality that their cherished reefs are in danger of disappearing. </p>



<p>The New Zealand representative continued, listing numerous plans of action to protect their reefs from the effects of climate and environmental change, citing wishes to, “subsidize the game and wildlife department to help further protect the numerous ecosystems from being overhunted and overfished. Additionally, increasing fines for littering along beach areas, as well as the number of organizations which are tasked with cleaning up ecosystems, including reefs.” </p>



<p>The representative&#8217;s parting words to those who are still failing to realize the brevity of time with which the world has to act on this matter are captured in the following statement: “When island nations begin to sink, and the damage is too far gone, maybe then they’ll realize it all could have been avoided.” With these solemn words, hopefully, enough people and nations will be called to take immediate action, realize yesterday was the time to act, and hopefully, tomorrow will not be the day when we look back on a ravaged and depleted world too far gone and lament what we have done.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
