<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Uncategorized &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/uncategorized/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:00:08 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Guerrilla fighters at the Sino-Indian border</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/guerrilla-fighters-at-the-sino-indian-border/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Margaret Vacek, The Dawn]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=583</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In recent updates there have been news of Indian guerrilla fighters at the border with China in response to the growing India and China border]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In recent updates there have been news of Indian guerrilla fighters at the border with China in response to the growing India and China border conflict. Guerrilla fighters may include armed civilians and non-professional paramilitary groups, even children.</p>



<p>Although the council claimed that safety of their people was the biggest concern, these fighters at the high risk Indian border raise many concerns about this. This also brings into question the preparedness of the nation as the border troops are not high-ranking military but civilians who are not trained and are at high risk facing the strong Chinese army.</p>



<p>In today&#8217;s press conference, the Indian Minister of Communications responded claiming, &#8220;&#8230;in our last press conference we did mention that we were confident in winning this war and that we believed we had the military strength to really support it.&#8221; This claim seems to falsify their reinforcing statement on the safety of Indian citizens as their &#8220;military strength&#8221; is made up of untrained citizens and possibly children, and ultimately contrasts the recent developments.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X&#8217;s New Collaboration Meltdown 💩</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/xs-new-collaboration-meltdown-%f0%9f%92%a9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The social media platform X, formerly known as Twitter, has created new borders for the expansion of the app. X&#8217;s current plan includes the collaboration]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The social media platform X, formerly known as Twitter, has created new borders for the expansion of the app. X&#8217;s current plan includes the collaboration of their companies such as Solar City and The Boring Company to create additional features to the app. These upgrades have currently been put on a major hold after the U.S. government announced they&#8217;ll be suing the platform regarding the accusations of spreading false information on the app. </p>



<p>The press representative of X announced yesterday the creation of &#8220;X Connect&#8221;, a user platform made to go worldwide, featuring add-ons for the app such as X Maps which collaborates with Solar City and X to create a map system within their app to help users. X also wants to implement an AI source into the app to allow for artificial intelligence to assist users. However, with the recent reaction from Elon Musk to the U.S. government being quite questionable, will X continue their journey to the collaboration of companies to the platform?</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNGA: The Real &#8220;Heroes&#8221; of Climate Change</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/unga-the-real-heroes-of-climate-change/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UNGA plans for solving the climate crisis have reached a stalemate. The general assembly is slow on their topic and the world does not]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The UNGA plans for solving the climate crisis have reached a stalemate. The general assembly is slow on their topic and the world does not have enough time for them to take their sweet time. No solution of any kind has been mainly addressed, countries are not getting anywhere on there on a plan of any kind. However, many countries pushed for the topic of climate change to be primarily addressed. </p>



<p>Since the 1850s, the climate crisis has shadowed the world every day. The climate of the world has been majorly changing the ideologies of countries through the years. Today the climate crisis is a major crisis for each and every country and the UNGA is taking their time on the issue that has increasingly been affecting every country. The UNGA will be wiped out because of climate change before they can help climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Delegations such as New Zealand have stated that “These solutions have taken much longer than they would like” and climate change is going to affect countries faster than we think. Other countries such as Tanzania say ,“ They agree with the resolutions going on currently.” The UNGA needs to pick a common direction and recommend a plan before it&#8217;s too late. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Future of Russia-Ukraine</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/future-of-russia-ukraine/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:55:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=323</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UNSC has been dealing with heavy disputes regarding the Russia-Ukraine war. Foundationally, the UNSC has been agreeing over the fact that violence with violence]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The UNSC has been dealing with heavy disputes regarding the Russia-Ukraine war. Foundationally, the UNSC has been agreeing over the fact that violence with violence is not the answer but rather it is necessary to negotiate with peaceful talks and negotiations to further discuss this matter.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Allied nations such as the U.S., Switzerland, and the UAE have been pushing for humanitarian aid, which the Russian Federation is open to. The U.S. primarily believes that it is important to focus on humanitarian aid first, before implementing other resolutions regarding the Russia-Ukraine war, as these would make humanitarian aid unable to reach the Ukrainian people and this war has been at the expense of the lives of civilians.</p>



<p>Additionally, due to Ukraine being a bread basket nation and having influence on many others, the impacts of this war such as food insecurity, and trading relations have been brought up due to the sheer economic impact, making it even more imperative to push for humanitarian aid. </p>



<p>Nonetheless, Brazil and China have not resonated with these sentiments as they feel that ending the war quickly should be the main goal. Brazil has proposed itself as a neutral mandator; using neutral grounds is needed to build communication between Russia and Ukraine. Switzerland has pushed back as they also have strong trade relations with both countries, leading to a clash between these two nations. </p>



<p>The Russian Federation, despite being open to Humanitarian Aid, has made it very clear that they do not condone NATO countries moving forward towards them. This was opposed by the U.S. and its allies who felt that this war was due to Russia invading a democratic country and have emphasized that they will be supporting the democracy of Ukraine as it is under the same protections as any other country.</p>



<p>In an interview with the Russian Federation, they shared strong sentiments about how they “will not yield to these NATO nations that are trying to interfere with our business and our direct conflict that is based in our cultural differences with Ukraine. That is not their business, that is not their place.” Although they have been open to talks, “there will most likely be very little progress made on this front.” The future of this war depends on these crucial decisions and only time will tell on how they will be able to combat these differences and resolve in favor of the people. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Welcome to CIMUN XX!</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/06/welcome-to-cimun-xx/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael McCarthy, Deputy USG for Media]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Wed, 06 Dec 2023 23:00:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=46</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Check back throughout the conference for news from the International Press Delegation.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Check back throughout the conference for news from the International Press Delegation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
