<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Association of Southeast Asian Nations &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2021/category/asean/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:20:49 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>Consensus on the Crisis in Korea</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/consensus-on-the-crisis-in-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Isabella Rosinia, BuzzFeed News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:20:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Association of Southeast Asian Nations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=336</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After much deliberation, members of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) have come to a consensus on the crisis in Korea.  According to the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After much deliberation, members of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) have come to a consensus on the crisis in Korea.  According to the resolution that was unanimously passed, there will be multiple new systems and programs created to help solve the crisis.  ASEAN has suggested the “creation of the ‘Pacify and Peace Program’ with the intent to foster international communist actions with Korea&#8230;form relations and negotiations with North Korea.”  This program seems to promise healthier relations between North Korean and members of ASEAN.  Additionally, the committee recommended “the creation of an ASEAN peace treaty with North Korean and Iran to denuclearize their arsenals.”  Seeing that the nuclear crisis in Iran had caused much uproar among the international community, it is reassuring to see that the committee has worked to solve any potential similar crises in the future.  Lastly, ASEAN “responds to nuclear weapons usage in the Southeast Asian region, ASEAN 6+ by applying the use of economic sanctions on the nation responsible&#8230;and preparing for military actions.”  The resolution passed by ASEAN seems to be promising for the health and prosperity of the international community.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">336</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran foreshadows North Korean nuclear development</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/iran-foreshadows-north-korean-nuclear-development/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Isabella Rosinia, BuzzFeed News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:46:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Association of Southeast Asian Nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=297</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Iran has officially begun to develop its nuclear weapons program. Recently, the Iranian leader stated that this is what happens when western nations do not]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Iran has officially begun to develop its nuclear weapons program. Recently, the Iranian leader stated that this is what happens when western nations do not have power over other countries, like Iran and North Korea.</p>



<p><img loading="lazy" width="339" height="271" src="https://lh6.googleusercontent.com/UoJW55FlcvtSa2AZyS8IMonnXBUost1r_yG3fARtPcXDpeJiW-ZCxXxuVql4NNsEhojbkJKRDCc9VxBGIAKALOnKc8dJw3D1BiWBDzhgoVNxoUtNXkyPp9To5FFsf88CNCJTsMsN"></p>



<p>Since the Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) has been discussing the situation in the Korean Peninsula, it can be assumed that the Iranian leader is seeking to foreshadow North Korea’s next move.</p>



<p>This news is extremely important to not just ASEAN members, but countries around the world. Currently, the committee is collaborating and discussing this crisis.&nbsp; We will let you know of any updates as they become available.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">297</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>“Nuking North Korea” would not affect South Korea “too much”: Singapore officials</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/nuking-north-korea-would-not-affect-south-korea-too-much-singapore-officials/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Zhang, The Korea Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Association of Southeast Asian Nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=292</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China and Laos have pushed for diplomatic solutions to solve dangerous nuclear instability within North Korea. A statement from the South Korean delegates has also]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>China and Laos have pushed for diplomatic solutions to solve dangerous nuclear instability within North Korea.</p>



<p>A statement from the South Korean delegates has also been released. “South Korea should maintain peace, until or unless threatened by the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK) [North Korea]. North Korea has continued to provoke the delegation of South Korea, and we would like to not act on a whim.”</p>



<p>The consensus is currently that continuing to be diplomatic is the best way to move forward. Still, some delegates oppose this.</p>



<p>‘Diplomatic action is not the best action” said the representative from Singapore Saturday evening.</p>



<p>The delegation from Singapore called for military pressure, believing that the European Union and the United States would support them.</p>



<p>“South Korea would not be affected too much, if we dropped one on (DPRK)” they reiterated.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Clearly, some countries do not have civilians and general welfare in mind.&nbsp;</p>



<p>ASEAN will continue to achieve a resolution to bring peace to the world and the Korean peninsula.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">292</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South China Sea Conflict Resolved</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/south-china-sea-conflict-resolved/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Isabella Rosinia, BuzzFeed News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 23:50:55 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Association of Southeast Asian Nations]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=260</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The South China Sea conflict, that has been plaguing much of the world for over a decade, has finally been resolved.  The ASEAN met to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The South China Sea conflict, that has been plaguing much of the world for over a decade, has finally been resolved.  The ASEAN met to discuss, amend, and vote on the two proposed draft resolutions.  It is now clear that they have made enough amendments to the draft resolutions, as both of them have passed.  Seeing that this conflict is seeking to be resolved by the passing of the resolutions, economic prosperity, free trade, and peaceful summits should be expected around the world.  While the issue of the South China Sea conflict has been discussed, debated, and resolved, the committee is now moving on to the situation on the Korean Peninsula.  We will keep you updated as more nations speak out on this issue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">260</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Potential Resolutions for the South China Sea Conflict</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/potential-resolutions-for-the-south-china-sea-conflict/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Isabella Rosinia, BuzzFeed News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:44:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Association of Southeast Asian Nations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=225</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) has been hard at work seeking solutions to the South China Sea conflict.  After extensive discussions, the committee]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) has been hard at work seeking solutions to the South China Sea conflict.  After extensive discussions, the committee has presented two separate resolutions. </p>



<p> In a bloc led by the Philippines and Laos, the notions of summits and economic growth were prioritized.  This draft resolution seems to promote peace and prosperity among nations around the world, especially those involved in the South China Sea issue.  Vulnerable nations have been promised protection through this resolution as well.  China has expressed concerns over the free trade plan that the Philippines bloc has presented.  </p>



<p>Conversely, in a bloc led by China, the issue of free trade was emphasized, this draft resolution seems to promote freedom of trade to all members of ASEAN as well as the option to participate in said program.  The Philippines has shown concern over the exclusiveness of this program, as it is limited to members of ASEAN and excludes all western influences.  Meanwhile, China has demonstrated its willingness to make amendments to its draft resolution.  We will update you with more specifics as they become available.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">225</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>North Korean leader Kim Jong-un hospitalized</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/north-korean-leader-kim-jong-un-hospitalized/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Zhang, The Korea Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:25:46 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Association of Southeast Asian Nations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=132</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kim Jong-un, North Korea’s leader, was recently hospitalized for potentially severe reasons. The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) will be coming together to discuss]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Kim Jong-un, North Korea’s leader, was recently hospitalized for potentially severe reasons. The Association of Southeast Asian Nations (ASEAN) will be coming together to discuss potential protocol if the leader were to pass away.</p>



<p>There would be many effects of Kim Jong-un’s death. One could be civil unrest and instability within the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea (DPRK), a state in an important geopolitical position situated between China and South Korea with nuclear arms and a military. ASEAN will be debating whether outside involvement should be used to prevent and or contain conflict within the DPRK.</p>



<p>Although South Korea’s close proximity calls for prevention of conflict, due to the close proximity, others do not agree. “Intervention, whether politically or militarily will only lead to unnecessary bloodshed, loss, and ignition of global tensions between major world powers” the representative from Laos said.</p>



<p>The issue at hand may also escalate China-U.S. competition due to China’s close connections to the Korean peninsula. This situation could also move into diplomatic and military committees at the United Nations.</p>



<p>In February, ASEAN will face the difficult challenge of setting aside differences in creating unity. The delegates from their respective countries will discuss the outcome of the state of the DPRK.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">132</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China Speaks Against Russia and the United States</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/china-speaks-against-russia-and-the-united-states/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Isabella Rosinia, BuzzFeed News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 03:20:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Association of Southeast Asian Nations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=97</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[China has stated that they believe that it is crucial for Western countries, like the United States and Russia, to not be included in the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>China has stated that they believe that it is crucial for Western countries, like the United States and Russia, to not be included in the conflict of the South China Sea. The Chinese government has claimed that these countries have no right to an opinion and only seek to further their political reach.</p>



<p>Furthermore, it was suggested that members of the Association of Southeast Asian Nations, also known as ASEAN, come together to discuss potential solutions to the issue of the South China Sea Conflict. Other countries such as Singapore, Thailand, and Malaysia, have expressed their support for the Chinese sentiments and objectives. Sovereignty has become an important topic of conversation regarding the issue of the South China Sea and possible solutions, we will keep you updated on this unfolding issue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">97</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Southeast Asia Situation</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/the-southeast-asia-situation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Isabella Rosinia, BuzzFeed News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 02:56:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Association of Southeast Asian Nations]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=90</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The situation in Southeast Asia has been plaguing the world for months. In November 2020, it was reported that the United States advised China to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The situation in Southeast Asia has been plaguing the world for months. In November 2020, it was reported that the United States advised China to avoid the use of violent military force against Taiwan. However, this has not seemed to have an impact on China’s actions, as they have looked towards the annexation of Taiwan. Many countries have expressed their opinions over this issue, mainly stating that they would prefer to have all actions remain peaceful.</p>



<p>“We strongly believe in adhering to the desires of both the United States and China through diplomatic measures that ease tension in the region,” the representative of the Philippines said.&nbsp;</p>



<p>For the past decade, the South China Sea crisis has been one of major discussions in the global trade market.&nbsp; The South China Sea dispute involves both the island and maritime claims by everlasting sovereign states within the region, namely Brunei, The People’s Republic of China, The Republic of China, Indonesia, Malaysia, Vietnam, and the Philippines. An estimated $3.37 trillion worth of global trade passes through the South China Sea annually. This accounts for a third of the global maritime trade. 80 percent of China’s energy imports and 39.5 percent of China’s total trade passes through the South China Sea.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The main conflict, the South China Sea crisis, has caused the nation of the Philippines much political and economic stress,” the representative from the Philippines also said.</p>



<p>Various nations, including the Philippines, have endured the great burden that tensions between China and the United States have created.&nbsp; While it seems as if there is no end in sight, multiple representatives have come together to discuss potential solutions to this pertinent problem.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“A main source of tension between the United States and China stems from trade disputes.&nbsp; Therefore, interjecting as the ASEAN to promote a joint trade force can be one of the many possible options,” the representative from the Philippines also said.</p>



<p>While China and the United States press on with their own agendas, nations across the world are suffering and hoping for a solution.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">90</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
