<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>United Nations General Assembly (1962) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/historical-committees/united-nations-general-assembly-1962/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:54:44 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>What, if any, Roles can Women Play in Society?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/what-if-any-roles-can-women-play-in-society/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 1962, the role of women in society is becoming more important. It is becoming more than just cooking, cleaning, and watching the children. The]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In 1962, the role of women in society is becoming more important. It is becoming more than just cooking, cleaning, and watching the children. The role that they can play in society is now more important than it has been before. </p>



<p>Hon. Orville Freeman mentions how women can play a significant role in the Cold War between America and Cuba. We have men who are standing with women to want to help them become more active in American society. Working with other powerful women and men can help everyone achieve a common goal that they want, which is for women to have more roles within society. </p>



<p>As a group, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women are working to see if they can introduce more women into the medical field, as well as the serving in the war if they so please. This would allow more empowerment within women, allowing them to be more confident to share their ideas; a critical perspective when considering the development of America. </p>



<p>Freeman also mentioned in an interview, “We believe that providing loans to women in entrepreneurship would enhance network and collaboration between women and those collaborations could be channeled into civic duties.”</p>



<p>Providing loans to allow women to be able to experience different professions will allow them to want to be more active in society. This is important because whether or not you need people to be more active in society, if they are not willing to do it, less people will want to be active in society. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Decolonization: What nations think</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/decolonization-what-nations-think/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Colin Brady, Izvestia]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 20:30:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=212</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the United Nations General Assembly, several delegates provided their input for decolonization. The representative for the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the United Nations General Assembly, several delegates provided their input for decolonization. The representative for the United Kingdom of Great Britain and Northern Ireland, Ethiopia, and Gabon all spoke. Beginning with the United Kingdom, the delegate spoke happily about their successes in decolonizing their once massive empire. Over three dozen countries have been decolonized as a result of the efforts of the United Kingdom. Finally the delegate had nothing but nice things to say about decolonization and spoke very highly of it.</p>



<p>Next a delegate from Ethiopia gave a speech. The Ethiopian delegate did not speak kindly of colonialism as it was once a colonial subject of Italy. It was only a little over 20 years ago that Ethiopians were under the thumb of Europeans. The delegate also spoke of how Ethiopia still grapples with the aftermath of being colonized by a foreign power.</p>



<p>The Gabonese delegate similarly had harsh thoughts on colonization. The delegate believed colonization slowed down the development of countries. He also said that these formerly colonized nations were often caught in proxy wars by major world powers. He also specified how entire regions can be destabilized by the selfish act of colonialism. The emotion and sincerity in the voice of this delegate was very clear. Finally, the delegate spoke about how a peaceful transition of power was necessary for a peaceful and successful state. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="757" height="785" src="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/IMG_1357.png" alt="" class="wp-image-268" srcset="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/IMG_1357.png 757w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/IMG_1357-289x300.png 289w" sizes="(max-width: 757px) 100vw, 757px" /></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Liveblog (Historical)</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/friday-liveblog-historical/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael McCarthy, Deputy USG for Media]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China is in Ashes</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/07/china-is-in-ashes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ari Ramjit, Pan African News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 05:01:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=110</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Climate change has been a long-lived issue of the global community. As the world&#8217;s economies develop, climate change has only advanced. The effects of climate]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Climate change has been a long-lived issue of the global community. As the world&#8217;s economies develop, climate change has only advanced. The effects of climate change are more visible than ever before with an increase in tropical storms, droughts, forest fires, and the acceleration of rising sea levels. It is now accepted that the only possible way to combat climate change is through a multifaceted approach of reduced emissions, carbon capture, carbon offset, and many more.</p>



<p>According to a delegate in the UN General Assembly, “China is currently working on achieving those goals of sustainability, and is on a good track to do so. Carbon emissions should peak by 2025, five years ahead of the original goal, 2030. China is achieving these goals by increasing solar and wind power generation capacity by 500  gigawatts, creating and investing in further electric vehicles, focusing on energy use in irrigation and establishing a quality emissions counting system for corporate companies. China is solving this climate crisis in a fast and efficient way.”</p>



<p>China produces about 30 percent of total emissions, more than the United States, the European Union and India combined, according to Global Carbon Budget 2022. China’s emissions grew by 10 percent year-on-year during the second quarter of this year – putting it on course to beat its previous record of 11.47 billion metric tonnes in 2021, according to data compiled by Carbon Brief, a United Kingdom-based website focused on climate policy.</p>



<p>“China will continue working towards these goals, and is going to continue to push to find safe alternatives to fossil fuels, and to implement further regulations on the matter. China is also looking into purchasing an area of land, such as the national parks in the United states, to reserve to combat any carbon dioxide emissions. In the future, China suggests other countries follow their lead. China would be pleased to aid any countries, particularly underdeveloped countries, that are also fighting for a cleaner world.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
