<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/2021/author/mjeleniewski/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 02:09:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>“Israel is like Simba,” from the Disney classic, Lion King</title>
		<link>/2021/israel-is-like-simba-from-the-disney-classic-lion-king/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 02:09:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=317</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Israeli cabinet officials make comical statements comparing the Iranian conflict to the events from a Disney movie during a press conference, Security Council and Arab]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">Israeli cabinet officials make comical statements comparing the Iranian conflict to the events from a Disney movie during a press conference, Security Council and Arab League come to major decisions</p>



<p>The United Nations Security Council has found itself scattered and unsure of which topic it should handle first, while the Iranian conflict and Korean Peninsula Conflict begin to reach a climax of sorts. The committee is pretty evenly split, with representatives from countries such as the United Kingdom and South Africa pushing for a focus on North Korea, commenting on concerns over a civil war with the involvement of nuclear weaponry, similar to the situation being seen on an international scale involving Iran. Other representatives feared the growth of Iranian nuclear weaponry, particularly the representative of Russia expressing their belief to the committee that Iran deserves to have “an olive branch” extended to them, saying that they are acting out of fear of the United States.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The representative of the United States then put their foot down, stating that their stance is firm: providing barriers in the case of an increasing aggression from the likes of Iran is insanely important during this crisis, and the US would be forced to take more severe action if Iran refuses to stop nuclearization efforts.</p>



<p>At this point, the Security Council barred the committee from all press, effectively silencing Fox News and keeping the public in the dark from future proceedings. Luckily, reporters have had the great opportunity to speak with an insider representative who wishes to be kept anonymous. They informed us that the Security Council passed a resolution that entailed the removal of U.N. sanctions and trade embargos–however, “all U.S. sanctions against Iran related to alleged human rights abuses, missiles, and support for terrorism are not affected by the agreement and will remain in place.” On top of this, the Security Council pledges to not interfere with the upcoming Iranian election.</p>



<p>After gaining this information, reporters ventured to listen in on the debate happening in the Arab League, while they also discussed the passing of two working papers on the table. It seems that the room is split into two blocs, one that gives prominence to demolishing western influence, spreading information into Asia that “glorifies Iran and islamic nations” and “demonizes Israel”, and the unification of Arabic states–the other wishing to work alongside the United States and Israel in possible peace negotiations (a possible rejoining of the JCPOA on Iran and the United States’ part), helping Iran continue a civilian nuclear program while condemning the development of nuclear weapons, and limiting the activities of Iranian nuclear activities (bimonthly surprise inspections of nuclear power plants, limiting uranium enrichment, dismantlement of excess centrifuges). The representative of Palestine went as far as to compare Israel to the “creation of the devil”. Anonymous sources leaked that a resolution paper passed, that of the bloc focusing on the dissemination of propaganda and demonizing Israel.</p>



<p>Fox News worries of upcoming updates regarding this plan, and hopes that this does not go unnoticed. The anonymous source also voices their displeasure with the fact that the paper passed “gives money to terrorists in our countries.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Finally, reporters had the great pleasure of being able to attend a press conference held by the Cabinet of Israel, in which they gave the press important messages to share with its allies and Iran. “Israel has tried to negotiate with Iran, Iran has threatened us numerous times. We will not tolerate these threats,” they told us. Members of the cabinet went on to compare the Ayatollah of Iran to the infamous Disney villain, Scar–from the Lion King–and pointed out similarities between the nation of Israel and the character of Simba the lion. This person proceeded to say that they will team up with a respective “Timon and Pumba”, that being the United States and Saudi Arabia, in preparing defenses against Iran if they were to strike first. “Though we hope there will be no war, we are prepared for one. We have exhausted all of our diplomatic solutions, we have a fear that the Iranian government might strike us,” members of the cabinet warned, and told the press that they want to make sure that the Security Council is aware that Israel will see any “progressive moves from Iran” as inciting violence.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">317</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chaos Erupts Between Iran and the World After Successful Nuclear Bomb Test</title>
		<link>/2021/chaos-erupts-between-iran-and-the-world-after-successful-nuclear-bomb-test/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 23:02:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arab League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=253</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a summit held between Iranian officials and many other international officials, controversy and anger caused the room to explode–similarly to Iran’s nuclear bombs. BREAKING:]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:13px">After a summit held between Iranian officials and many other international officials, controversy and anger caused the room to explode–similarly to Iran’s nuclear bombs.</p>



<p>BREAKING: Iranian warships sighted to be positioned in the Strait of Hormuz blocking traffic, and has led to the dissemination of shocking information–Iran is speculated to be two weeks away from producing a bomb, sending the world into panicked and tense debate following this act of aggression.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Arab League began to discuss rumors of uranium enrichment occurring within Iran, stating that if they were to follow historical events, it was highly likely for this to be happening. Many representatives wanted to wait for complete and concrete evidence before jumping to conclusions or taking actions, and denounced the sightings of warships to simply be a western plot to sow seeds of disinformation and instability. The representative of Kuwait stated, “Yes, there were sightings of Iranian ships around straits blocking traffic. It is NOT confirmed if these ships are troops yet, however. It is a very delicate solution, but many countries see it as an opportunity for Westerners to divide the Middle East and others believe these reports are an Iranian calculated move.” In agreement, the representative of Palestine told the committee to “look at every word that comes out of a westerner’s mouth with a reasonable amount of doubt”.</p>



<p>While these discussions continued, and tensions only rose, news broke out of a successful Iranian nuclear bomb test, leading to the formation of a summit between many of the parties involved–including members of the US cabinet, Saudi Arabian cabinet, Iranian cabinet, and Israeli cabinet. Despite many efforts to keep the press and international community in the dark, reporters were able to enter this summit and get live news coverage. Other parties that were not represented at the summit, such as the Russian Federation, sent someone to speak on behalf of their cabinet. The Minister of Defense told the press that As the Minister of Defense, I have been watching the tensions and movements in the Middle East carefully. Western Aggression makes me fear for the sovereignty of Iran, especially with recent troop movements. I hope that all affiliated countries are willing to work together to find a peaceful solution, and avoid bloodshed.”</p>



<p>Now, the summit that the press attended seemed to contradict this wish for peace entirely.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Upon entering the room, the discussion seemed to place a heavy focus on supervision of nuclear programs as to ensure that nuclear weaponry isn’t being created, and that Iran is true to its word on its comments of simply using nuclear power as energy to benefit its people. The Ayatollah of Iran and the Israeli Minister of Infrastructure were engaged in heated debate, trying to push for a negotiation to allow their respective nations the ability to supervise the other’s nuclear programs to ensure stability. The US Secretary of Transportation told the committee that actions taken by previous leadership–the Trump Administration–do not reflect the current opinion of the US cabinet, and they wish to come to a peaceful conclusion of the summit.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Soon, things took a turn for the absolute WORST. A member of the summit made a public comment on the presence of the press in the room, causing multiple people to express discontentment and confusion as to why the press was even in the room. To this, the Ayatollah responded: “I invited the press: time and time again, the international community hasn’t allowed true transparency. It’s time for that to happen.” Debate continued as per usual, until a member of the press asked the members of the summit if they were aware of the recent nuclear bomb test perpetrated by Iran. This caused the entire room to fall into chaos and dismay, a large uproar occurring at the Ayatollah’s only response: “The west will finally learn the true power of Iran. Let’s go,” and sudden departure.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The press heard several desperate and angered cries, “the Ayatollah is a lying dog!” “The Kingdom of Saudi Arabia will not stand for this!” “The US will seek immediate action!” And the representative of Israel: “We are prepared to enter Iran with our troops, nuclear weapons will stand. God bless us all.”</p>



<p>Nuclear war on the horizon? Fear bubbling up within our committee rooms? Can we ever find peace? The US cabinet left the press with a final, chilling message:&nbsp;</p>



<p>“Operation Ohio, then?”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">253</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Will Iran Face Punishment for NPT Violations</title>
		<link>/2021/will-iran-face-punishment-for-npt-violations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 22:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arab League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=240</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Security Council and Arab League’s opinions heavily overlap during discussions of possible punishments or actions to be taken against Iran, the idea of sanctions]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:13px">The Security Council and Arab League’s opinions heavily overlap during discussions of possible punishments or actions to be taken against Iran, the idea of sanctions cause heavy controversy.</p>



<p>After exciting and taxing discussion and passage of a paper on the transfer of power after the death of Kim Jong Un, the Security Council transitioned into a new conversation on how to take action against Iran due to violations of the NPT as leaked in previous articles from Fox. Many cabinets and committee rooms have been simply talking about how they must take quick and dutiful action, but the Security Council has been extremely attentive to holding Iran accountable while ensuring the safety of the public.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Many interesting sentiments were thrown around by representatives, including a heavy focus on either the reinstatement of the JCPOA or the recreation of a similar plan. The Security Council hopes to take note of the downfalls of the JCPOA and change them for the better, and improve upon the parts that worked exemplary until various withdrawals. Another focus has also been placed on whether or not sanctions would be in order, or do more harm than good–a similar conversation to that of the Arab League. Members such as the representative of Germany stated that punishment and sanctions have the ability to be helpful in many cases, but they fear that Iran will not wish to rejoin the JCPOA or join any future plans if sanctions are too overbearing and harm the economy too much–“The delegation of Germany is greatly concerned by Iran’s nuclear activities and thinks it is important that we act immediately. To elaborate, we view the JCPOA played a vital role in suppressing Iran’s nuclear capabilities, and hopes to work with other countries to create a new version of that deal. Germany understands the U.S and Israel&#8217;s conflict with Iran, but our main priority is de-escalating the situation and maintaining peace.”</p>



<p>The Security Council seemed to want to express the prominence of the people in whatever solution that comes forth during committee, many representatives warning against further economic sanctions to avoid plunging the Iranian people into more suffering–almost completely echoing sentiments expressed throughout the Arab League committee, showing that perhaps our world isn’t so divided after all. Ideas for the creation of a new nuclear deal floated around, entailing the support of Iran’s nuclear energy development–yet condemning the development of nuclear weapons, such as “intercontinental ballistic missiles,” as quoted from the representative of South Africa. The bloc working on these ideas told the committee that it was very important to allow Iran a method of redemption through peaceful means, and allowing them to be able to express their viewpoints on the matter as to come to a peaceful solution. The Security Council urges the cabinet of Iran to bring a representative into this committee as to try for peace talks and negotiation, and expresses its discontentment for all efforts to infringe upon Iran’s national sovereignty.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The delegation of Russia’s representatives told the press that “it’s a very delicate situation–we must exercise our power with great restraint to accomplish our mission.” It is of utmost importance and international interest that the world can recognize the major security threat that a new nuclear state can bring.</p>



<p>The Press was able to venture into the Arab League after hearing rumors of propaganda plans, in order to “foster patriotism” within “the new age of the Arab League”. Stay tuned for a further in-depth analysis as information comes.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">240</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Proposed Propaganda Campaigns &#8211; How the Arab League Plans to Tackle the Iran Crisis</title>
		<link>/2021/proposed-propaganda-campaigns-how-the-arab-league-plans-to-tackle-the-iran-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:32:53 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arab League]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=219</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Arab League continues discussion of the Iranian crisis, leaking concerning information surrounding possible propaganda campaigns and other Middle Eastern countries developing nuclear weapons–following in]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:12px">The Arab League continues discussion of the Iranian crisis, leaking concerning information surrounding possible propaganda campaigns and other Middle Eastern countries developing nuclear weapons–following in Iran’s dangerous footsteps</p>



<p></p>



<p>The Arab League is up in arms about the extreme power imbalance within the Middle East, verbalizing their worries of economic instability within countries such as Lebanon and Iran! Many representatives are firmly against any plans of foreign–specifically western–involvement due to their “past of manipulation”, and an overall fear of major powers taking advantage of the salient resources found within the Middle East. Countries such as Iraq made their opinions clear that they do not wish to work with the United States, stating that “they are not afraid to bomb us,” and that the only way to stop Iran’s nuclear weapons development plans would be to remove these weapons–which is not a feasible solution, in many eyes. During discussions, representatives began to echo each other&#8217;s ideas and came to a common consensus: one nation should not be able to have total power over the Arab League. Comments from the representative of Libya bring a pressing issue to the table: should all of the members of the Arab League “have the ability to have nuclear [power/weapons]”?</p>



<p>As alluded to in a previous article written by Fox News, we were able to listen in on the discussion when a representative mentioned “the new Arab age”–as the press listened in further, the representative of Libya was happy to privately elaborate, sending a warning to the Iranian government: “The new Arab Ages is here! We must unite as one country fostering the great Arab Ideals. We understand the Iranian threat is large and thus we, the Arab League, have decided to keep a close inspection on the Iranian Nuclear Plan. If they do not meet our standard, we will cut diplomatic ties. With a united Arab League, we will come together as one to promote our corporation together. Conflict and tension will decrease severely and we will come together as a whole!”</p>



<p>Fox News reporters were sadly unable to listen into the entire conversations revolving various plans, but once we entered the room, we were able to hear a representative mention the usage of a possible propaganda campaign. The representative of Libya stated that “even if [they] don’t use propaganda, we need to [show and foster] patriotism&#8230;Many people here are against each other and we need to combine them.” The Arab League seems to be very focused at the moment on uniting in ideology and forming a unified body to fight against conflicts threatening the Arab world.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Of course, the mention of propaganda concerned the press–but Fox News is dedicated to avoiding biased information and jumping to conclusions, and reached out to members of the committee to expand on what exactly was meant by this comment. Luckily, we were able to get a few words from the representative of Palestine, who told Fox News that the plan mentioned was “essentially utilizing social media, chat rooms, and messaging boards to disseminate pro-Arab League and pro-Iranian viewpoints. Many citizens of foreign countries view the Arab League as breeding grounds for radicals and terrorists, and do not understand the plight of Arabs or the true state of politics in the Middle East. This plan would try to spread pro-Iranian views, such that both citizens and government figures of foreign nations are sympathetic to Iran, and understand the actions of the Arab League.”</p>



<p>Is this simply a tactic to foster patriotism within the Middle East and Arab community, and ensure that the viewpoints of these groups are heard–or is this a scheme to spread harmful propaganda and rhetoric to allow for Iran and the Middle East to gain support in their nuclear weapons development programs? A hopeful unification project, or an anti-western ploy to advance nuclear power?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Fox News is dedicated to continuing listening into these conversations to ensure safety and security. Stay Tuned.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">219</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>“A Gross Violation of What The UN Stands For!”</title>
		<link>/2021/a-gross-violation-of-what-the-un-stands-for/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 19:59:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[UN Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=197</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United Nations Security Council faces controversy and extreme conflict while discussing the rise of Kim Yo Jong upon the untimely death of Kim Jong-un,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4>The United Nations Security Council faces controversy and extreme conflict while discussing the rise of Kim Yo Jong upon the untimely death of Kim Jong-un, representatives speak argumentatively against proposed draft resolutions.</h4>



<p>Following the sudden and jarring death of North Korean leader Kim Jong-un, the United Nations Security Council found themselves in a very stressful–yet important–predicament. Reporters were able to hear various viewpoints from a vast array of representatives during their discussion of proposed draft resolutions. They decided to speak on how the Security Council would deal with the rise of Kim Yo-jong to power, and whether or not they felt inclined to interfere with political proceedings.</p>



<p>According to debate from a handful of speakers, the committee currently has two draft resolution papers on the floor–affectionately referred to as Resolution paper 1.1, and 1.2. The representative of Vietnam clarified the main differences between both pieces, telling committee that 1.1 focuses on “the need to retain peace,” while 1.2 places an emphasis onto the “need to find peace”–elaborating further that the writers of the draft paper 1.2 had a firm stance that peace does not currently exist in North Korea under the leadership of the Kim dynasty.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It was quickly made clear to the press that the five permanent members of the Security Council–China, France, Russia, the United Kingdom, the United States–were in great support of passing the draft resolution 1.1, as per comments made by the United Kingdom’s representative in a private interview, stating that: “We believe that the best solution to avoid conflict is to recognize Kim Yo-jung as leader and begin negotiations with the new government.” Other P5 nations’ representatives expressed contentment with the 1.1 draft resolution, while the delegation of France made further comments expressing their discontentment with the second draft resolution on the table. “1.1 is a comprehensive plan that will keep peace in the DPRK and hopefully bring them to the table. 1.2 attempts to take over the DPRK, which is highly inappropriate and uncalled for. South Africa [the main writer of said draft resolution] is way out of line in many ways.”</p>



<p>The representative from Russia even went as far as to call the entire draft resolution a “gross violation of everything that the UN stands for,” denouncing 1.2 as nothing more than a warmongering misuse of the Security Council’s power.</p>



<p>Due to such a large controversy, Fox hoped to be able to get a few words from the main writer of the 1.2 draft resolution, South Africa. “South Africa, Tunisia and Vietnam have been working together to ensure the rights of man are upheld at any cost. We are hoping the UN will start doing something and help the people of North Korea instead of letting the people of North Korea suffer,” the representative told the press.</p>



<p>While the Security Council closed the room to press during voting procedure, Fox News was able to gain leaks from a representative that wished to remain anonymous in this article as to avoid controversy. This representative told reporters that Draft Resolution 1.1 passed with only 3 representatives voting no, and Draft Resolution 1.2 ended up failing and not going into motion. Perhaps this is for the best, as the draft resolution stated that it wished to force elections in the name of “sovereignty.”</p>



<p>Specific plans that are now going to be put into actions include: incentivizing nonproliferation in North Korea, allowing for the stabilization of the nation under Kim Yo Jong, cohesive contingency plans in the case of civil conflict, and investigating the sudden death of Kim Jong Un.</p>



<p>After all of this distressful debate, the public and Fox News both still worry about the rising conflict of Iran and its nuclear developments–and it seems that many members of the Security Council agree with this sentiment, hoping to begin drafting resolutions to alleviate the situation. The representative of France hopes that “an Iranian representative [could] join us and discuss reducing sanctions and limiting nuclear weapons–but not nuclear power.”</p>



<p>Fox News stands in support of the great work that the representative from the United States is performing in this committee, and they told the press that “the US is willing to take any means necessary to ensure the safety of Israel, Saudi Arabia, and the Strait of Hormuz. Whether it be through the reintroduction of the Iran Deal or other programs.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>While cabinets remained closed, the press was able to obtain a leak from the Israeli cabinet surrounding Iran and the nuclear weaponry crisis. The full statement reads as follows: “Israel desires to maintain peace throughout the entire middle east, but recently the international intelligence community and press has stated that Iran is likely developing new Nuclear weapons. We desire to come to a diplomatic solution and craft new treaties with the United States and Iran and will remain strictly defensive, but if the situation presents itself we are prepared to defend our nation”</p>



<p>While this committee discusses the up-and-coming situation regarding Iran, we hope that they can come to peaceful negotiations surrounding sanctions–to ensure the safety of the world, and to avoid a third world war; this time, an all out nuclear one. Stay Tuned.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">197</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Can The Middle East Work Toward Peace?</title>
		<link>/2021/can-the-middle-east-work-toward-peace/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 18:00:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Arab League]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=155</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[An in-depth look into the Arab League’s response to Iran’s violation of the Non-Proliferation Treaty and whether or not they will lift sanctions based on]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-center">An in-depth look into the Arab League’s response to Iran’s violation of the Non-Proliferation Treaty and whether or not they will lift sanctions based on the answer–nuclear war on the horizon?</p>



<p>During its time searching for a broader reach of perspectives on the current Iranian nuclear crisis, Fox News was able to get an inside look into the discussions of the Arab League. After being able to interview members of the Iranian cabinet, Fox News was surprised at the lack of information dissemination that was occurring within the Arab League.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The representative of Iraq from the Arab League asked the committee what acts that Iran was being punished for, “[these] nuclear issues are purely speculation”, and implored for the committee room to lift sanctions on Iran out of concern for its citizens. While the Iranian cabinet very openly discussed its plans for nuclear development and hopes to become a new worldwide nuclear power, the nations represented in the Arab League seemed in the dark on these topics, referring to Iran’s nuclear plans as “merely speculation”, and rumors–despite the Iranian Ayatollah stating that they “will lead Iran into nuclear power”. Fox hopes that this dissemination of new information publicly will help further discussions from committees tackling these dire conflicts.&nbsp;</p>



<p>A big topic of interest during the Arab League’s conversation on how it plans to deal with Iran and its violation of the Non-Proliferation Treaty (NPT) was the involvement of western and first-world countries. Representatives of countries such as Palestine and Kuwait voiced concerns about western countries, specifically on how they feared that the United States only wishes to manipulate Middle Eastern countries to their advantage and push the region into further economic instability. However, members of committees such as the representative of Somalia countered these concerns by proposing that the Arab League <em>needed </em>to have “first-world countries involved”, due to the fact that many nations involved within these conflicts simply do not have the money or resources to adequately combat the issues discussed.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The representatives of the Arab League also discussed sanctions on Iran, and whether they should increase them, decrease them, or keep them at the exact level that they remain currently. Representatives have made the stances clear–Iraq, Palestine, Libya, and Kuwait are adamantly against sanctions in any way shape or form against Iran, worrying of bringing harm upon the citizens rather than the intended target: the Iranian government. “Many countries in the arab league are [considered] important trading partners with Iran, and we can’t risk economic instability due to a vendetta the US has against them,” the representative of Kuwait said. The debate seemed to reach a common consensus at its conclusion: Sanctions against Iran are far too harmful to the public, and defeat its purpose of punishment toward the government. Despite this, a few representatives, such as the delegate from Libya wish to continue economic sanctions due to violation of the NPT. We hope that this kind of violation does not go unnoticed within this committee</p>



<p>The representative from Palestine left Fox News with a message condemning the actions perpetrated by the United States and western nations, pledging allegiance to Iran during this conflict: “We believe that Iran is being punished with economic sanctions for doing what the United States does on a regular basis. The United States has thousands of nuclear weapons, so many that it could destroy the entirety of the Middle East without suffering a major loss in their nuclear stock. Iran’s response, building a nuclear weapon, is simply the act of a nation desperate for survival in the face of an overwhelming foe. The committee is currently split on how to tackle the Iranian nuclear affair, a majority wishes to side against Iran. However, a smaller minority including myself, Iraq, and Mauritania wish to back Iran against the forces of America and Israel.”</p>



<p>Fox News will remain actively seized in the matter, and will continue to provide up-to-date information based off of incoming debate, and is looking forward to an insider interview with the representative of Lebanon. Stay Tuned.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">155</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>“We have our new weapon in case things go wrong,” rumors on Iranian nuclear weaponry confirmed</title>
		<link>/2021/we-have-our-new-weapon-in-case-things-go-wrong-rumors-on-iranian-nuclear-weaponry-confirmed-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:39:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=152</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Reporters have been able to sit in on various conversations held by Iranian officials during their discussions of outgoing rumors and dire conflicts. These discussions]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Reporters have been able to sit in on various conversations held by Iranian officials during their discussions of outgoing rumors and dire conflicts. These discussions included possible negotiations with the United States over Iran’s discontentment regarding sanctions, as well as rumored nuclear power. On top of this, we were even able to get direct quotes from highly important figures in the Iranian decision making process. Throughout these conversations, these figures confirmed that Iran is working on the creation of nuclear weaponry in response to sanctions and tensions with the U.S.</p>



<p>There have been two polarizing sentiments floating around the room since the committee gathered by the Iranian Ayatollah began–one emphasizing peace and nonviolent negotiation with the United States, and one with plans for manipulation, terror, and using nuclear power to spark fear into the world’s eyes. It is of utmost importance to not jump to conclusions, and hope for the best in these kinds of situations.</p>



<p>Members of the committee such as the Minister of Science and Research, Minister of Defense and Armed Forces, and the Minister of Intelligence began echoing each other in their attitudes, particularly stating that they wish to avoid a war of any kind through de-escalation tactics. Other ministers, however, are on record stating contradictory beliefs. The Minister of Petroleum stated that “We will not give into [Donald Trump’s] tactics” referring&nbsp; to sanctions and withdrawal from the JCPOA (Joint Comprehensive Plan of Action), commonly known as the Iran Nuclear Deal.</p>



<p>“[We should] want to use Biden’s policy to our advantage to complete our nuclear [plans],” the minister added.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Minister of Foreign Affairs, in response, agreed: “They crippled our GDP [when leaving the JCPOA]&#8230;made us an economic floor for the world to walk on.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Other worrying quotes include the Ambassador to Pakistan’s comment, stating that “we have our new weapon in case things go wrong”, in regards to negotiations against the sanctions the United States has placed on Iran.</p>



<p>With all of this worrying and colorful language occurring in this committee, does the worldwide public have an oncoming nuclear conflict to fear? Based on quotes from the Ministers of Defense and Armed Forces, and Intelligence, both prominent figures in the decision making process and room, we are led to believe and desperately hope not.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Minister of Defense and Armed Forces stated, “We have the supplies, technology, and forces to successfully use our nuclear weapons if necessary, but we’d rather sit down and converse about this ongoing conflict. We’re asking that under the jurisdiction of the Biden Administration, they reinstate their partaking in the JCPOA, this way, unfair sanctions can not be imposed. We’d also appreciate transparency, deceiving us will only lead to extreme conflict. The United Nations is committed to promoting and actively helping nations reconcile after political, social, economic turmoil, and because the damage that Donald Trump created and left behind is so profound, we must move forward with restoring transparency with the United States to benefit us all.”</p>



<p>The Minister of Intelligence left Fox News with this statement: “We would like the United States to know that their actions will not be forgotten, but we can work together to lift their cruel sanctions placed on our shoulders. We would also like to mention that we are aiming for peace; not war.”</p>



<p>Fox News will be dedicated to continuing an in-depth and live analysis on the topics at hand, and will be reporting all pertinent information as soon as possible. We hope that the information spread in this article will be able to encourage world leaders to come to peaceful agreements, rather than the suggestions from the Iranian Minister of Energy to “manipulate the weak power of the United States”. Stay Tuned.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">152</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saudi Arabian Council of Ministers to Discuss Iranian Nuclear Developments</title>
		<link>/2021/saudi-arabian-council-of-ministers-to-discuss-iranian-nuclear-developments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 03:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Saudi Arabia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=92</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.N. experts warn of the Iranian government’s developments in nuclear technology, ‘potentially leading them to obtain weapons-grade fissile material by mid to late February’, report]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4>U.N. experts warn of the Iranian government’s developments in nuclear technology, ‘potentially leading them to obtain weapons-grade fissile material by mid to late February’, report says.</h4>



<p>Highly surprising and important intelligence was recently publicized by the Saudi Arabian General Intelligence Presidency (GIP)–the Iranian government is rumored to be continuing its developments on nuclear technology. Per the report, this could  “lead them to obtaining weapons-grade fissile material by mid to late February”. </p>



<p>Due to existing tension between Iran and the rest of the world, U.N. experts have stated finding heavy evidence that <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/un-experts-evidence-iran-houthi-rebels-yemen">Iran has sent weapons to Houthi rebels in war-torn Yemen</a>. They have also found a list of weapons that include anti-tank guided missiles, sniper rifles, and RPB launchers–all of the aforementioned weaponry being adorned with trademark Iranian markings/labels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During President Trump’s time in office, his administration was adamant to warn the public of Iran’s increasing likelihood to disrupt the stability of the Middle East through arms trade.&nbsp; Former Secretary of State, Mike Pompeo, even went as far as to impose sanctions on the Houthi rebels specifically, identifying them as a foreign terrorist organization (FTO). In response, the Trump Administration pushed for the implementation of more sanctions, due to the impending expiration of 2015 sanctions, as well as a broader arms embargo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the Biden Administration, upon taking office, has suspended many of the sanctions that were imposed to battle against previously mentioned issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Saudi Arabian officials as well as Middle Eastern officials worry about the increasing tension and the consequences it can have on the well being of the entire region as a whole, if these weapons become a reality. What will the Saudi Arabian government do about these developments?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Salamin bin Abdulaziz Al Saud has decided to take action against spreading rumors by arranging for a meeting between the Council of Ministers of Saudi Arabia, who will be tasked with tackling these problems of dire importance. Fox News is dedicated to ensuring that the public is kept up-to-date with major proceedings regarding this cabinet–in relation to current worldwide problems.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">92</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
