<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>General Dynamics Corporation &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/2021/category/general-dynamics-corporation/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 01:36:17 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>General Dynamics wants to Monopolize Through Blackmail, Bombings, and Confrontations about Adultery</title>
		<link>/2021/general-dynamics-wants-to-monopolize-through-blackmail-bombings-and-confrontations-about-adultery/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 19:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Dynamics Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=369</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mixed discussions taking place in General Dynamics’s boardroom paint a picture of a company preparing for drastic action, with disregard for the consequences or a]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Mixed discussions taking place in General Dynamics’s boardroom paint a picture of a company preparing for drastic action, with disregard for the consequences or a great deal of common sense. “Back to blackmailing the DOD…” stated a General Dynamics executive, before discussions commenced regarding supplying arms to Russia. Executives also suggested providing pizza, free of charge and topped with green peas, to the world, although reasonable suspicion exists that this was a press stunt in order to disguise their real, much more sinister ideas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Suggestions put forth by the board included sabotaging Lockheed Martin by framing them for bombings, blackmailing opposing executives, bombing the headquarters of competitive companies, and telling foreign executives “Your wife cheated on you!” It was not made clear the exact purposes of these actions, but it’s glaringly obvious that the rest of the world is no match for the might of General Dynamics and its pizza-enthusiast executive board.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">369</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>General Dynamics Insider Publicly Reaches Out to Belarus</title>
		<link>/2021/general-dynamics-insider-publicly-reaches-out-to-belarus/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Associated Press Wire]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:19:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[AP Wire]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Dynamics Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2021/?p=284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Dear General Major General Viktor Khrenin, Minister of Defense of Belarurs,Gulfstream feels for you and your grieving country at this time. However, we realize your]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Dear General Major General Viktor Khrenin, Minister of Defense of Belarurs,<br>Gulfstream feels for you and your grieving country at this time. However, we realize your need of protection during these difficult times of forming yopur Democracy. If you are interested, Gulfstream would like to provide aircrafts for your military. Payment programs are available. If you are interested like me know and we can work put further details. -VP/CFO of Gulfstream</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">284</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
