<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>The Janes &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/the-janes/feed/?simply_static_page=1212" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:31:42 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>After The Janes Press Conference Fiasco, Members Speak Out</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/after-the-janes-press-conference-fiasco-members-speak-out/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Olivya Lang, MTV]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 05 Feb 2023 06:16:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[The Janes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1664</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As you all have heard, something huge has happened in the Janes. During the press conference, an argument ensured between two members, and the press]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As you all have heard, something huge has happened in the Janes. During the press conference, an argument ensured between two members, and the press heard something about getting arrested. Here&#8217;s the video of the argument.</p>



<p></p>



<p>A group has split apart from the Janes. The organization has been spilt into one group of the 7 original members &#8220;The Janes&#8221; and The other three members are now a part of an unknown organization called &#8220;The Does&#8221;. </p>



<p>MTV was privileged to get a statement from two members of &#8220;The Janes&#8221;, The Director of Public Policy and the Director of Communications. </p>



<p>&#8220;We are the Janes collective. A collective is founded on togetherness. the Janes are incredibly hurt and betrayed by the treason of former Janes&#8217; member Gabriela Vasquez AKA Gabby. One of the most discussed values the Janes value is loyalty. A person seeking abortion needs to trust the abortion clinic and clinician. Thus we cannot support Gabriela, and we will be investigating the situation and plan to sue her. Following Gabriela, the Lead Activist is the Directory of Community Relations and the Founder.&#8221;</p>



<p>On the other hand, anonymous source told MTV that they do not plan to follow through with the legal actions presented by the Directors of Public Policy and Communications. </p>



<p>There was a second leak relating to the Janes partnership with ExxonMobil. ExxonMobil gave &#8220;The Janes&#8221; $500K for funds. What they don&#8217;t know is that the money is being laundered to the underground group &#8220;The Does&#8221;, and they are using this money to do more embezzlement. This is why &#8220;The Janes&#8221; was split in the first place. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Janes aim social media campaign to grow movement</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/janes-aim-social-media-campaign-to-grow-movement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 03:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Janes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Janes, a nonprofit group that aims to promote equitable access to abortion, have been organizing a social media campaign to protect women’s right to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Janes, a nonprofit group that aims to promote equitable access to abortion, have been organizing a social media campaign to protect women’s right to choose. Citing concerns over repression of reproductive rights in an era where abortion is not protected federally, the Janes have been working to make sure that right is given.</p>



<p>The founder of the Janes explained her concerns with the government’s lack of progress in expanding abortion access. “The U.S. has failed to protect women’s rights,” she said. “That’s why we’re doing all that we can to protect abortion access.”</p>



<p>The organization is beginning with establishing social media accounts and leading assemblies and community events. “We’d like to use any form of social media,” said the Founder. “TikTok, Instagram, maybe even LinkedIn to recruit nurses and gynecologists.”</p>



<p>TikTok in particular has elicited support amongst Janes. Because Gen Z is statistically the most active cohort on TikTok, many of the leaders believe raising awareness on the platform will educate teens. “As an adult, I’ve spent 13 hours on TikTok sometimes,” said co-founder Kendra Winter. “So if we make videos targeted at kids, we’ll be able to reach them efficiently.”</p>



<p>For the founder, expanding access to abortion through social media is not a pipe dream, it is an integral part of American democracy. “The best way to reform democracy is to work within it,” she said. “Through social media, we can encourage citizens to vote and take action to make sure their rights are protected.”</p>



<p>The Janes have also explored connecting with local press and other organizations to raise awareness of abortion rights. </p>



<p>“While we aim to use social media to build a national platform, we want to stay local to Chicago on the ground for now,” the founder explained. The Director of Community Relations also cited Gen Z for Change as a potential organization to collaborate with.</p>



<p>The Janes chair admits her lofty goals, stating that “it’s going to be hard to organize a benefit concert or get Taylor Swift to speak out.” However, the group, which currently has under 100 volunteers and workers but over 20,000 followers, aims to grow on social media even more. “We can use hashtags like #WeAreJane,” said the director of communications. “That way, we’ll expand our reach to women nationwide.</p>



<p>The founder is confident that using social media will maintain American democratic values. “The government is doing what it can,” she said. “But if we use social media to build a movement, we’ll actually be a bigger part of the government and expand the people’s will.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Janes: A True Advocate of Women&#8217;s Rights</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/the-janes-a-true-advocate-of-womens-rights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 02:01:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Janes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1229</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Janes is an organization founded in the 60s the as an &#8220;underground abortion network to bring abortions back to give people access to these]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="442" height="593" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-03-7.59.43-PM.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1239" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-03-7.59.43-PM.png 442w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-03-7.59.43-PM-224x300.png 224w" sizes="(max-width: 442px) 100vw, 442px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">The Janes Lead Activist at the Protest</figcaption></figure>



<p>The Janes is an organization founded in the 60s the as an &#8220;underground abortion network to bring abortions back to give people access to these vital lifesaving services for people in Illinois and Chicago for those who need it,&#8221; the Lead Activist of the Janes said. Today the Janes peacefully protested outside of the White House to get the attention of President Biden. &#8220;The White House has refused to meet with the janes so we will force them to listen” the Co-Founder of the Janes reported. The Biden administration hasn&#8217;t done enough and the Janes can&#8217;t communicate with the cabinet about increasing rights to abortion and codifying law. The U.S. cabinet refuses to meet with the Janes.</p>



<p><br>The Janes emphasizes that ever since the fall of Roe v. Wade there has been extremely limited access to abortion. The Janes&#8217; protest aims to &#8220;create true change for people with uterus’ across the nation&#8221; the Founder of the Janes said. The Janes has 2 demands for the U.S. government 1) Childcare, transportation, education, and paid leave and 2) a Public call upon states to publicly fund abortion services. The protest is using #WeAreJane to share abortion stories and document the protests and invites members of the public to use the hashtag. The rally featured posters with quotes &#8220;We Must be Heard,&#8221; &#8220;Pro-Life is a Lie!&#8221; and &#8220;My Body My Choice!&#8221;</p>



<p><br>It is now up to the cabinet to decide whether they will support the Janes&#8217; demands or hold firm with the lack of support for abortion rights.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
