<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Hongtao Hu, The Sun &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/author/hhu/feed/?simply_static_page=1300" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:31:35 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Iran accused of misconduct in Iran-Iraq War</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/iran-accused-of-misconduct-in-iran-iraq-war/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hongtao Hu, The Sun]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 23:05:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of Iraq (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1708</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Hot off of accusations that its ally Syria is engaging in chemical warfare, the USSR is pressuring Iran to cede the territories of Golestan, North]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full"><img decoding="async" width="600" height="396" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/President_Ali_Khamenei_in_Iran-Iraq_War.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-1709" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/President_Ali_Khamenei_in_Iran-Iraq_War.jpg 600w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/President_Ali_Khamenei_in_Iran-Iraq_War-300x198.jpg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 600px) 100vw, 600px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">President Ali Khamenei visiting soldiers during the Iran-Iraq War. (Source: Wikipedia Commons)</figcaption></figure>



<p>Hot off of accusations that its ally Syria is engaging in chemical warfare, the USSR is pressuring Iran to cede the territories of Golestan, North Khorasan, and Razavo Khorasan due to claims of civilian killings.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The USSR has accused Iran of killing USSR civilians in its northeastern provinces, stating that Iran has “endangered and already killed thousands of innocent civilians” in the provinces of Golestan, North Khorasan, and Razavi Khorasan, and thus requests to occupy said provinces.</p>



<p>It is important to note that the war between Iraq and Iran is occurring along the western border of Iran, with Iraq fighting a 2-front war between Syria to the west and Iran to the east.&nbsp;</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh3.googleusercontent.com/8Q0ML2L8YV6PJB1ns9_ei-8aPrTmBsafGE9ML_2u1fv03Mq-BtncbE6qFcvsGDmCHG8JfOsR1kmmi_F-u5DnUN3JpT8otN5tMXuctYK7ArI4RmvZj5pQ0F_nGrYKmNkXb-zA7ZFSjZ3gY0MRhJDG6Q0" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Iran has asserted that the war is occurring nowhere close to possible USSR civilians, claiming that the USSR is threatening Iran with military action.</p>



<p>The Iranian Minister of Petroleum states that “it seems like the USSR has the worst intentions for the Middle East” and is beginning to establish a demilitarized zone within the provinces, along with seeking diplomatic negotiations with the USSR.</p>



<p>The Minister of Petroleum is also requesting the international community to take notice, stressing that “we hope the international community and especially the U.S. can recognize the severity of the USSR’s deception and their threat at this moment.”</p>



<p>Additionally, the Iraqi cabinet has accused Iran’s ally Syria of using chemical warfare and thus violating the Geneva Convention during its incursion into the western borders of Iraq.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Minister of Foreign Affairs from Iraq calls upon the Arab League to take action against Iran, stating: “There’s a great importance that the Arab League applies trade sanctions against Iran so that the Iranian and Syrian treachery can near an end.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iran states that it’s currently looking into the accusations of chemical warfare and reconsidering its relationship with Syria, however, they are still allying with them.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>A house divided</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/a-house-divided/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hongtao Hu, The Sun]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 07:01:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of Iraq (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran-Iraq War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Sun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1358</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the Iran-Iraq war continuing for over a year, Iran, Iraq, and Russia are divided &#8212; not only against each other, but among themselves. However,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="819" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-1024x819.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-1359" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-1024x819.jpeg 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-300x240.jpeg 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D-768x615.jpeg 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/93A9C0BB-632B-49F6-A5F2-05D7634B1B9D.jpeg 1431w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>With the Iran-Iraq war continuing for over a year, Iran, Iraq, and Russia are divided &#8212; not only against each other, but among themselves.</p>



<p>However, one faction has joined forces: the USSR and Iraq.</p>



<p>While notorious for secrecy, The Sun has received an anonymous report about a meeting between the USSR and Iraq, where a member of the USSR cabinet was reportedly heard saying to Iraq: “our house is your house.” </p>



<p>However, the USSR is burdened with the loss of a member of its cabinet.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In this meeting, the USSR stated that the recently deceased Finance Minister of the USSR was discovered to be colluding with members of the Iranian cabinet.</p>



<p>Could the USSR have “disappeared” the Minister of Finance for political purposes? Is the USSR providing nuclear resources to Iraq? Only time will tell.</p>



<p>In other news, Iraq is experiencing internal turmoil along its southern border, incited by Ayatollah Khomeini’s words: “to our brothers in Iraq especially, I turn to you now. You know in your hearts that the mongrel demon-spawn of the greater Satan Saddam Hussein will never care for you…now it is time for you to be freed of your oppressor in accordance with the wishes of the Muslim people, and the true Sharia!”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Such words have invoked the “righteous” fervor of Iraqi citizens and have led to several civilian arrests in Iraq.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In response, the Ambassador to the United Nations for Iraq offered a “sneak peek” of a future directive to The Sun, hinting at creating literacy programs and actions to reduce hunger in the population.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In Iran, after discovering the news of a collaboration between the deceased Finance Minister of the USSR and a member of their cabinet, accusations went flying about a possible “traitor” in their midst.&nbsp;</p>



<p>With the Iran-Iraq war in the midst of its first year, both sides of the conflict are experiencing similar troubles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Iran Gains New Allies in Iran-Iraq War</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/iran-gains-new-allies-in-iran-iraq-war/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hongtao Hu, The Sun]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 01:44:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of Iraq (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[League of Arab States (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Iran-Iraq War]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Sun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1223</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Recently,&#160; the Iranian Cabinet has gained additional allies in the Iran-Iraq war, countering the support the Arab League provides to Iraq’s military, of which appears]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh4.googleusercontent.com/p4rOMIyh9qeN9oWDs5Ptr0KrPE1wXKpPFVXWIBHHB6-P8TiQYUCh26-3o__0GzTseJ-LXjMq3Umk858KdBmbVc-WeXjUxaKfz87UA_Jl9nCDltF9_AXNRkLBrGwKIuCdWivys5xZn_zzU2qRNYzxBhM" alt=""/></figure>



<p>Recently,&nbsp; the Iranian Cabinet has gained additional allies in the Iran-Iraq war, countering the support the Arab League provides to Iraq’s military, of which appears to be more divided than it may seem.</p>



<p>Iraq, as part of the Arab League, has long had resources to draw upon from its neighboring countries. Such support from the Arab League was demonstrated today, when Iraq’s Minister of Foreign Affairs delivered a rousing speech claiming that Iraq would achieve stability in the Middle East if it defeated Iran in the ongoing Iran-Iraq war. Conversely, the minister also warned of the consequences in the event of an Iranian victory: “If Iran wins this war, then it poses a threat to the entire Middle East”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>However, during a question and answer segment, detractors spoke up: the delegation from Libya questioned Iraq’s “aggressive” stance in the invasion of Iran, to which the Foreign Minister stated: “Iraq is the sword that protects the entire Middle East”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>It is important to note that Iran is not in the Arab League. However, this does not mean that Iran is without allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>In a recent interview The Sun conducted with The Minister of Petroleum in the Iran Cabinet, he stated that the Iranian Cabinet had written directives to ally with and buy weapons from Romania and North Yemen, adding: “When we are going to other countries, we are not going for some ideological basis that has been perpetuated by the Cold War”.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This is cooperated by a document The Sun obtained from the Iran Cabinet, where “R” stands for Romania and “NY” stands for North Yemen.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="1024" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-1024x1024.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-1227" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-1024x1024.jpeg 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-300x300.jpeg 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-150x150.jpeg 150w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-768x768.jpeg 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1-1536x1536.jpeg 1536w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/42548F41-C06D-4667-AD9B-410C1A6A1AA1.jpeg 1735w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p>What does this mean for Iraq? Well, we can turn to a correspondence the delegate for Iraq in the Arab League sent to their cabinet. This war will not only be a “war of attention” that the delegate most certainly misspelled, as both countries may turn to additional Western countries for aid, but also a “war of attrition” where evenly matched militaries reach a deadlock, where they each attempt to capture yards, not kilometers of territory. Even if the delegate for Iraq made a simple spelling error, this time, it’s important to listen to what he means, and<strong> </strong>what he says. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kurdish coalition attempts to overthrow Iraqi leadership</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/kurdish-coalition-attempts-to-overthrow-iraqi-leadership/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Hongtao Hu, The Sun]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:36:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of Iraq (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=832</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With the development of Iraqi Kurds joining an opposition front against the Baghdad government, Suddam Hussein’s attempts to ally with Kurds seems to fail to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With the development of Iraqi Kurds joining an opposition front against the Baghdad government, Suddam Hussein’s attempts to ally with Kurds seems to fail to extend to those living inside his borders. </p>



<p>Since the beginning of the Iran-Iraq War, Iraq’s government has tried to leverage the Kurdish factor against Iran, allying with and establishing a weapons supply route to the Kurdish Democratic Part of Iran (KDPI), located near the northern Iranian cities of Nowdesheh and Qasr-Shirin. Backed by Iraqi supplies and captured Iranian deposits, the KDPI attempted to establish “Kurdish Liberated Zones”, however, by the end of 1981, Iran pushed back against Iraqi forces in the northern front, subsuquently attacking the KDPI and squashing Hussein’s attempt to raise the Kurds as a potential threat against Iran.</p>



<p>Furthermore, the recent Iraqi coalition of dissident Ba’athists, breakaway Iraqi Army officers and Iraqi Shiites have a new ally: Iraqi Kurds. This coalition calls itself the Iraqi Front of Revolutionary, Islamic and National Forces, and has managed to execute a series of attacks from Rawanduz, 25 miles from the Iranian border to Amadiyah, lying near the Turkish border.</p>



<p>This insurgency group, supported by Syria and the Iranian Army, are further emboldened by the Iraqi Army’s waning control over northern Iraq, as forces have been transferred to other regions in order to support the war against Iran.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Other countries are cautious in their support for this new Kurdish movement: “We believe that the Kurdish people have the right to self-sovereignty, however, militant uprisings will only cause unnecessary bloodshed,” the representative from Australia said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
