<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/archive/2021/category/cabinet-of-the-peoples-republic-of-china/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:45:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>US-Russia standoff amidst internal scandal</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/us-russia-standoff-amidst-internal-scandal/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alexander Calabrese, The Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:45:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=349</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Two global superpowers, the United States of America and Russia, may be on the brink of potential military conflict in the small landlocked Eastern European]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Two global superpowers, the United States of America and Russia, may be on the brink of potential military conflict in the small landlocked Eastern European nation of Belarus. Since the assassination of Belarusian dictator Alexander Lukashenko a few days ago, a U.S.-backed democratic opposition government has come to power led by Svetlana Tikhanovskaya, but the state is still very much unstable. Russia has been conspicuously quiet on the matter in recent days but it believed to be preparing for war, albeit much more covertly. The U.S. is believed to be directly supplying the new government, and are also believed to be using modern tactics involving social media and internet memes to influence public opinion amongst the Belarusian people.</p>



<p>Reports early this morning suggest that the Department of Defense has acted in Belarus without the approval of the White House and Commander-in-Chief. A CIA insider reported that “the DOD lied about the presidential approval” which raises serious concerns regarding co-operation within the government. In a CIA memo revealed yesterday, the Agency called the Department of Defense “dysfunctional” and questioned their decision-making. Though the Department of Defense is yet to make any sort of public response to the allegations, sources in the Department described the CIA as “a tough batch”.</p>



<p>Will internal struggles between different institutions in the U.S. government prevent America from coordinating a viable and consistent response to a conflict on NATO’s doorstep? If the trends of recent hours continue, that may well be the case.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">349</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Whistleblower Reveals Chinese Secrets: Will the World go M.A.D.?</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/whistleblower-reveals-chinese-secrets-will-the-world-go-m-a-d/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Justin Wytmar, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:20:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=332</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In both North Korea and Iran, the situation is inching increasingly nearer to Mutually Assured Destruction (M.A.D.). China has publicly moved troops to the North]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In both North Korea and Iran, the situation is inching increasingly nearer to Mutually Assured Destruction (M.A.D.). China has publicly moved troops to the North Korean border after affirming the legitimacy of Choe Ryong Hae. The PRC is denouncing the rule of Kim Yo Jong, the de facto leader of the North Korean state, and has affirmed that &#8220;the best course of action is to engage militarily.&#8221; On Saturday, a Chinese whistleblower leaked further information to the New York Times.&nbsp;</p>



<p>China is actively using its military against the South Korean military at the North Korean Border. Additionally, the Chinese cabinet is making preparations to bomb Seoul with non-nuclear munitions. The whistleblower informed us that &#8220;the nuclear option was also brought up as a final straw.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Chinese have made plans for an attempted South Korean counter-invasion of China. Under the circumstance that South Korean forces cross the Chinese border, Beijing &#8220;will go nuclear.&#8221; A nuclear war cannot lead to a victory for any of the belligerents. To be as blunt as possible: This is not good.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The whistleblower asked the New York Times to print the following statement: &#8220;By leaking documents to publications like yours I am doing everything in my power to prevent the doomsday scenario and I hope that everyone in my cabinet does the same, even if this includes overthrowing Xi Jinping who has been a notorious warmonger in this situation.&#8221;</p>



<p>As the possibility of a bombing, coup, or nuclear war increases, the world holds their breath. The New York Times will continue to keep you updated as the situation develops.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">332</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>The US declares war on China. Here is what we know.</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/the-us-declares-war-on-china-here-is-what-we-know/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:17:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=331</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the last session of the day, members of the United States Cabinet have reportedly declared war to China. Sources confirmed the Feb. 6 attack]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>In the last session of the day, members of the United States Cabinet have reportedly declared war to China.</strong></p>



<p>Sources confirmed the Feb. 6 attack by Chinese forces in South Korean territory, leaving many wounded and severely injured. In a press release sent by the Cabinet of the United States, they clearly stated their discomfort of this attack, as well as condemning the attack on South Korea forces. “This strike characterizes an uncalled for escalation of violence in an already unstable region that is both immoral and irresponsible”, they said.&nbsp;&nbsp;</p>



<p>Later that day, They classified this attack as “A direct attack to our ally South Korea” witch would be followed by these statements regarding the conflict:</p>



<p>A: Declare war on China. They attacked one of the United States&#8217; most important allies.<br>B: Send in aircraft of our own to fire on Chinese soldiers.<br>C: Continue our support in a more covert fashion. We can&#8217;t get ourselves directly involved.<br>D: Choose your own, or a combination of these options.</p>



<p>The new Biden administration has found themselves in two wars already, and the reputation of the United States seems to be going back into violence and war. The BBC will keep covering this topic closely, and report any new updates.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">331</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>South Korean tensions escalate with China and North Korea.</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/south-korean-tensions-escalate-with-china-and-north-korea/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nathan Zhang, The Korea Herald]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 01:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of South Korea]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=313</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Political and militaristic tensions have reached a breaking point as China and the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea face off against South Korea and its]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Political and militaristic tensions have reached a breaking point as China and the Democratic People’s Republic of Korea face off against South Korea and its allies.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Earlier today, China and Russia officially recognized Choe Ryong-hae, Kim Jong Un&#8217;s former Head of State.</p>



<p>South Korea, Japan, and India, backed by the United States, recognized the North Korean People&#8217;s Liberation Front (PLF) as the legitimate government of Korea. The PLF is a group of military defectors from North Korea that support the reunification of the Korean Peninsula. While political tensions rise, militaristic tensions follow. According to a recent leak, Chinese aircraft have fired upon South Korean soldiers at the 38th parallel.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Although the Cabinet of South Korea has not made action yet, action may be taken against The People’s Republic of China.&nbsp; After the recent encounter with China, it may be reasonable that the two countries will enter war against each other.&nbsp;</p>



<p>If war is to occur, nuclear arms may be involved. Foreshadowing this today, Iran released a statement that “western nations do not have power over other countries, like Iran and North Korea” after conducting a successful nuclear test. This may suggest that North Korea will go to extreme means if South Korea were to invade the DPRK.&nbsp;</p>



<p><br>Whether the South Korean government will go to war is unknown, but tomorrow, the world will find out whether the tensions between China and the Korean peninsula will deescalate.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">313</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Fingers Off!</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/fingers-off/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Justin Wytmar, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:24:27 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Israel]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=285</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the classic eighties film War Games, the movie ends when a near-sentient computer avoids a global nuclear war when it learns the vital lesson]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the classic eighties film <em>War Games</em>, the movie ends when a near-sentient computer avoids a global nuclear war when it learns the vital lesson that, just like Tic-Tac-Toe, nobody wins in a nuclear war. Unlike Tic-Tac-Toe (where every game ends in a cat&#8217;s game), a thermonuclear war ends with everyone dead (a far bleaker outcome). Nevertheless, Iran and Israel seem to have their fingers on the button.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As the New York Times (and other outlets) already reported, an Israeli delegate stated that, &#8220;Our nuclear weapons also will stand at the ready as time continues onward, and God bless us all.&#8221; In an interview, an Iranian ambassador told the New York Times that, &#8220;To the question &#8216;will Iran deploy nukes if invaded?&#8217; I respond with this: &#8216;Would India use its nukes if it was invaded? Would the US? Would Israel?&#8217; Of course. Do not demonize Iran! We have our nukes so that we may never have to use them, you see?&#8221;</p>



<p>It should frighten the world that two nations are this close to detonating nuclear weapons. If Israel launched a preemptive nuclear strike, Iran will no doubt respond, which will no doubt provoke the United States, which will no doubt provoke China and Russia. Alternatively, if Iran launches a nuclear strike, Israel will no doubt respond, which will no doubt provoke Russia and China, which will no doubt provoke the United States. No matter the situation, everyone loses.&nbsp;</p>



<p>This precept isn&#8217;t revolutionary, the idea of Mutually Assured Destruction (or M.A.D. for short) originated in the Cold War. But for some reason, global leaders seem anxious to put their finger on the proverbial big, red button. Why is this the case? Maybe the Ayatollah wants to seem like a strong leader for his people, maybe Israel wants to stay vigilant as a tiny nation surrounded by self-proclaimed enemies. Whatever the reason, it&#8217;s time for the Israelis and the Iranians to rematch War Games, or even just listen to some common sense. To the leaders of Iran and Israel, on behalf of the global community, fingers off!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">285</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>China Wary of Potential Trade Agreement</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/china-wary-of-potential-trade-agreement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Isabella Rosinia, BuzzFeed News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:50:34 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=160</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Trade is and has always been an issue of the South China Sea conflict.  Recently, there have been ongoing discussions of a free trade plan]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p class="has-text-align-left">Trade is and has always been an issue of the South China Sea conflict.  Recently, there have been ongoing discussions of a free trade plan involving the South China Sea.  While some nations of ASEAN believe that this would benefit multiple economies, others are rather skeptical of this plan.  Indonesia and Malaysia believe that China must be a part of this trade agreement, as they and many other countries depend heavily on China’s economy.  China has spoken out on this issue and expressed concerns about the exclusion of other countries, such as Western nations in this free trade agreement. They are  specifically worried about potential exploitation of nations.  The Philippines has sided with China and mentioned that globalization is becoming more and more prevalent to the international community, especially with regards to trade.  We will keep you updated with more news as it becomes available.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">160</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
