<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/archive/2021/author/nmaly/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 01:37:38 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>General Dynamics wants to Monopolize Through Blackmail, Bombings, and Confrontations about Adultery</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/general-dynamics-wants-to-monopolize-through-blackmail-bombings-and-confrontations-about-adultery/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 19:08:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[General Dynamics Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=369</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Mixed discussions taking place in General Dynamics’s boardroom paint a picture of a company preparing for drastic action, with disregard for the consequences or a]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Mixed discussions taking place in General Dynamics’s boardroom paint a picture of a company preparing for drastic action, with disregard for the consequences or a great deal of common sense. “Back to blackmailing the DOD…” stated a General Dynamics executive, before discussions commenced regarding supplying arms to Russia. Executives also suggested providing pizza, free of charge and topped with green peas, to the world, although reasonable suspicion exists that this was a press stunt in order to disguise their real, much more sinister ideas.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Suggestions put forth by the board included sabotaging Lockheed Martin by framing them for bombings, blackmailing opposing executives, bombing the headquarters of competitive companies, and telling foreign executives “Your wife cheated on you!” It was not made clear the exact purposes of these actions, but it’s glaringly obvious that the rest of the world is no match for the might of General Dynamics and its pizza-enthusiast executive board.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">369</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>CIMUN Very Passionate About Their Merchandise</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/cimun-very-passionate-about-their-merchandise/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:52:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=361</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the weekend, the push by administrators for delegates to purchase merch for the Chicago International Model United Nations conference (CIMUN) has escalated. From Friday’s]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Over the weekend, the push by administrators for delegates to purchase merch for the Chicago International Model United Nations conference (CIMUN) has escalated. From Friday’s brief mentions of the merch URL to Saturday night’s trivia-night showcase and Sunday morning’s aggressive pitches by the CEO of Bluebird Aero Systems, CIMUN merch has become a focal point of the conference.</p>



<p>The aforementioned website contains a wide variety of CIMUN merchandise, including shirts, mugs, masks, and hats, all with the CIMUN logo. Many purchases have already been made, but staff continue to push delegates to make purchases, providing a promotional code as well as sketchy incentives for purchases, with Bluebird’s CEO stating that delegate awards will be given on the basis of merchandise purchases.</p>



<p>Since no reporting body can be entirely neutral, the <em>Jerusalem Post</em> has linked below the URL of CIMUN’s much-promoted merchandise website.&nbsp;</p>



<h1><a href="http://cimunmerch.org/" data-type="URL">cimunmerch.org</a></h1>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">361</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Major Movements Made By Bluebird Aero Systems</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/major-movements-made-by-bluebird-aero-systems/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:27:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bluebird Aero Systems]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=341</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The executives of Bluebird Aero Systems, the fast-growing Israeli technology company, have sparred over a wide variety of ideas for expansion of their services. A]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The executives of Bluebird Aero Systems, the fast-growing Israeli technology company, have sparred over a wide variety of ideas for expansion of their services. A general consensus was reached regarding the benefits of partnering with global governments, with executives showing significant desire to establish more formal ties with the United States government for both civilian and defense-related technology sales. Upon request for comment, Bluebird’s Vice President of Government Affairs stated that, “Bluebird would positively regard a partnership with a foreign nation,” although no specific nations were mentioned. Expansion is also being considered into states with the potential for high use of these aircraft, with the potential for future contracts existing with India and many Middle Eastern nations, while demonstrated animosity exists towards the idea of a contracted partnership with Russia.</p>



<p>Reportedly, a few members of the executive board have also expressed interest in joining the Israeli Defense Fund, a step that would tie the corporation even more closely to the Israeli government and provide increased linkage with foreign partners, including the United States. This push has been spearheaded by Bluebird’s Chief of Operations, who has emphasized the importance of international cooperation. While a directive has been drafted in this matter, its status is unknown as of press time.&nbsp;</p>



<p>As of Sunday morning, Bluebird has passed a directive proposing a formal partnership with Boeing after extensive discussions. This partnership will be a collaboration between the two businesses in order to develop more advanced technologies, including aeronautics systems, and progress a joint green initiative. Boeing has not yet formally agreed to the partnership, and updates will be provided as the partnership is formalized.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">341</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia Planning Attack on Belarusian Government</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/russia-planning-attack-on-belarusian-government/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Members of Tactical Missiles Corporation and Sukhoi, currently under the control of the government of the Russian Federation, are deliberating actions to be taken against]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Members of Tactical Missiles Corporation and Sukhoi, currently under the control of the government of the Russian Federation, are deliberating actions to be taken against the current situation in Belarus. Executives are debating cyberattacks, a possibility of cutting communication networks or electricity, and the possibility of arming the public, which could incite an insurrection against the newly placed government. A speech by President Vladimir Putin in front of the United Nations has also been promoted by members of the board in order to inject Russia’s voice into the Belarusian matters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russian executives have also uncovered evidence of intervention by the Central Intelligence Agency, likely behind Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya’s recent rise to power. This discovery has caused strong reactions among Russian executives, with some proposing the idea of war on the grounds of this involvement, with a near consensus regarding some type of action against the United States. Plans are in progress by Russian executives to launch a military offensive against Minsk, the capital of Belarus, in order to unseat the government and remove the influence of members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO). Executives have developed a rough plan to deploy 100,000 troops to Minsk, along with a fleet of armored vehicles. The exact impacts of these movements remains unclear, but escalating and sustained unrest in Belarus is a near certainty.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">301</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BAE Systems Denies Rumors of CIA Cooperation</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/bae-systems-denies-rumors-of-cia-cooperation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:40:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BAE Systems]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=226</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a statement to the Jerusalem Post Saturday, BAE Systems formally denied the previously released information regarding a collaboration with the U.S. Central Intelligence Agency]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a statement to the <em>Jerusalem Post</em> Saturday, BAE Systems formally denied the previously released information regarding a collaboration with the U.S. Central Intelligence Agency (CIA), stating that it “should be considered misinformation” and that the information was not provided by the BAE Systems board. BAE also stated that any information not given directly from the board should be considered incorrect and unreliable.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The statement was given in response to earlier disruption in which an article was published regarding rumors of a BAE Systems deal with the CIA, which was denied by the board in communication with British Prime Minister Boris Johnson almost immediately after its release.&nbsp;<br>Neither side of the issue relating to the earlier publication has been independently verified by the <em>Jerusalem Post</em>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">226</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia Obtains Sukhoi and Tactical Missiles Corporation</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/russia-obtains-sukhoi-and-tactical-missiles-corporation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A temporary merger between Sukhoi and the Tactical Missiles Corporation has evolved, with the Russian Federation taking control of the two corporations. Sukhoi and TMC]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A temporary merger between Sukhoi and the Tactical Missiles Corporation has evolved, with the Russian Federation taking control of the two corporations. Sukhoi and TMC will now work to execute the will of the Russian government, specifically moving in relation to the ongoing crisis in Belarus. Russian President Vladimir Putin, in a statement to the employees of the two companies, directed executives to take whatever action necessary to remove American presence in Belarus, saying that “anything and everything is on the table.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russian executives presented suspicion that Belarus is making moves towards NATO, with Minister Boris Obnosov stating that the presence of NATO troops in Belarus is “all but certain.” The disruption and crippling of the fragile new Belarusian government was encouraged by Putin, with his suggestions including cyberattacks and the bribery of officials. Putin urged the two companies to avoid military force, but to take any other steps to interfere with the presence of U.S. and other NATO officials within Belarus. At this time, multiple directives are being considered to take action on this front, but no concrete steps have been taken.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">221</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>BAE Systems Considering Lockheed Martin Partnership, In Turmoil</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/bae-systems-considering-lockheed-martin-partnership-in-turmoil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 17:59:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[BAE Systems]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Lockheed Martin Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=163</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a dramatic shift in the status quo of international technological contractors, UK-based company BAE Systems has initiated communications with Lockheed Martin. Executives are considering]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a dramatic shift in the status quo of international technological contractors, UK-based company BAE Systems has initiated communications with Lockheed Martin. Executives are considering a partnership with Lockheed Martin, with sharing of European transportation infrastructure and servers on the table, with other possibilities being cooperation on cybersecurity. However, terms of the deal are uncertain, and strong opposition to a merger is widespread. CIA partnerships have also been proposed, but have temporarily been tabled.</p>



<p>BAE Systems has faced turmoil, both internal and external, in recent months. Conflict within company leadership has also presented issues, as strong disagreement between BAE’s CEO and members of the board of directors has hampered progress on a deal and has already resulted in changes in position within the company. The corporation is bankrupt, and the implementation of a new CEO presents the opportunity for radical change in the company.</p>



<p>BAE Systems’ newly appointed CEO, Ms. Lisa Carr, has stated that the company’s current financial difficulties are entirely the responsibility of the previous CEO, Charles Woodburn, and has promised significant changes in the company’s strategy moving into 2021. It’s unclear exactly what these changes may include, but increased foreign partnership appears to be a very viable option, with potential markets including Europe, Asia, and the US. Division is present over the possibility of a Belarusian deal, with major decisions being revisited due to Belarus’s rapidly deteriorating situation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">163</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Bluebird Aero Systems Directors To Convene, Considering Expansion</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/bluebird-aero-systems-directors-to-convene-considering-expansion/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 16:35:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Bluebird Aero Systems]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=105</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On Jan. 5, 2021, the Board of Directors of the Bluebird Aero Systems Corporation are scheduled to convene. They will likely discuss the opportunity to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On Jan. 5, 2021, the Board of Directors of the Bluebird Aero Systems Corporation are scheduled to convene. They will likely discuss the opportunity to expand global use of the&nbsp; Unmanned Aircraft Systems (UAS) and Unmanned Aerial Vehicle (UAV) technologies. The UAS and the UAV&nbsp; have the potential to drastically change the way many technologies are used by the military and civilians.</p>



<p>Bluebird Aero is an up-and-coming company, which was founded in 2002. The company develops and sells UAS and UAV technology, which they say have a variety of military and civilian uses. Some being: military surveillance missions, weather tracking, and cargo deliveries. These technologies are becoming increasingly relevant, with a recent large purchase of stock by the Israeli government bringing global attention to the corporation. UAS and UAV technology could be valuable advancements in the many conflicts in which the Israeli government currently has a stake and are being utilized by several governments, including India.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Directors are expected to address the growth of the company, among other things, raising questions regarding executive plans surrounding research and development, governmental cooperation, and use in a growing number of contexts. Either way, the decisions made at the upcoming meetings may be incredibly consequential.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">105</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
