<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/author/asouphakdy/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:20:57 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>China: Humanitarian Aid is a Given</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/china-humanitarian-aid-is-a-given-ready-to-be-published/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:10:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=430</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As more debate arises in the Security Council on the Russia-Ukraine War, China raises its position on the solution by vetoing the resolution of humanitarian]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As more debate arises in the Security Council on the Russia-Ukraine War, China raises its position on the solution by vetoing the resolution of humanitarian aid in the council.</p>



<p>The reason for this is that China believes through this crisis the Security Council has failed to commit to helping the major crisis going on within Ukraine. If the Security Council cannot commit to the bigger task that was at hand the act for humanitarian aid should be put at a pause.</p>



<p>The Security Council failed to amend a peace talk between Russia and Ukraine and has failed to release any statement on the matter. The representative from China commented, &#8220;it shows a lack of commitment towards ending a War&#8221; and putting funds toward humanitarian aid would be unreasonable due to the lack of commitment the Council has. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X&#8217;s New Collaboration Meltdown 💩</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/xs-new-collaboration-meltdown-%f0%9f%92%a9/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:31:09 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=417</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The social media platform X, formerly known as Twitter, has created new borders for the expansion of the app. X&#8217;s current plan includes the collaboration]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The social media platform X, formerly known as Twitter, has created new borders for the expansion of the app. X&#8217;s current plan includes the collaboration of their companies such as Solar City and The Boring Company to create additional features to the app. These upgrades have currently been put on a major hold after the U.S. government announced they&#8217;ll be suing the platform regarding the accusations of spreading false information on the app. </p>



<p>The press representative of X announced yesterday the creation of &#8220;X Connect&#8221;, a user platform made to go worldwide, featuring add-ons for the app such as X Maps which collaborates with Solar City and X to create a map system within their app to help users. X also wants to implement an AI source into the app to allow for artificial intelligence to assist users. However, with the recent reaction from Elon Musk to the U.S. government being quite questionable, will X continue their journey to the collaboration of companies to the platform?</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>&#8220;Peace Talks&#8221; are Not an Option</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/peace-talks-are-not-an-option/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 03:15:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=396</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The delegations of China and Brazil have proposed peace in the Russia-Ukraine War and it has just been shut down by the Western delegations. Humanitarian]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p> The delegations of China and Brazil have proposed peace in the Russia-Ukraine War and it has just been shut down by the Western delegations. Humanitarian aid is not the problem here; it is the Western bloc of nations in the Security Council refusing to bring peace to the Ukrainian nation. In the republic stance, there were refusals from the council denying any concessions of military aid along with a refusal of ceasefire with Brazil commenting that they thought it would help Russia and save Ukrainian lives which China and Brazil state is &#8220;ridiculous&#8221;.</p>



<p>&#8220;Politics are playing too big of a conflict in this War,&#8221; says China, and Brazil and China are at a neutral stance to the War. Nations have denied peace talks and ceasefire and are assuming the position of Ukrainians in this War. There have also been major refusals to initiate a peace talk with Russia and Ukraine and with the neutrality of Brazil and China, they believe peace could&#8217;ve been the answer. But with many representatives in the Security Council arguing opposing perspectives neutrality is off the table. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNGA: The Real &#8220;Heroes&#8221; of Climate Change</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/unga-the-real-heroes-of-climate-change/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:56:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=256</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The UNGA plans for solving the climate crisis have reached a stalemate. The general assembly is slow on their topic and the world does not]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The UNGA plans for solving the climate crisis have reached a stalemate. The general assembly is slow on their topic and the world does not have enough time for them to take their sweet time. No solution of any kind has been mainly addressed, countries are not getting anywhere on there on a plan of any kind. However, many countries pushed for the topic of climate change to be primarily addressed. </p>



<p>Since the 1850s, the climate crisis has shadowed the world every day. The climate of the world has been majorly changing the ideologies of countries through the years. Today the climate crisis is a major crisis for each and every country and the UNGA is taking their time on the issue that has increasingly been affecting every country. The UNGA will be wiped out because of climate change before they can help climate change.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Delegations such as New Zealand have stated that “These solutions have taken much longer than they would like” and climate change is going to affect countries faster than we think. Other countries such as Tanzania say ,“ They agree with the resolutions going on currently.” The UNGA needs to pick a common direction and recommend a plan before it&#8217;s too late. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Security Council must act on Ukraine War: China</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/07/security-council-must-act-on-ukraine-war-china/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Akina Souphakdy, Xinhua State News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 06:06:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=94</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Russian-Ukrainian war has been an ongoing crisis since February of 2022, with over 350,000 casualties, which the People&#8217;s Republic of China deems purely unacceptable.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Russian-Ukrainian war has been an ongoing crisis since February of 2022, with over 350,000 casualties, which the People&#8217;s Republic of China deems purely unacceptable. Today, the war is still active and many countries, such as the U.S., have put major sanctions on the Russian Federation. </p>



<p>The representative of the People&#8217;s Republic of China to the Security Council believes that “now is not the time for symbolic grandstanding” and they need to put out real resolutions to end the war. It is not a time to add “fuel to the fire.” </p>



<p>The People&#8217;s Republic of China urges the stance of the Security Council that the war is not a matter to pull political affairs into. There should be laws passed in order to help the people and if any political matter arises within the resolutions China believes politics is not the first option.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
