<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Cabinet of Saudi Arabia &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/archive/2021/category/cabinet-of-saudi-arabia/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:40:09 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>Russia and Iran come Together. Attack in Saudi Arabia a Possibility</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/russia-and-iran-come-together-attack-in-saudi-arabia-a-possibility/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Alejandro Moreno, BBC News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:40:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Iran]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Saudi Arabia]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=346</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Irani Cabinet came into agreement with Russia, creating a new partnership to respond to alleged Saudi Arabian Attacks. The Israeli cabinet held a successful]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p style="font-size:13px"><strong>The Irani Cabinet came into agreement with Russia, creating a new partnership to respond to alleged Saudi Arabian Attacks.</strong></p>



<p>The Israeli cabinet held a successful meeting with the Russian Cabinet regarding humanitarian aid and nuclear resources . During the discussions after this agreement it was mentioned several times the possible killing or Attack in Saudi Arabian Soil. The King and main oil refineries are among the targets of the Irani cabinet, as well as possible . The following statement was passed by the Cabinet:&nbsp;</p>



<p>To the people of Iran, we as a Cabinet have recently voted unanimously to join the CSTO with the Russian Federation. The Islamic Republic of Iran now considers the Russian Federation a strong nuclear superpower that we call a friend. Russia has recently protected our sovereign nation from a Saudi Arabian attack on our nuclear program. In response to this attack on our nation, the Cabinet of the Islamic Republic of Iran has decided to respond to the Saudi Arabian attack by attacking oil refineries in Saudi Arabia and ports on the Strait of Hormuz. We have also decided as a Cabinet to increase naval presence on the Strait of Hormuz. Any military action that will be taken in the new future are in response to the aggression of the imperialist west.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Iran also showed full support to the Chinese government after the attacks in South Korea, and it&#8217;s happy for “non-imperialist”&nbsp; adversity presented to the United States of America. This alliance with Russia could bring more stability to their situation in the Middle East, but it could also mean a more catastrophic war between G5 nations. The BBC will keep you informed of any new updates.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">346</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Saudi Arabian Council of Ministers to Discuss Iranian Nuclear Developments</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/saudi-arabian-council-of-ministers-to-discuss-iranian-nuclear-developments/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Maddy Jeleniewski, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 03:10:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of Saudi Arabia]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=92</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[U.N. experts warn of the Iranian government’s developments in nuclear technology, ‘potentially leading them to obtain weapons-grade fissile material by mid to late February’, report]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<h4>U.N. experts warn of the Iranian government’s developments in nuclear technology, ‘potentially leading them to obtain weapons-grade fissile material by mid to late February’, report says.</h4>



<p>Highly surprising and important intelligence was recently publicized by the Saudi Arabian General Intelligence Presidency (GIP)–the Iranian government is rumored to be continuing its developments on nuclear technology. Per the report, this could  “lead them to obtaining weapons-grade fissile material by mid to late February”. </p>



<p>Due to existing tension between Iran and the rest of the world, U.N. experts have stated finding heavy evidence that <a href="https://www.foxnews.com/politics/un-experts-evidence-iran-houthi-rebels-yemen">Iran has sent weapons to Houthi rebels in war-torn Yemen</a>. They have also found a list of weapons that include anti-tank guided missiles, sniper rifles, and RPB launchers–all of the aforementioned weaponry being adorned with trademark Iranian markings/labels.&nbsp;</p>



<p>During President Trump’s time in office, his administration was adamant to warn the public of Iran’s increasing likelihood to disrupt the stability of the Middle East through arms trade.&nbsp; Former Secretary of State, Mike Pompeo, even went as far as to impose sanctions on the Houthi rebels specifically, identifying them as a foreign terrorist organization (FTO). In response, the Trump Administration pushed for the implementation of more sanctions, due to the impending expiration of 2015 sanctions, as well as a broader arms embargo.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Now, the Biden Administration, upon taking office, has suspended many of the sanctions that were imposed to battle against previously mentioned issues.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Saudi Arabian officials as well as Middle Eastern officials worry about the increasing tension and the consequences it can have on the well being of the entire region as a whole, if these weapons become a reality. What will the Saudi Arabian government do about these developments?&nbsp;</p>



<p>Salamin bin Abdulaziz Al Saud has decided to take action against spreading rumors by arranging for a meeting between the Council of Ministers of Saudi Arabia, who will be tasked with tackling these problems of dire importance. Fox News is dedicated to ensuring that the public is kept up-to-date with major proceedings regarding this cabinet–in relation to current worldwide problems.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">92</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
