<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/author/rwuppalapati/feed/?simply_static_page=1315" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:29:43 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Chinese finance minister announces plan to become sole Taiwanese ruler</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/chinese-finance-minister-announces-plan-to-become-sole-taiwanese-ruler/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:24:38 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ministries of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1677</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The People’s Republic of China’s finance minister laid out his plans to become the sole ruler of Taiwan in an exclusive interview with the Moscow]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The People’s Republic of China’s finance minister laid out his plans to become the sole ruler of Taiwan in an exclusive interview with the Moscow Times. The Minister explained his goals and his desire for the Taiwanese people.</p>



<p>Claiming that Taiwan was rightfully Chinese land, the minister explained why he felt the obligation to want the island. </p>



<p>“The citizens of Taiwan want a minister who is in accordance with the people,” he said. “I am that person.” </p>



<p>The Chinese finance minister also reiterated that he is the only person he believes the Taiwanese people want ruling over them. </p>



<p>“I have experience as a finance minister, and I know how money runs a country,” he explained. He also elaborated that China taking over Taiwan would complete China’s adherence to the one country, two systems policy.</p>



<p>The minister of finance remained mum on how he would implement his plans to take over the island. “I haven’t decided on anything specific,” he said, in regard to how he would invade the island. “But when the time is right, Taiwan joining us will be inevitable.”</p>



<p>He also laid out the Communist system that he would impose in Taiwan. “The Taiwanese people do not want a democracy,” he stated. “They want a system of government similar to what rules mainland China.” According to a recent poll conducted through Taipei’s National Chengchi University, only 6.5 percent of Taiwanese citizens support reunification and rule under the People’s Republic of China.</p>



<p>“I want to see Taiwan under new management,” the finance minister explained. When asked how he would deal with potential opposition from current Taiwanese citizens, he was blunt. “We need reeducation rather than suppression of the press,” he said. “The only way the world will learn to understand our Communist government is if we re-educate them through increased media and literature.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Corrections to Moscow Times-Al Jazeera Articles</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/corrections-to-moscow-times-al-jazeera-articles/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 22:08:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Al Jazeera Editorial Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1656</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Moscow Times would like to sincerely apologize for errors in the press that have been reported in two recent articles about Al Jazeera. Firstly,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Moscow Times would like to sincerely apologize for errors in the press that have been reported in two recent articles about Al Jazeera. Firstly, the Moscow Times incorrectly transcribed a quote from the Minister of Technology calling upon a “hostage takeover.” In reality, the Minister of Technology called upon a “hostile takeover.” Additionally, in the opinion piece, “No objective news will come out of Al Jazeera until it cuts off Qatar,” the Minister of Technology’s assertion was repeated more accurately but he was misidentified as the Minister of Transportation. The Minister of Technology made the statement. The Moscow Times would also like to clarify a comment about the journalistic standards, this was made in regard to a working paper where the Balkans Director was questioning how to improve journalistic standards, and should not be taken to mean that Al Jazeera currently has none. That said, the Moscow Times stands by all other assertions made in both articles.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Soviets Continuing Covert International Operations at Expense of Freedom</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/soviets-continuing-covert-international-operations-at-expense-of-freedom/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 20:27:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Soviet Union (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1582</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an exclusive interview with the Moscow Times, the USSR’s cabinet revealed plans to intervene in the war in Argentina to further spread Communism there.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In an exclusive interview with the Moscow Times, the USSR’s cabinet revealed plans to intervene in the war in Argentina to further spread Communism there. In the aftermath of the UK’s victory in the Falklands, Soviet ministers announced plans to support military action to make Argentina a Communist nation.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“We want a strong ally in Latin America,” said the Administrator of Affairs. “[Cuban leader Fidel] Castro said he was very willing to spread Communism in the region, and we would be helped with a strong ally.”</p>



<p>However, the Soviets made no mention of increasing freedom of the press or expanding democracy in Argentina. After the South American power suffered under a rightist military dictatorship led by Jorge Videla and Leopoldo Galtieri, the Soviets under Andropov have expressed plans to implement a leftist dictatorship partially financed by Cuba.</p>



<p>Other Soviet ministers have proclaimed that these plans to invade Argentina have been scrapped. “We wanted to focus more on the safety of our constituents,” said the Minister of Defense. “That’s what’s important.”</p>



<p>However, gas prices have risen, according to the Minister of Internal Affairs. Hunger rates have remained high amongst many Russian constituents. Furthermore, the USSR cabinet remained hesitant to assist their hungriest constituents, with the Minister of Defense wondering, “are food banks too democratic?”.</p>



<p>The USSR Cabinet further affirmed its monetary interests to trade with Iran instead of Iraq in their conflict. While the Minister of Defense expressed a desire to stay neutral and the Administrator of Affairs worried that involvement in the Iran-Iraq War would spark tension, others, such as the Minister of Internal Affairs, favored under-the-table deals such as arm sales to keep funding. “I’m just throwing ideas on a dartboard to see what sticks,” he said. Additionally, several ministers described a desire to trade with “puppet states” to build Soviet influence around the world even further.</p>



<p>The USSR reaffirmed total resistance to press freedom, with the Minister of Defense proclaiming that “the Moscow Times is already a wonderful newspaper. We don’t need more than two”. The Moscow Times is currently based in Amsterdam and editorially repudiates all forms of dictatorship and censorship. Meanwhile, Soviet citizens are kept unaware of warfare specifically so they cannot retaliate.</p>



<p>The Soviet Union maintains that its actions are motivated out of goodwill for its people. However, the Cabinet Chair spoke bluntly. “We’re the Soviet Union; nothing is illegal to us,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>No objective news will come out of Al Jazeera until it cuts off Qatar</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/no-objective-news-will-come-out-of-al-jazeera-until-it-cuts-off-qatar/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 16:42:32 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Al Jazeera Editorial Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1514</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the minutes after the Qatari minister of transportation threatened to cut off Al Jazeera and hold its journalists accountable, the network began discussing new]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the minutes after the Qatari minister of transportation threatened to cut off Al Jazeera and hold its journalists accountable, the network began discussing new plans to please the Qatari government. In the SLAY working paper, Al Jazeera discussed plans to change their coverage and portray Qatar in a more positive light.</p>



<p>One of the clauses in the paper involves Al Jazeera hiring an economist from the greater Middle East to speak about why Qatar is an ideal nation to move to because of its strong resources. They also hope to create a project to tell stories and traditions from Qatar to ensure its history is portrayed in the best light possible.</p>



<p>All after the government threatened to fire the Board of Directors and hold them hostage.</p>



<p>The editorial opinion of the Moscow Times is that when dictatorships begin threatening the well-being of journalists, the journalists’ lives take precedence over adherence to the truth. Al Jazeera has implemented some workarounds to ensure journalistic integrity, such as company-wide surveys to identify points of reform in stories, such as impartiality and bias. However, these workarounds are anonymous and could easily be manipulated by the Qatari government. Furthermore, describing investment opportunities in Qatar may enrich the government to further suppress the views of journalists.</p>



<p>In another working paper, titled “We Address Takeover Evacuation” (We ATE), Al Jazeera has laid out plans to leave the country in case the government attempts to falsely imprison or harm the journalists. However, the Moscow Times believes that this must be the action taken if Qatar’s money continues to suppress the voice of journalists. Censorship naturally degrades reporting; the Balkans Director even questioned, “have we defined journalistic standards for hiring?” If Al Jazeera hopes to maintain serious coverage and be considered a voice of the Arab World, it must have the courage to leave Qatar and establish its own independence as a network.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Qatari technology minister threatens to hold Al Jazeera members hostage</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/qatari-technology-minister-threatens-to-hold-al-jazeera-members-hostage/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 15:56:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Al Jazeera Editorial Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1487</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After Al Jazeera’s recent actions to create a TikTok network and expand their news scope, the Qatari government still expressed its anger with the network’s]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After Al Jazeera’s recent actions to create a TikTok network and expand their news scope, the Qatari government still expressed its anger with the network’s progress. The government specifically cited “flailing international reporting” as the cause of its ire.</p>



<p>&nbsp;“We had high hopes for the nascent network, and were determined to share many opinions,” said the Minister of Technology. “But by the recent callousness of reporting, we will have no choice but to hold Al Jazeera journalists hostage.”</p>



<p>Al Jazeera’s journalists believe that the Qatari government’s anger is veiled criticism of the network’s opinions. “We embrace journalism and journalistic ethics,” said the Mubasher Director. “So when the government threatens us, it means they’re imposing their opinions over the truth we report.”</p>



<p>Other Al Jazeera Board of Directors members addressed a need to appease the Qatari government. </p>



<p>“We need the funding from the government,” said the Balkans Director. “It’s not ideal, but we may have to appease the Qatari government in order to survive.” </p>



<p>However, the Balkans Director clarified that he does not want to take orders directly from Qatar.  “We still need to focus on internal efforts, and report on issues where we’re independent, but still reporting on issues Qatar wants us to report on,” he said.</p>



<p>However, Al Jazeera’s journalists have affirmed that their top priority is currently maintaining journalistic integrity, and hope to report even if they are held hostage or are evicted from Qatar. “The government may seize our property at any time,” said the Mubasher Director. “So we need to make sure we can safely be evacuated.”</p>



<p>The Mubasher Director pleaded for international support to help the journalists against the Qatari government, whose Energy Minister recently advocated a “forgive and forget” attitude towards Russia’s invasion of Ukraine. “The world needs to know where Qatar is putting their resources,” the Mubasher Director said. </p>



<p>The Arabic Director expanded on this. “We need international aid to make sure we can wean off government support and maintain our independence,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Janes aim social media campaign to grow movement</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/janes-aim-social-media-campaign-to-grow-movement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 03:15:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Janes]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Janes, a nonprofit group that aims to promote equitable access to abortion, have been organizing a social media campaign to protect women’s right to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Janes, a nonprofit group that aims to promote equitable access to abortion, have been organizing a social media campaign to protect women’s right to choose. Citing concerns over repression of reproductive rights in an era where abortion is not protected federally, the Janes have been working to make sure that right is given.</p>



<p>The founder of the Janes explained her concerns with the government’s lack of progress in expanding abortion access. “The U.S. has failed to protect women’s rights,” she said. “That’s why we’re doing all that we can to protect abortion access.”</p>



<p>The organization is beginning with establishing social media accounts and leading assemblies and community events. “We’d like to use any form of social media,” said the Founder. “TikTok, Instagram, maybe even LinkedIn to recruit nurses and gynecologists.”</p>



<p>TikTok in particular has elicited support amongst Janes. Because Gen Z is statistically the most active cohort on TikTok, many of the leaders believe raising awareness on the platform will educate teens. “As an adult, I’ve spent 13 hours on TikTok sometimes,” said co-founder Kendra Winter. “So if we make videos targeted at kids, we’ll be able to reach them efficiently.”</p>



<p>For the founder, expanding access to abortion through social media is not a pipe dream, it is an integral part of American democracy. “The best way to reform democracy is to work within it,” she said. “Through social media, we can encourage citizens to vote and take action to make sure their rights are protected.”</p>



<p>The Janes have also explored connecting with local press and other organizations to raise awareness of abortion rights. </p>



<p>“While we aim to use social media to build a national platform, we want to stay local to Chicago on the ground for now,” the founder explained. The Director of Community Relations also cited Gen Z for Change as a potential organization to collaborate with.</p>



<p>The Janes chair admits her lofty goals, stating that “it’s going to be hard to organize a benefit concert or get Taylor Swift to speak out.” However, the group, which currently has under 100 volunteers and workers but over 20,000 followers, aims to grow on social media even more. “We can use hashtags like #WeAreJane,” said the director of communications. “That way, we’ll expand our reach to women nationwide.</p>



<p>The founder is confident that using social media will maintain American democratic values. “The government is doing what it can,” she said. “But if we use social media to build a movement, we’ll actually be a bigger part of the government and expand the people’s will.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia expels journalists as Ukrainians killed</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/russia-expels-journalists-as-ukrainians-killed/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 02:16:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1245</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Russian Federation has refused to open the door to journalists who attempt to report on their politics, with the president personally intimidating journalists who]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Russian Federation has refused to open the door to journalists who attempt to report on their politics, with the president personally intimidating journalists who challenge his politics. When Moscow Times reporters attempted to enter what was an Open Meeting, they were immediately arrested and threatened by the guards.</p>



<p>Some of the reporters attempted to challenge the president. “I am the President,” he responded back. “I do what I want.”</p>



<p>The Russian President specifically cited the Moscow Times’ stance against the Russian invasion of Ukraine, an action the president repeatedly referred to as a “righteous cause.” However, more than 7,000 civilians have been killed in the war in Ukraine, all while Russia’s GDP has decreased by 0.5 percent.</p>



<p>Freedoms for journalists and the media have greatly diminished according to watchdog group Freedom House, while 12 journalists have been killed in Ukraine since the start of the war. Furthermore, Russian actions have been financially assisted by a variety of companies and countries.</p>



<p>ExxonMobil has spent up to 16 billion dollars on Russia since 2005, and left about 4 billion dollars in assets when they pulled back in 2022. When questioned about their assistance in Russia’s war, ExxonMobil’s Board of Directors were unable to provide clear responses. “Check the 10K,” said the President. “I don’t know the complete answer.”</p>



<p>ExxonMobil has aimed to uphold national and international law. President of Technology and Engineering LD DuCharme stated that “we are mainly focused on sustainability.” However, many executives also joked about the lack of consequences for violating the U.S. deal. “When you’re rich, you don’t lose time,” said the ExxonMobil President. “You lose money instead.”</p>



<p>Additionally, according to the US Treasury Secretary, China had made an offer to Russia to undercut the US-ExxonMobil deal at a cheaper rate. Chinese officials admitted the offer, but said that they had not entertained the deal. “We have no plans to further negotiate with Russia,” said the Chinese Finance Minister.</p>



<p>However, China still sends billions of dollars to Russia. “We have always been cooperating with them,” said the Finance Minister. “Nothing is new.”</p>



<p>However, Russia’s war has been bolstered by continuous funding. As one of the Moscow Times evicted journalists stated, “they pay for war, and receive its profits to shut down the press.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>African Union will never address anything until it addresses corruption and a free press</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/african-union-will-never-address-anything-until-it-addresses-corruption-and-a-free-press/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 23:19:22 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[African Union]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1176</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the African Union’s general assembly floor, delegates convened to discuss how to mitigate issues from climate change to biodiversity. Countless resolutions written have called]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On the African Union’s general assembly floor, delegates convened to discuss how to mitigate issues from climate change to biodiversity. Countless resolutions written have called upon using in-depth solutions to ensure ecotourism can be expanded, deforestation can be prevented, and a great deal of progress can be made to fully bring Africa into the 21st Century. The WE AID PB&amp;J Paper was written to hold industries and corporations accountable for their environmental damage.</p>



<p>But this is par for the course for the African Union. Meeting after meeting, decade after decade, working papers with lofty goals to end pollution, eradicate hunger, expand access to clean plumbing are passed. And yet, there is no real change in Africa. Corrupt governments and a lack of press freedoms continue to lie to their citizens while enriching themselves, preventing any meaningful resolutions from being implemented.</p>



<p>Only seven countries in sub-Saharan Africa are considered Free by Freedom House, a global liberties watchdog. Reporters Without Borders, meanwhile, has highlighted 21 African countries in either red or black because violations of free press are so egregious that journalists cannot report news critical of their governments without fear for their well-being. And corruption has not ended. In January 2023, The Corruption Perceptions Index gave sub-Saharan Africa as a whole 32 out of 100 marks due to continued bribery and violation of political rights across the continent. With such discouraging metrics, it is no wonder why the African Union’s work fails to have long-term impacts. That is why it’s vital for them to take the delegation of Côte d’Ivoire’s lead to primarily pass resolutions that hold leaders accountable and expand the freedom of the press.</p>



<p>Côte d’Ivoire recognized that partisanship within the committee has prevented resolutions from being passed in a speedy manner. </p>



<p>“The delegation of Côte d’Ivoire is working towards a steady democracy,” said their representative. “That’s why we’re succeeding.”</p>



<p>The delegation of Guinea-Bissau concurred. “We lacked discussion of free press, but the free press is what holds governments accountable,” a Guinea-Bissau representative said. “We need to start giving a voice to the people.”</p>



<p>To ensure global democracy, it is vital that every country puts in its dues to combat corruption and the lack of a free media &#8211; because that will allow resolutions to be put into action.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>USSR unveils plans to spread communism globally</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/ussr-unveils-plans-to-spread-communism-globally/</link>
					<comments>/ipd-archive/XIX23/ussr-unveils-plans-to-spread-communism-globally/#respond</comments>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 21:53:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Soviet Union (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1125</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Through an exclusive interview with the Cabinet of the USSR, the Moscow Times has learned the goals the Soviet Union has to spread Communism globally.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Through an exclusive interview with the Cabinet of the USSR, the Moscow Times has learned the goals the Soviet Union has to spread Communism globally. The USSR’s number one priority is to focus on improving the lives of the Soviet people, by eliminating distinctions between class.</p>



<p>“The entire basis of Communism is that everyone is created equal,” the Minister of Defense said. “Everyone has the same job status and makes the same amount of money.” </p>



<p>In the eyes of the Soviet Union, this is why a free press and democracy do not need to exist. </p>



<p>“We’ve eliminated distinctions between outside groups,” said the Minister of Defense. “That’s why only two newspapers need to exist in Russia.”</p>



<p>The Soviets point to their strong economic numbers as evidence of their success. The nation boasts a 1 percent unemployment rate (by contrast, modern Keynesian economics supports a 3 to 4 percent unemployment rate to curb inflation). And according to the Minister of Finance, “unemployment in the USSR is expected to drop further.”</p>



<p>Their economic goals extend further.</p>



<p>“We aim to spread egalitarianism, raise the GDP, and implement the Brezhnev Doctrine,” said the Administrator of Affairs. The Brezhnev Doctrine believes in military intervention in any country where socialist rule is under threat.</p>



<p>This emphasis on militarism has brought the USSR into public light following their Afghan invasion. To grow Soviet influence, the Minister of Defense hopes to “make as much leeway in Afghanistan.” </p>



<p>When further pressed on spreading Communism through force, the Defense Minister initially stated that invading nearby nations was a possibility. However, she quickly corrected herself.</p>



<p>“I’m not saying we will invade other places,” she explained. “But we need to show other countries the right form of government.”</p>



<p>All of the Cabinet members insisted on invasions and resistance to democracy as a means to protect the USSR. </p>



<p>“Other countries have unfairly invaded our own,” said the Administrator of Affairs. However, when he was asked to give examples, he could not give any. Still, the USSR Cabinet was adamant that their current foreign invasion was the right thing to do. </p>



<p>“We’re using force because we’ve had to,” said the Minister of Defense. “Capitalism has failed for so long, and when other nations see that Communism works, they will go along with us.”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
					<wfw:commentRss>/ipd-archive/XIX23/ussr-unveils-plans-to-spread-communism-globally/feed/</wfw:commentRss>
			<slash:comments>0</slash:comments>
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>US, Chinese Leaders Conflict on Relationships Between Free Media and Oil </title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/us-chinese-leaders-conflict-on-relationships-between-free-media-and-oil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Rishabh Wuppalapati, Moscow Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 19:08:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[ExxonMobil (XOM)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1051</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On February 3, the United States Cabinet and the ExxonMobil Board of Directors held an open door meeting to discuss expansion of oil drilling to]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On February 3, the United States Cabinet and the ExxonMobil Board of Directors held an open door meeting to discuss expansion of oil drilling to global markets. At the same time, Chinese leaders discussed dealing with their oil crisis caused by the Russo-Ukrainian War. However, the nations’ approaches to dealing with opposition have starkly differed.</p>



<p>An ExxonMobil executive who wished to remain anonymous acknowledged that protests over the private deal may erupt. “We can’t stop protests from happening,” said the executive. “So we need to address the volatility of them by working with their demands.” American secretaries have also discussed how they will address protests. “We do not want to create a monopoly with our deal,” said the CIA Director. “So if protests erupt, we’ll need to address that.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>While Chinese leaders have openly welcomed protests, they have explained mass arrests of protestors. “We have no knowledge of unjust detaining,” said Finance Minister Liu Kun. “The only reason protestors were arrested was for sedition and treason, and we want to speak to the leaders directly.” Culture and Tourism Minister Hu Heping also outlined her concern with free press reporting on the protests. “There is a massive security issue with private press,” she said. “Government owned does not mean unfree.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>ExxonMobil secretaries admitted their frustration with protests nonetheless. “Protestors don’t know what they want from ExxonMobil,” said the anonymous secretary. “We know what we want.” Various Cabinet members discussed how ExxonMobil will expand drilling in untapped markets with a goal of making American markets more competitive than Russian and Chinese markets. The executive further discussed his wishes to achieve what the public desires, a sentiment echoed by executive LD DuCharme. “We want to also invest into biofuels,” she said.</p>



<p>In the meeting between the US government and ExxonMobil, the Treasury Secretary specifically mentioned ExxonMobil’s commitment to sustainability as the reason for working with them. “We need to keep competition up,” said the Secretary. “If Exxon violates our deal or US laws, the deal is over.”</p>



<p>Chinese officials have remained mum on expanding oil drilling amongst mass protests in the country. Finance minister Liu Kun explained his hesitancy on action. “We want to keep our neutrality,” he explained. “So it’s difficult to say where our oil will come from.” However, the United States Treasury Secretary was clear. “Nothing is more valuable to the US than oil,” he said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
