<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/author/kritchie/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:53:02 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>PRESS CONFERENCE: United States is Shocked China&#8217;s Actions</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/press-conference-united-states-is-shocked-chinas-actions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between the two countries. The U.S. representative has sensed some aggression from China, also shown through how they have allowed themselves to come into meetings with no prior conversation. </p>



<p>The United States has further commentary on the fact that China has said they do not want forgiven involvement at the moment because of any possible influence on their election. Yet, the United States mentioned how the Chinese app, Tencent,  is spreading misinformation and has directly influenced China’s election. Showing that even with no current foreign relations, there are still direct influences on their election via the country’s social media app. Was it really worth it to cut connections with other countries that have not had an influence when you country has had an influence first? </p>



<p>Due to the previous actions that China has taken, the United States feels that China is rejecting any possible diplomatic offers. Furthermore, the U.S. has called upon the United Nations Security Council to help deal with these issues in China and even Taiwan as it is going to be needed to keep international peace between countries. After coordinating with the U.S. Security Council representative, the U.S. is urging the most powerful peacekeeping body in the world to help to deal with China’s actions as quickly and as effectively as possible. Now, the United States will no longer be in contact with the China government because of all the previously mentioned issues and that they have disrespected diplomacy. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X is Getting Sued? What Will Happen Now?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/x-is-getting-sued-what-will-happen-now/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[X Corporation, owner of the social media platform formerly known as Twitter and currently developing X-Connect, is currently being sued by the U.S. government. They]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>X Corporation, owner of the social media platform formerly known as Twitter and currently developing X-Connect, is currently being sued by the U.S. government. They say they have nothing to hide, but, if they have nothing to hide, what is the real reason for them getting sued? The X representative said that they have not had government involvement because of the issues that are surrounded with it, but they are not involved and are having issues with that same government. </p>



<p>They say that they are still committed to the development of the X-Connect app while following regulations and focusing on innovations even after this information of them being sued. After a U.S. cabinet meeting in which an A.I. implication was brought up, the U.S. government and X each threatened to sue the other entity. So they say that they have no government relations, yet still talk to the U.S. cabinet? That is directly going against what the X representative said they were doing. How are you able to go against your own words?</p>



<p>Even though they are receiving an abundance of backlash and are in the midst of getting sued, X Corporation is still attempting to further develop their app. Which also raises the question, will that affect the amount of users that will use their X-Connect app? They have said that they are going to continue to control their app because they have trust in their own systems, and as of now have no further comment on the situation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago City Council: Updates from Alderperson Pat Dowell from Ward Three</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/chicago-city-council-updates-from-alderperson-pat-dowell-from-ward-three/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 21:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Updates on what has been going on within the past few days have been shared from Alderperson Pat Dowell from Ward three. This includes updates]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Updates on what has been going on within the past few days have been shared from Alderperson Pat Dowell from Ward three. This includes updates on recent bills that were passed, historical sites, the education system, and the migrant situation throughout Chicago. </p>



<p>Today, there was a bill passed that Dowell was included in that will allow Chicago to bring some of the historical sites back to life. It was mentioned how there was some concern in structural changes, but, it was reassured that no exterior structural changes would be made to any historical structures, and that the interior would be dealt with by the private investors. The main structural changes that would be made would be if there is serious damage to the site. </p>



<p>More recently, there is a bill in the works that relates to mental health awareness in students and teachers. As well as awareness to any issues in relation to bus drivers, which not detail was given on. Other important issues that Dowell is currently looking into and discussing is the issue of environmental education. </p>



<p>After working with Alderperson Nicole Lee from the eleventh ward, the pair were able to pass a bill relating to the migrant situation. This bill aims to reuse old buildings that can be quickly fixed up into housing. This would be a short term solution that would be implemented until a longer term solution is found for this crisis. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago City Council working on healthcare, housing, and historical sites</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/chicago-city-council-working-on-healthcare-housing-and-historical-sites/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Chicago City Council is attempting to pass a paper, or even multiple papers, in regard to healthcare and housing in relation to migrants, and]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Chicago City Council is attempting to pass a paper, or even multiple papers, in regard to healthcare and housing in relation to migrants, and historical sites and bringing in revenue. A group discussion was held to hear what some had talked about when they had time for smaller group discussions. </p>



<p>On the historical sites aspect of the conversation, Ald. Rossana Rodriguez-Sanchez, 33rd, brought up how she wants to see how they can attempt to bring back the old tourism-based economy. On a similar note to that, Ald. Pat Dowell, 3rd, mentioned everything in historical sites should stay the same unless there is severe damage to a site, and at that point in time they will help to reconstruct it to make it almost, if not, the same. Revenue has also been mentioned by Ald. Brendan Reilly, 42nd, and the Ald. Andre Vasquez, 40th, mentioning that roughly $550 million worth of revenue can be generated from historical sites. </p>



<p>Ald. Dowell also noted that there should be more healthcare for migrants. In relation to that, Ald. Reilly mentioned how healthcare is a complex topic, but there is an ordinance that will soon be ready to be passed that can tie into such things like healthcare. </p>



<p>Yet another issue, which relates to migrants, is the issue of housing. It was brought up that drug use and addiction was one of the issues that related to homelessness in Chicago. Something that was brought up to help this issue of drug addiction is better healthcare options for people who are struggling with drug addiction. It has been agreed upon that getting help for this addiction can decrease the issue relating to homelessness, not only for migrants, but for others living in Chicago.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>BREAKING NEWS: Classified US Government Documents released to the Public</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/breaking-news-classified-us-government-documents-released-to-the-public/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 17:02:39 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=535</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[To our fellow Americans,&#160; This letter was drafted by Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson depicts the status of women in the eyes of the U.S.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>To our fellow Americans,&nbsp;</p>



<p>This letter was drafted by Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson depicts the status of women in the eyes of the U.S. Cabinet and Vice President. This letter was in response to the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women after they proposed multiple resolutions to address the labor standards of women, women&#8217;s civic engagement, and women’s engagement in the ongoing Missile Crisis in Cuba. To highlight some of his sentiments, he stated that the sentiments of the PCSW were not priorities, and the administration does not have the time to address any of these issues.</p>



<p>The women in America should not take elements of this letter and be content. The women in America should take this letter as an opportunity to prove to their governmental representatives that their contributions to the public sphere are still relevant to embody the capitalist values of our society.</p>



<p><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/k2LLD4vH6iG_JblqhSpS7QsFl6lsj-xA1Nq8CGOue96ary85kG9YWrti95zeUa6wg-fztL4HtSOOYSDmge2APDOfS56tYtsynR3JC_DMGzOxAPsU6RjT2FKPo9LubOa6dkEjcORgJqsKT6JUqrZ9Obi98ZavgddFmkZIYNaOczrI3aFtS7hyuom5QlUSKg" width="93" height="93"><img decoding="async" src="https://lh7-us.googleusercontent.com/9NG4gKNdsHHLkjYuYZtZWGnZdQI03dXQybaSSuIXeeYcNA_usYSBVFcvxgO8NW6CVW0gGiuxV6Iz5rU8EJyVO_aVxx3I1oSQ3VPCuDLORUw8Gq6rZ6otpPz0L8FXCl-eHAi-PV-AXTsq-h1zW6OCxhm7rFB-qqWKgvvxINpdOp6-38nkewZyZdMsdC0oWQ" width="160" height="84"></p>



<p>Letter from LBJ</p>



<p>Office of President John F. Kennedy</p>



<p>Washington D.C.<br>October 1962</p>



<p>_____________________________________________________________________________</p>



<p>October 1962, Washington D.C. &#8211;</p>



<p>While your input on policy has been appreciated previously. I have the unfortunate task of informing your commission that we currently cannot pursue your policies regarding women in the workplace. They may have some potential, but because of the events occurring in Cuba, the President does not have the time to review them.</p>



<p>Your commitment to our nation is admirable, and I have nothing but respect for Mrs. Roosevelt. However, while we struggle with a response to this crisis, we cannot spare any time to review this report.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Office of the Vice President of the United States of America</p>



<p>Vice President Lyndon B. Johnson</p>



<p>The letter, when delivered to Mrs. Roosevelt, the former first lady,&nbsp; <em>may</em> have contributed to her death, it seemed to have caused her weak heart to give out. Unfortunately, she passed away later that night, and America lost a national treasure. Now the American people are faced with a decision, will we tolerate her death? Will we let Mr. Vice President Lyndon B Johnson gets away with his disregard for women or will we stand up to him? <strong>America stands true today, and America will stand strong tomorrow, with women behind it.&nbsp;</strong></p>



<p>Concerned American Citizen</p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>What, if any, Roles can Women Play in Society?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/what-if-any-roles-can-women-play-in-society/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:54:43 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=521</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In 1962, the role of women in society is becoming more important. It is becoming more than just cooking, cleaning, and watching the children. The]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In 1962, the role of women in society is becoming more important. It is becoming more than just cooking, cleaning, and watching the children. The role that they can play in society is now more important than it has been before. </p>



<p>Hon. Orville Freeman mentions how women can play a significant role in the Cold War between America and Cuba. We have men who are standing with women to want to help them become more active in American society. Working with other powerful women and men can help everyone achieve a common goal that they want, which is for women to have more roles within society. </p>



<p>As a group, the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women are working to see if they can introduce more women into the medical field, as well as the serving in the war if they so please. This would allow more empowerment within women, allowing them to be more confident to share their ideas; a critical perspective when considering the development of America. </p>



<p>Freeman also mentioned in an interview, “We believe that providing loans to women in entrepreneurship would enhance network and collaboration between women and those collaborations could be channeled into civic duties.”</p>



<p>Providing loans to allow women to be able to experience different professions will allow them to want to be more active in society. This is important because whether or not you need people to be more active in society, if they are not willing to do it, less people will want to be active in society. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Senators are Voting Against Their Own Views</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/senators-are-voting-against-their-own-views/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many United States senators have gathered in an attempt to discuss their opposing views, similar views, and create resolutions to solve their issues that they]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Many United States senators have gathered in an attempt to discuss their opposing views, similar views, and create resolutions to solve their issues that they are combating. Senator Mike Mansfields has mentioned, “Some senators have lost sight of that given power that they have, they are working with the interest of their own minds and not the the best of the people.” Allowing yourself to stay in line and work for what is best for the people is critical in this position, which some are clearly struggling to do. </p>



<p>Senator Humphrey, who was previously the majority whip, was not present, so it was elected by the rest of the senate that Senator Johnston would be whip, to cover in his absence. The responsibility of the whip is to keep everyone in line so they are following policy, which is important information to note. “There have been some conflicts that Senator Johnston has been involved in, but in the end, some senators, like Senator Young from Ohio, have been working across the aisle with Republican minorities, instead of working with democratic Allies,” Mansfield mentioned in an interview. It is already being seen that the whip who was elected is already working with opposing parties, which sparks the question, is that someone who you want to be representing your party? </p>



<p>Mansfield has been able to work around, listening in on what others are doing and saying, and has had many resolutions to the issue at hand, an example of one of the people who are staying in line, as one should be doing. A quote from Mansfield, “I went and worked with Senator Adkin of Vermont and we wrote a paper on agriculture that just passed. Other bills we have passed, in regards to our first topic which was innovation, and industrialism and developing the American interior, all four bills passed, which they don’t directly step over each other, but they do.” Mansfield has passed many bills, further showing that he is one of the few that can stay in line, as the senate should be doing. </p>



<p>There have been resolutions passed by both the Republican and Democratic Parties, two specific ones being written in part by Senator Young, and another by a Republican senator; both passing with 27 votes. But, it was seen that opposing parties were voting with papers that were from the opposing parties, which were directly seen in this situation. This is causing conflict within the Democratic Party because it is not allowing them to vote properly because some are voting for Republic papers that have opposing views to what they are trying to pass. </p>



<p></p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X Comes Forward with New Updates to the App; How Will They Move Forward?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/x-comes-forward-with-new-updates-to-the-app-how-will-they-move-forward/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 03:02:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=380</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[X, previously known as Twitter, is now providing the world with more updates. Elon Musk took over the app and has re-named it X, but]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>X, previously known as Twitter, is now providing the world with more updates. Elon Musk took over the app and has re-named it X, but as the X representative explained, there is a new update to the app, and it is now called, X Connect. The X representative has announced the first round of beta testing that X and that the app is now accessible is many countries across the world. </p>



<p>The X representative stated how, “X AI is used to flag false information.” There are opposing view on this opinion stated by the X representative by the U.S.A. representative. While X is saying that false information will be flagged, the U.S.A. is warning others to watch what they post on X. </p>



<p>X representative said, “X maps is something that we have never seen before.” Yet, most mobile phones, whether Apple, Samsung, or Google, have some sort of maps app. So why is implementing a map setting into an app on a phone that already has a map built in? It is nothing that we have not already seen before. </p>



<p>“Our goal is to create an easy use for the user,” X representative shared. Yet the X Connect app is only slightly the same as the original Twitter app that was used before the purchase from Elon Musk. The new features are just getting father off from the original app that everyone did love. </p>



<p>The new X Connect app that is being proposed is using AI technology within the app, which has already been discussed negatively by a large population of the public. There have also been some new proposed features that are taking away from the social media aspect of the app, which would seem to take away from the connect aspect of the app that the X representative tried make everyone aware of. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>How Can Climate Change be Stopped?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/how-can-climate-change-be-stopped/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:55:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly Plenary]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=334</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Climate change is not a new problem. It&#8217;s been an ever-growing issue since back in 1988 with the depletion of the ozone layer. It has]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Climate change is not a new problem. It&#8217;s been an ever-growing issue since back in 1988 with the depletion of the ozone layer. It has continued to grow and has had lasting effects on the economy. Some of these effects can be seen through unbalances in weather, and the increase in temperatures throughout the years.</p>



<p>These increasing temperatures have also affected the production of food, which has had an increase in hunger and a decrease in nutrition. Heat can diminish water, which also can lead to droughts, which are creating more deserts and people are facing threats of not having enough water. Along with the talk of water, these temperatures can affect the amount of rainfall, increasing the frequency of storms, landslides, and destroying homes, which is costing billions of dollars to repair. Along with that, climate change is making ice sheets melt, which is making the ocean levels rise, which can be threatening to islands and communities on those islands. </p>



<p>A representative from India shared, “Holding countries accountable and allocating our resources and funds towards combating climate change.” Most countries have their own contributions to climate change, but holding them accountable can help stop this threatening issue. </p>



<p>“All of us have established a climate goal and not all of us are meeting it. That’s an issue.”, the representative from India mentioned. Most countries have brought up the issue of climate change, it is whether or not they actually exceed the standards to actually attempt to stop climate change. </p>



<p>“Seeing why they can’t meet their goals and giving them resources to allow them too,” which was also mentioned by the delegate from India. India is willing to help and wants to make sure that countries, even their own country, has the needed resources to put a stop on climate change. </p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago City Council passes widespread ordinance to address public safety, mental health, community events</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/chicago-city-council-passes-widespread-ordinance-to-address-public-safety-mental-health-community-events/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 21:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=284</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A new ordinance has passed sponsored by Alds. Coleman, Nugent, Sigcho-Lopez, Waguespack, Napolitano, Rodriguez, Ramirez-Rosa, Vasquez, Hidden, Burnett, Cardona, Harris, Taylor, Mitts, Reilly, Gardiner, Silverstein,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A new ordinance has passed sponsored by Alds. Coleman, Nugent, Sigcho-Lopez, Waguespack, Napolitano, Rodriguez, Ramirez-Rosa, Vasquez, Hidden, Burnett, Cardona, Harris, Taylor, Mitts, Reilly, Gardiner, Silverstein, Taliaferro, and Villegas. This ordinance having 19 sponsors and 8 sections within it has passed after an open vote. </p>



<p>The ordinance is known as BULLS, which stands for bonding us locals like superglue. This ordinance first mentions funding for municipal marketing, wanting to bring together more community events, allowing and wanting more small business owners to partake in events, as well as some government profit from some public events, so that money can go back towards the city. To stay on the topic of government, that section also mentions that government figures should also be allowed to have 50 percent off of event tickets. </p>



<p>The following section mentions better, and more training of police officers so Chicago can have officers that represent their city well. The following section has talked about better safety techniques for the public, which can follow along with the previously mentioned section. </p>



<p>Section five of this ordinance mentions how treatment should better be implemented for mental health matters within the city. Section six is looking for infrastructure improvement, and can be related back to section five in a subsection that mentions the distribution of security cameras. </p>



<p>The following section is looking to implement a better relationship with the youth and police force within society, including more programs for the youth audience. The final section of this ordinance wants public and social transparency. </p>



<p>This paper wanted to further implement public safety and good relations within the communities, and after being passed, it can now do so. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
