<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Ella Cho, Jerusalem Post &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/author/echo/feed/?simply_static_page=1360" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 14:57:21 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Food scarcity and the &#8220;Root of All Evil&#8221;</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/food-scarcity-and-the-root-of-all-evil/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ella Cho, Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 03:26:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (Present Day)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1220</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Tensions rose between the U.S. and Russia while the UNSC discussed the global food scarcity crisis. Russia’s invasion of Ukraine has only served to worsen]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Tensions rose between the U.S. and Russia while the UNSC discussed the global food scarcity crisis. </p>



<p>Russia’s invasion of Ukraine has only served to worsen the global food crisis. Much of the world is reliant on Ukrainian grain and the war has severely impacted Ukraine’s ability to export goods. </p>



<p>The representative from the U.S. feels strongly that food security cannot be achieved until the war in Russia and Ukraine is resolved. The representative even went as far as to claim Russia’s invasion of Ukraine is “the root of all evil” and “the direct cause” of the global food crisis. Russia, on the other hand, holds an opposing stance. </p>



<p>“Food security is not possible until western encroachment ends,” the representative of Russia stated. </p>



<p>When asked if the U.S. will continue to provide military aid to Ukraine knowing this information, the representative of the U.S. answered yes. The U.S. feels passionately that they and NATO have an obligation to protect the freedom of Ukrainian people. </p>



<p>When questioned about Russia’s involvement in the world hunger crisis, the Russian representative said, “the root of this crisis is NATO encroachment and western imperialism.”</p>



<p>Russia feels that until western forces stop intruding on Russia’s sovereignty, the international food security issue will be incredibly difficult to solve. Russia, in fact, finds the U.S.’s involvement in the Ukrainian-Russian conflict, “deeply concerning” and claims they are only exacerbating the already dire conditions. Who is truly to blame for the ongoing food crisis is unclear, what is incredibly clear though is that millions of lives are continuing to be lost due to starvation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Kenya in a Food Crisis</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/kenya-in-a-food-crisis/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ella Cho, Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:32:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (Present Day)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=826</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Kenya, along with the majority of other African countries, is experiencing one of the worst food crises in decades. The food crisis is a result]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Kenya, along with the majority of other African countries, is experiencing one of the worst food crises in decades. The food crisis is a result of numerous factors: Kenya’s extreme droughts, the COVID-19 pandemic, and the ongoing war between Ukraine and Russia, which combined account for more than 40% of Africa’s grain supply. The effects of food insecurity are devastating. “3.5 million Kenyans are experiencing extreme hunger. Roughly one person, in Kenya, Ethiopia, or Somalia, will die of starvation every 48 seconds”, the representative from Kenya said. Malnutrition poses as an even greater threat to already vulnerable populations and nearly one million children under five years of age and pregnant or breastfeeding women are experiencing malnutrition, said the World Food Programme.</p>



<p> Death isn’t the only side effect of food scarcity. According to the International Federation of Red Cross, also known as the IFRC, the hunger crisis in Kenya has caused, “higher rates of child marriage, increased school drop outs and escalating conflicts as people try to cope and access precious resources”. Food scarcity has massive ripple effects across the country and will continue to wreak havoc in Kenya as a result. The food crisis only appears to be getting worse as the number of Kenyans in need of urgent food assistance increased five-fold between August of 2020 and June of 2022 the World Food Programme reported. </p>



<p>Ultimately, the hunger crisis in Kenya, and other African countries, is a dire issue which can no longer go ignored. This situation must become a priority for the UNSC before millions of lives are lost to starvation. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
