<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>United Nations Security Council (1982) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/category/united-nations-security-council-1982/feed/?simply_static_page=1241" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:22:53 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>The U.K. conquers Argentinian Falklands territory</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/the-u-k-conquers-argentinian-falklands-territory/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dia Murali, Buenos Aires Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 16:53:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[House of Commons of the United Kingdom (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Opinion]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Britain&#8217;s brutalization of Argentinian forces over the occupation of the Falklands seems to have inflated the egos of House of Commons representatives. They callously deem]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Britain&#8217;s brutalization of Argentinian forces over the occupation of the Falklands seems to have inflated the egos of House of Commons representatives. They callously deem this conflict as an &#8220;economic opportunity&#8221; and discuss plans to initiate a war with Argentina. The consensus of the body establishes that &#8220;war is imminent&#8221; and slanders Argentina by deeming the country as &#8220;aggressors.&#8221;</p>



<p>It is confirmed by a House of Commons member that the U.K. is working to &#8220;preemptively&#8221; attack Argentina. The only justification for this is Argentina&#8217;s supposed antagonizing of the U.K., which was merely a question of Argentina defending their rightful territory. This proposition of extreme violence serves as a statement to establish that the U.K. is &#8220;the greatest country in the world&#8221; and that &#8220;if war is what it takes to prove it, so be it.&#8221;</p>



<p>The Conservative Party in the House is working on a paper named &#8220;Beating Argentina Badly Efficiently&#8221; to begin militarizing the Falklands in an attempt to intimidate and bombard Argentina. The aggressively named paper is being kept under wraps to avoid attention from other nations—especially the U.S. The U.K. is looking to convert current residents of the Falklands to British citizens and extend U.K. infrastructure. Establishing a 45,000 strong military presence in the Falklands will serve to help Britain maintain its dictator-like control over the islands. The paper goes so far as to condone lethal violence and &#8220;extermination&#8221; against those &#8220;invaders&#8221; who oppose their reign.</p>



<p> </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The USSR&#8217;s Alleged Crimes</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/the-ussrs-alleged-crimes/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Molly Robson, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 02:46:29 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1218</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[When it comes to war crimes, how far is too far? The 1982 UNSC got into a heated debate this afternoon around the USSR&#8217;s actions,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>When it comes to war crimes, how far is too far? The 1982 UNSC got into a heated debate this afternoon around the USSR&#8217;s actions, both past and present. As stated on Twitter, the USA representative was vindictive in their assertions, stating that the USSR had committed crimes which had gone unpunished by other global powers. While the USA mainly cited the Soviet Gulags, Japan was quick to condemn communism and was immediately criticized by the Zairian representative. The Japanese may not be well-liked on the world stage, as they played a major role in colonialism as part of World War II. This involvement was brought up by the Zairian representative as an example of Japanese hypocrisy. Could Japan rebound from this and stay in good international standings? Earlier this morning, the US representative expressed their annoyance with the UNSC&#8217;s issue with &#8220;going in circles&#8221;. How long the Council can go in circles without coming to conclusions remains to be seen.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Has the UN Security Council gone soft against the USSR?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/has-the-un-security-council-gone-soft-against-the-ussr/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Campbell Wixted, Le Monde]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 01:07:58 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United Nations Security Council (1982) is currently debating the Russian invasion of Afghanistan. The United States of America is attempting to temporarily suspend the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large"><img decoding="async" width="1024" height="634" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-13-1024x634.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1201" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-13-1024x634.png 1024w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-13-300x186.png 300w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-13-768x476.png 768w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-13.png 1200w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">United Nations Security Council 1980</figcaption></figure>



<p><br>The United Nations Security Council (1982) is currently debating the Russian invasion of Afghanistan. The United States of America is attempting to temporarily suspend the USSR from the Security Council on the grounds of violation of the Geneva Convention. The USSR retaliated to this idea by threatening to wage war on the United States due to policy differences. The United States has answered as peacefully as possible, that they want to remain peaceful and secure the nation of Afghanistan.</p>



<p>However, finding a resolution that most of the representatives in the council can agree upon is proving to be a difficult task. </p>



<p>&#8220;We are going in circles,&#8221; said a representative from the USA. </p>



<p>The council is frustrated between reckoning with opposing views. The U.K. is neutral, Poland doesn&#8217;t support force against USSR, Zaire believes the U.S. should stop supporting the Mujahideen, China is in favor of stopping the war and the USSR plans to continue opposition, despite plans from global superpower the USA alleging that the USSR has committed war crimes.</p>



<p>Additionally, the U.S. and Japan are the only nations wishing to punish the USSR for their criminal actions. The remainder of the Security Xouncil refuses to condemn the Soviet&#8217;s action. Begging the question has the world lost its strength against the USSR? Even if the U.S. is the lone actor seeking action against Russia, the U.S. will act. The U.S. will stop at nothing to see communism fall and the USSR lose influence across the world.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Japan Appeals for Nuclear Policy Change</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/japan-appeals-for-nuclear-policy-change/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Dia Murali, Buenos Aires Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 19:18:20 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Soviet Union (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1982)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=880</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Let Japan&#8217;s pain serve as a lesson to all countries considering nuclear warfare.&#8221; &#8211; UNSC Representative of Japan As evidenced by the aftermath of Hiroshima]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<blockquote class="wp-block-quote">
<p>&#8220;Let Japan&#8217;s pain serve as a lesson to all countries considering nuclear warfare.&#8221;                                 </p>
<cite> &#8211; UNSC Representative of Japan</cite></blockquote>



<p>As evidenced by the aftermath of Hiroshima and Nagasaki, no other country is as uniquely positioned to understand the significance of nuclear weapons as Japan. The UNSC Representative of Japan discusses the need for a revision in the globe&#8217;s attitude towards nuclear warfare in an exclusive interview. The rapidly growing desire of many nations to increase their nuclear stockpiles is more than enough cause for concern. Instead of addressing how to control the usage of such destructive weaponry, Japan argues that the focus should be on abolishing the use of nuclear weapons entirely. </p>



<p>&#8220;Japan has experienced the wrath of atomic warfare firsthand. Turning to nuclear violence is always the worst possible option; all nations, whether they are directly involved in the conflict or not, suffer from the consequences.&#8221; To state the issue plainly, Japan believes that no countries should have access to nuclear weaponry at all. The general reason behind nations working to increase their collections of arms is because said nations are seeking ways to defend themselves from other countries with nuclear weapons. As one country&#8217;s arsenal increases, another country does the same out of the fear of attack.</p>



<p>If the possibility of nuclear attack is negated entirely, then there would be no need for any state to fear such a large scale attack. The back and forth paranoia would greatly diminish. Some may argue that nations need to have access to nuclear weapons in order to deter others from attacking, but if there are <em>no weapons</em> to attack other countries with, then the threat reduces greatly across the board. Any country who actively stands by nuclear proliferation must have an ulterior motive—what other reason is there to support such violent methods?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Security Council Progress</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/security-council-progress/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Molly Robson, Fox News]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 18:31:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1001</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Security Council has mainly been focused on the resolution of the conflict between Iran and Iraq. During committee sessions today and yesterday, they began]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-5.png" alt="" class="wp-image-1013" width="839" height="629" srcset="/ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-5.png 400w, /ipd-archive/XIX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/image-5-300x225.png 300w" sizes="(max-width: 839px) 100vw, 839px" /><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Combat on the ground in the Middle East (Encyclopedia Britannica)</figcaption></figure>



<p>The Security Council has mainly been focused on the resolution of the conflict between Iran and Iraq. During committee sessions today and yesterday, they began the construction of a working paper to attempt both ceasefire and humanitarian aid. As the US representative stated during Thursday&#8217;s session, &#8220;progress is what [we] hold so dear&#8221;. This progress that the US has been fighting for so fiercely is coming closer and closer, as the Security Council becomes potentially ready to pass its working paper. Zaire&#8217;s representative was very focused on the UN&#8217;s ability to send humanitarian aid to affected regions, while the larger powers were more interested in creating an effective ceasefire. This comes at an important moment in the diplomatic proceedings – during yesterday&#8217;s press conference, the Iraqi representative was asked about the potential for Iraq&#8217;s nuclear development. The representative chose not to comment on the matter, which raises some questions about their future plans for the conflict.</p>



<p>Fox News</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
