<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Janean Edmond, The Times (South Africa) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2022/author/jedmond/feed/?simply_static_page=179" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2022</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 19:16:18 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>On this Sunday: Sunday world news update</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/on-this-sunday-sunday-world-news-update/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janean Edmond, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 19:07:31 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=733</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On this Sunday there seems to be many updates on what has been happening around the world! The international community has been faced with many]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-full is-resized" datatext=""><img decoding="async" src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/09BAB155-6E80-47DD-B312-D405BFA8E7A1.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-756" width="619" height="484" srcset="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/09BAB155-6E80-47DD-B312-D405BFA8E7A1.jpeg 381w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/09BAB155-6E80-47DD-B312-D405BFA8E7A1-300x235.jpeg 300w" sizes="(max-width: 619px) 100vw, 619px" /></figure>



<p>On this Sunday there seems to be many updates on what has been happening around the world! The international community has been faced with many different challenges and situations! Let’s see how these different groups have handled these crises!</p>



<p>United States Cabinet:</p>



<p>Ex CIA Director has been replaced with a deputy of CIA after having been fired, gone to trial and found guilty as a whistleblower. Ex-CIA director’s crime was leaked sensitive documents to the Chinese government and they are carrying out their sentence in Guantamo Bay. Most Cabinet members did not have nice things to say about the former CIA Director so it seems that the replacement of the CIA director is a win-win situation</p>



<p>United Nations Security Council:</p>



<p>The united nations security council seems split on how to handle the potential new nation in Belarus. A group led by Kenya and Mexico want to involve themselves in the new nation’s potential development to prevent further conflict, while the group of China and Russia are drafting legislation to remove themselves from the development of the new nation and be impartial with the goal of stopping conflict. Let’s see which plan works out!</p>



<p>Cabinet of China:</p>



<p>The Cabinet of China is successful in their cyber security attacks against the United States. China’s “green energy” plan  has also been revealed as a trojan horse plan to gain control and influence in the crumbling democracy of Belarus. <br></p>



<p>update:</p>



<p>China nukes everyone.</p>



<p>Cabinet of Russia:</p>



<p>The Russian cabinet has assassinated their leader Vladimir Putin. They also have been working on finding a replacement leader. Good luck to them</p>



<p>Cabinet of Germany:</p>



<p>Saturday Night the Cabinet of Germany was able to hear from two refugees on their experience of immigration. This morning when returning to Germany to report i was informed that they have changed their nation’s name to Nicki Minaj Nation of Barbz Leaders. They also threatened to conquer China!</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-full" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1001" height="975" src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/9BBF24C6-7BEF-4947-A989-BCCFA4905896.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-742" srcset="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/9BBF24C6-7BEF-4947-A989-BCCFA4905896.jpeg 1001w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/9BBF24C6-7BEF-4947-A989-BCCFA4905896-300x292.jpeg 300w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/9BBF24C6-7BEF-4947-A989-BCCFA4905896-768x748.jpeg 768w" sizes="(max-width: 1001px) 100vw, 1001px" /></figure>



<p>Cabinet of turkey:</p>



<p>The President of Turkey screamed at the Russian Cabinet ”take a big fat L” this morning. It is not known why this happened. In other news the Turkish Minister of Treasury and Finance was executed in response to his proposed coup against President Erdogan. <br></p>



<p>Bill and Melinda gates foundation: </p>



<p>The foundation accuses Pfizer of pocketing over 2 million dollars that was donated to them for vaccine distribution in developing countries.</p>



<p>Defense leadership forum:</p>



<p>Due to arguments between Lockhead Martin and U.S Rep Mike Rogers Lockheed Martin no longer sells to the United States.</p>



<p>That is all see you next Sunday!</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Emotional Testimony Shared by Belarusian Refugee</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/emotional-testimony-shared-by-belarusian-refugee/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janean Edmond, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 18:21:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Uncategorized]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=700</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[&#8220;Nobody has won everybody has lost&#8221; -Saif Raza Azim Two Belarusian refugees were welcomed by the Cabinet of Germany to share their emotional testimonies of]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p>&#8220;Nobody has won everybody has lost&#8221; -Saif  Raza Azim</p></blockquote></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="683" src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/B1698C58-F352-4B70-AD8D-4DE4DBA174C6-1024x683.jpeg" alt="" class="wp-image-729" srcset="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/B1698C58-F352-4B70-AD8D-4DE4DBA174C6-1024x683.jpeg 1024w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/B1698C58-F352-4B70-AD8D-4DE4DBA174C6-300x200.jpeg 300w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/B1698C58-F352-4B70-AD8D-4DE4DBA174C6-768x512.jpeg 768w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/B1698C58-F352-4B70-AD8D-4DE4DBA174C6-1536x1024.jpeg 1536w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/B1698C58-F352-4B70-AD8D-4DE4DBA174C6-2048x1366.jpeg 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>Past protest in Belarus led by Belarusian women.</figcaption></figure>



<p>Two Belarusian refugees were welcomed by the Cabinet of Germany to share their emotional testimonies of immigration. They both seemed hopeless for the situation in Belarus and pleaded with the German Cabinet members to look at the immigration crisis more humanely. </p>



<p>“We are not statistics,” shares Marina Pikic. Marina shared that most of her life she has been a refugee and she has lost her homeland and family and friends because of the political turmoil in Bosnia; even with her migration to Germany she still struggles to get adequate health care and is food insecure.</p>



<p>Another refugee that accompanied Ms. Pikic was Mr. Saif Raza Azim. He shared that he lost his wife and daughter and was not upset at their enemy but how inhumanely the world treated refugees.</p>



<p>Th experience last night of listening to both Saif and Marina should be a reminder to the international community that refugees are people and that policy should be considered with caution and care. </p>



<p>Germany had the privilege of meeting with the two refugees one on one. Could this affect their future immigration policies in the future?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>EU hurts refugee crisis in Turkey</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/eu-hurts-refugee-crisis-in-turkey/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janean Edmond, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 06 Feb 2022 01:29:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Federal Cabinet of Germany]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Cabinet of Turkey]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=635</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[I had the privilege to have one-on-one interviews with the minister of education in Turkey and the minister of social services. From both interviews I]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-image size-large" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="768" src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/30FCF152-D8ED-456D-9854-C94352209997-1024x768.png" alt="" class="wp-image-658" srcset="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/30FCF152-D8ED-456D-9854-C94352209997-1024x768.png 1024w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/30FCF152-D8ED-456D-9854-C94352209997-300x225.png 300w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/30FCF152-D8ED-456D-9854-C94352209997-768x576.png 768w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/30FCF152-D8ED-456D-9854-C94352209997-1536x1152.png 1536w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/30FCF152-D8ED-456D-9854-C94352209997-800x600.png 800w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/30FCF152-D8ED-456D-9854-C94352209997.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>The Sunday Times interviews the Minister of Family, Labor, and Social Services</figcaption></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="768" src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/C654CE69-54D4-4202-AC37-A3DA54B9F8E2-1024x768.png" alt="" class="wp-image-656" srcset="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/C654CE69-54D4-4202-AC37-A3DA54B9F8E2-1024x768.png 1024w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/C654CE69-54D4-4202-AC37-A3DA54B9F8E2-300x225.png 300w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/C654CE69-54D4-4202-AC37-A3DA54B9F8E2-768x576.png 768w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/C654CE69-54D4-4202-AC37-A3DA54B9F8E2-1536x1152.png 1536w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/C654CE69-54D4-4202-AC37-A3DA54B9F8E2-800x600.png 800w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/C654CE69-54D4-4202-AC37-A3DA54B9F8E2.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>The Sunday Times interviews the Minister of Education</figcaption></figure>



<p>I had the privilege to have one-on-one interviews with the minister of education in Turkey and the minister of social services. From both interviews I was able to learn how the refugee crisis in Syria and other countries has hurt Turkey’s services to its citizens. Though there has been directives that have helped with this crisis it is important to recognize how the EU has created this burden on Turkey. <br></p>



<p>Sunday Times: Why has Turkey added to directives clauses on refugee education?<br>Minister of Education: In countries like Syria that have a big outflow of refugees, the majority of the refugees have migrated to neighboring nations specifically Turkey. Disappointingly, many families are traveling to Turkey, which has hurt social services in Turkey because of the number of people who are now utilizing these services. Turkey is a small country though powerful and does not have the infrastructure to support these people.</p>



<p>Sunday Times: How has Turkey’s relationship with the EU affected the refugee crisis?</p>



<p>Minister of Education: The European Union is very stingy with the number of refugees they allow into their borders. They havent helped much in terms of relief or allowing people into their nations to take the burden off Turkey. </p>



<p>Sunday Times: I&#8217;m sorry to hear that! How has COVID affected the number of refugees Turkey has seen? </p>



<p>Minister of Education: Due to COVID, Turkey has been forced to close their borders a few times, which has caused the number of refugees to decrease. However, COVID has made the means of immigration more unsafe. Most refugees are not vaccinated against COVID or potentially bring it with them. Refugee sites specifically have had high number of COVID cases. </p>



<p>Sunday Times: What are solutions Turkey has been focusing on with the refugee crisis?</p>



<p>Minister of Social Services: Turkey has worked on directives that increase social service access to refugees and increased the budget for these services.</p>



<p>Sunday Times: Good to hear there have been strides hopefully other countries step up to help with this crisis!</p>



<p>Update:</p>



<p>Turkey&#8217;s Minister of Foreign Affairs and Germany&#8217;s Minister of foreign affairs organized a meeting between the two nations to discuss refugee issues. Turkey ends up upset with the indifferent of reaction of Germany. The cabinet of Germany believes the EU and themselves have done enough to aid the crisis. Both countries leave unhappy.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="768" src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/E0EC2C53-A095-49FE-AF58-7B5ED8CAC054-1024x768.png" alt="" class="wp-image-663" srcset="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/E0EC2C53-A095-49FE-AF58-7B5ED8CAC054-1024x768.png 1024w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/E0EC2C53-A095-49FE-AF58-7B5ED8CAC054-300x225.png 300w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/E0EC2C53-A095-49FE-AF58-7B5ED8CAC054-768x576.png 768w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/E0EC2C53-A095-49FE-AF58-7B5ED8CAC054-1536x1152.png 1536w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/E0EC2C53-A095-49FE-AF58-7B5ED8CAC054-800x600.png 800w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/E0EC2C53-A095-49FE-AF58-7B5ED8CAC054.png 2048w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /><figcaption>German officials left in shock after meeting with Turkey goes well</figcaption></figure>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China’s race to Taiwan</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/chinas-race-to-taiwan/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janean Edmond, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:17:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Ministries of the People’s Republic of China]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=504</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[“The East is rising but the West is declining” Xi JINPING China is working hard to develop their economy, technology, and geopolitical influence to become]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="CHINA UPDATE" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Nixm0Ks4m3w?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-pullquote"><blockquote><p><br>“The East is rising but the West is declining”</p><cite>Xi JINPING</cite></blockquote></figure>



<p>China is working hard to develop their economy, technology, and geopolitical influence to become a global superpower. So far the progress they have made in these developments include a military preparation and development plan, New China Financial Gain Plan, and an action plan to take over Taiwan. </p>



<p>Phew, sounds like a lot right!! Well let me break it down for you!</p>



<h2 id="new-china-financial-gain-plan">New China Financial Gain Plan</h2>



<p>China’s economy is the second largest in the world and is projected to become the largest by 2030. The GDP and economic success of China is a form of political legitimacy with its citizens. China’s cabinet has created plans to further economic advancements and success within China. The plan outlines points of increased taxation, machine investments, and more.</p>



<h2 id="military-preparation-development-plan">Military Preparation &amp; Development Plan</h2>



<p>Chinese cabinet members have drafted a multifaceted resolution that helps the country grow its militaristic power and capabilities. The government has designated leftover money from Belt and Road investments to be invested in China’s Military budget. There were also proposals made to create a new military division called the Special Military Engineering division: that works on aerospace military research. There are also plans to build new military technology &#8212; specifically fighter jets &#8212; and a new destroyer fleet. What is driving China to increase military investment and research? Taiwan.</p>



<h2 id="taiwan">Taiwan</h2>



<p>The goal of China is to reunite with Taiwan and for them to be ruled under China. There are plans being developed by China’s cabinet to further take over the island. Simply, China is working to infiltrate the country with propaganda, create a political party and nominate a puppet leader, create cyber attacks, and once that has all taken place fulfill a military invasion with Chinese troops. China seems set on reuniting with Taiwan and is not afraid of using aggression to get what they want.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>INTERVIEW: Secretary of Defense Austin on China-US relations</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/interview-secretary-of-defense-austin-on-china-us-relations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janean Edmond, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 20:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Cabinet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe loading="lazy" title="Sunday Times of South Africa does virtual interview with Secretary of Defense of US Cabinet" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/32IY-4JdvGI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UN Security Council to the rescue in Tigray</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/un-security-council-to-the-rescue-in-tigray/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janean Edmond, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 18:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (Present Day)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United Nations Security Council is working diligently to develop solutions that combat the war in Ethiopia. Many of the nations of the Security Council]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The United Nations Security Council is working diligently to develop solutions that combat the war in Ethiopia. Many of the nations of the Security Council have close relations with Ethiopia and recognize that the problems in Ethiopia can and will directly affect international relations as well as their own nation.&nbsp;The Security Council has two groups that are working to merge their ideas together to effectively aid refugees and prevent further violence with the Tigray conflict.</p>



<p>“The United States of America and their allies are dedicated to resolving the issue of confronting Ethiopia,&#8221; said a representative from the United States. &#8220;The country of Ethiopia is being plagued by political conflict with many human violations taking place. The United States condemns any acts that result in a violation of human rights. The United States has and will give humanitarian assistance to those affected by the situation in Ethiopia.”</p>



<p>The United States is working with Mexico, Kenya, India, and Iran to draft legislation to create a nongovernmental organization focused on refugee safety and work with existing organizations to give humanitarian aid for items like food and water. Other Security Council members had similar ideas and additionally proposed that Russia stop selling weapons to Ethiopia and send military troops into Ethiopia to prevent additional violence. It is clear that the United Nations Security Council is dedicated to stopping the Tigray conflict in Ethiopia and aiding citizens in Ethiopia. The international community should look towards further development of these plans and the execution of these ideas.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/3947/15592141515_ab951ea2b7_b.jpg" alt="" width="724" height="1089"/><figcaption>Ethiopian family in a refugee camp</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
<br />
<b>Notice</b>:  ob_end_flush(): failed to send buffer of zlib output compression (0) in <b>/home/public/news/wp-includes/functions.php</b> on line <b>5279</b><br />
