<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Caleb Renner, Ha&#8217;aretz &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/author/crenner/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 05:58:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>UN will not allocate military or humanitarian resources to India</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/13/un-will-not-allocate-military-or-humanitarian-resources-to-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 04:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=648</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amidst the unbelievable drama surrounding the Sino-Indian conflict, everyone is left wondering what will happen next. Following a visit to the United Nations Security Council,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Amidst the unbelievable drama surrounding the Sino-Indian conflict, everyone is left wondering what will happen next. Following a visit to the United Nations Security Council, a vote among all members resulted in only one representative voting to give military resources to India while all 10 others voted no. Consequentially, a nearly unanimous vote to send humanitarian aid to India has been vetoed by the Republic of China, resulting in the U.N. not reserving any resources to the Indian Council. </p>



<p>The Republic of China, independent from the People&#8217;s Republic of China and which does not have U.N. representation, accepted an interview where they shared some important information about how the cabinet has been acting on the issue. Both nations China and India continue to be shocked by each other&#8217;s actions with their militaries and hatred towards both sides is building up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is the Senate being shut out, or are they separating themselves?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/is-the-senate-being-shut-out-or-are-they-separating-themselves/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 21:48:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=525</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Concerns have arisen as multiple senators express their displeasure with the lack of communication between branches of the United States government. Several new resolutions presented]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Concerns have arisen as multiple senators express their displeasure with the lack of communication between branches of the United States government. Several new resolutions presented before the Senate emphasize better and more frequent levels of communication between the executive and legislative branches, but also dart between numerous topics.</p>



<p>The U.S. Senate has struggled to come to conclusions on major topics as the subject of debate shifts continuously, but valuable arguments are still being made. Civil rights and checks and balances float around the room while Senators talk about what is most important for the country. However, the consensus proves to be that immediate action needs to be taken on the rights of women and all people of color. Even then, the two groups in desperate need of civil rights protections cannot seem to be agreed upon.</p>



<p>Cooperation seems to be absent and agreement is rarely occurring in any part of the debate, even though nearly all senators share the view of the vitality of the topics. The priorities of the Senate remain questionable seeing that conversations within the chamber have no majorly effective results. As stated by more than one Senator, the allocation and protection of these rights to minority groups is imperative, and it is clear that the Senate, while indecisive, is determined to create conclusions. The future of social inequality remains anticipated yet uncertain.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Is JFK Under the Threat of Impeachment?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/is-jfk-under-the-threat-of-impeachment/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:44:56 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=401</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a majority Democratic yet visibly divided Senate, Senators are heavily struggling to reach any sort of agreement over how to take action on the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a majority Democratic yet visibly divided Senate, Senators are heavily struggling to reach any sort of agreement over how to take action on the intensifying Cuban Missile Crisis, and debates have even led to an angry proposition that President John F. Kennedy be impeached. It is no longer just party differences that are causing splits between views, as senators representing the same party express contradicting opinions on what to do about Cuba. Solutions and objectives repeatedly contradict each other while various senators give speeches to the Cabinet. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-image"><img fetchpriority="high" decoding="async" width="1600" height="1025" src="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-519" srcset="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81.jpg 1600w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-300x192.jpg 300w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-1024x656.jpg 1024w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-768x492.jpg 768w, /ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/4b1adba12c9ec3326adb979fd4fdbe81-1536x984.jpg 1536w" sizes="(max-width: 1600px) 100vw, 1600px" /></figure>



<p>After listening to the opinions of a few Democrats, it seems that de-escalation of the crisis appears to be a popular idea amongst the Democratic party. On the other hand, Republicans desire to push for greater protection of American citizens from any expansion of communism and the Cuban Missile Crisis onto American soil and to raise funds for fighting the Cold War effort.</p>



<p>According to the Democratic Senator of Wisconsin, William Proxmire, &#8220;All of the members of the Senate are trying as hard as they possibly can to regain citizens&#8217; trust and restore public faith in the Senate.&#8221; Following up on the scandals concerning the political and ideological associations of some Senators, it is clear that they strongly wish to make up for what has happened. Proxmire emphasized that he would like to call upon every Senator to do what is best for all Americans despite political beliefs, and that peace is the priority to negotiate for.</p>



<p>It has additionally been noted that amplifying involvement in the crisis would be far too costly for the United States, seeing that we, as a nation, are still recovering from some economic recessions coming back from war. Considering all this, the Senate has yet to pass anything regarding the Cuban Missile Crisis, and leaves Americans increasingly anxious over the tomorrow of the United States.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago City Council passes ordinance unanimously</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/chicago-city-council-passes-ordinance-unanimously/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:26:35 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=277</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Chicago City Council has been discussing solutions for the levels of societal interaction and the general conditions in the city boundaries, particularly about the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Chicago City Council has been discussing solutions for the levels of societal interaction and the general conditions in the city boundaries, particularly about the public and the police. The safety of the people has been a top concern throughout all meetings, leading to debates about the overall relationship between Chicagoans and the police. The BULLS (Bonding Us Locals Like Superglue) ordinance promotes diverse relations with the Chicago PD, including with youth and with people of color, and pushes forward greater levels of public transparency along with safer infrastructure and technology.</p>



<p> Sponsor Ald. Anthony Napolitano, 41st, commented, &#8220;I am very proud to see my fellow aldermen recognizing and addressing the issue of public relations with the police department, and I am hopeful that this will not just improve relations with the police in Chicago but that this will inspire other cities to follow suit.&#8221; </p>



<p>Chicagoans should be proud to see their alderpersons proving their strong dedication to their beloved city, trying their best to improve standards of life and safety across the city. All alderpersons have been working on providing the most productive solutions possible and are acting as efficiently as they can. Some of the more specific parts of the resolutions that had been passed were creating programs for the spread of mental health awareness among both parents and children, adding lighting along alleys and streets to make people feel safer, recruiting more people of color into the police and fire departments to better reflect the demographics of the community as a whole.</p>



<p>Several more actions will be initiated based on the BULLS ordinance that will enhance the perceptions and interactions of not just Chicagoans but citizens across the U.S., and there is a lot of anticipation for seeing how efficiently this will play out. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Interview with the Secretary of Agriculture in the Presidential Commission on the Status of Women</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/07/interview-with-the-secretary-of-agriculture-in-the-presidential-commission-on-the-status-of-women/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 07 Dec 2023 03:42:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=84</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-video"><video controls src="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Caleb-Renner-interview-first-assignment.mov"></video></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		<enclosure url="/ipd-archive/XX23/wp-content/uploads/2023/12/Caleb-Renner-interview-first-assignment.mov" length="88715318" type="video/quicktime" />

			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
