<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>PD Committees &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/pd-committees/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:56:45 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>U.S. cabinet: cry for action</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/u-s-cabinet-cry-for-action/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Richa Sharma, Times of India]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:56:44 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=651</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The U.S. cabinet had recently called upon a representative from the UN Security Council regarding the matter involving Taiwan. The cabinet started with suggestions for pressuring China with the situation in Taiwan, and the proposal of possible sanctions which the UNSC is open to was discussed. </p>



<p>The U.S. cabinet currently already has ships in Japan for a diplomatic presence in the region, moving forward with sanctions they feel will be the most effective way Additionally, they feel that these harder sanctions will pressure China about their wrongdoings and have more international pressure about correcting their wrongs. </p>



<p>The representative from the UNSC had advised that there is a firm reason for these sanctions on China, and that the body does whatever they can in significance with their cause, supporting Taiwan. </p>



<p>Later on, in the press conference, the United States cabinet, madam Press Secretary had explained that the United States was shocked by China’s reaction to the call for a revote. The U.S. has time and time again reached out to the PRC yet has received no response, but the PRC was reported to barge into the U.S. cabinet&#8217;s closed session when it was “most convenient for them.” China’s sudden aggression within Taiwan now gives the U.S. reason to believe that there is heavy Chinese involvement, as their own social media platform, Tencent has also been explicitly spreading disinformation that directly influenced the results of the election. </p>



<p>The cabinet has also called upon the UNSC to help with the current issues within Taiwan, specifically the corruption seen within the election and the democracy impeded from within it. Additionally, they have coordinated asking for how the UNSC will choose to move forward with China’s actions as the U.S. government specifically will no longer be contacting the Chinese government due to the “disrespect of sanctity diplomacy.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>An intercepted source has also let us know that China is threatening the U.S. and threatening to get rid of some things that are unknown in regard to the U.S. The U.S. economy also is thriving and has no further need for China. </p>



<p>Furthermore, in an interview with UN Ambassador Linda Thomas Greenfield, “The U.S. is trying their best in order to help Taiwan as the United States has empathy for all and they are heavily focused on the economy to help our citizens. Alongside this, we are arranging a meeting with the U.S. delegation from the Security Council as their input is valuable.”</p>



<p>The response from the UNSC is still being awaited and more developments will continue as debate on the next steps to be taken continue.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PRESS CONFERENCE: United States is Shocked China&#8217;s Actions</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/press-conference-united-states-is-shocked-chinas-actions/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:53:01 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the People's Republic of China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=645</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After a press conference, where both the United States and China were in attendance, new information has come out about what is going on between the two countries. The U.S. representative has sensed some aggression from China, also shown through how they have allowed themselves to come into meetings with no prior conversation. </p>



<p>The United States has further commentary on the fact that China has said they do not want forgiven involvement at the moment because of any possible influence on their election. Yet, the United States mentioned how the Chinese app, Tencent,  is spreading misinformation and has directly influenced China’s election. Showing that even with no current foreign relations, there are still direct influences on their election via the country’s social media app. Was it really worth it to cut connections with other countries that have not had an influence when you country has had an influence first? </p>



<p>Due to the previous actions that China has taken, the United States feels that China is rejecting any possible diplomatic offers. Furthermore, the U.S. has called upon the United Nations Security Council to help deal with these issues in China and even Taiwan as it is going to be needed to keep international peace between countries. After coordinating with the U.S. Security Council representative, the U.S. is urging the most powerful peacekeeping body in the world to help to deal with China’s actions as quickly and as effectively as possible. Now, the United States will no longer be in contact with the China government because of all the previously mentioned issues and that they have disrespected diplomacy. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X is Getting Sued? What Will Happen Now?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/x-is-getting-sued-what-will-happen-now/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:32:42 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=627</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[X Corporation, owner of the social media platform formerly known as Twitter and currently developing X-Connect, is currently being sued by the U.S. government. They]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>X Corporation, owner of the social media platform formerly known as Twitter and currently developing X-Connect, is currently being sued by the U.S. government. They say they have nothing to hide, but, if they have nothing to hide, what is the real reason for them getting sued? The X representative said that they have not had government involvement because of the issues that are surrounded with it, but they are not involved and are having issues with that same government. </p>



<p>They say that they are still committed to the development of the X-Connect app while following regulations and focusing on innovations even after this information of them being sued. After a U.S. cabinet meeting in which an A.I. implication was brought up, the U.S. government and X each threatened to sue the other entity. So they say that they have no government relations, yet still talk to the U.S. cabinet? That is directly going against what the X representative said they were doing. How are you able to go against your own words?</p>



<p>Even though they are receiving an abundance of backlash and are in the midst of getting sued, X Corporation is still attempting to further develop their app. Which also raises the question, will that affect the amount of users that will use their X-Connect app? They have said that they are going to continue to control their app because they have trust in their own systems, and as of now have no further comment on the situation.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China Expresses Discontent With an Article They say is &#8220;Unrepresentative of Our Beliefs&#8221;</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/china-expresses-discontent-with-an-article-they-say-is-unrepresentative-of-our-beliefs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the morning of Dec. 9, 2023, The Times of India published a piece on China recently using it&#8217;s veto power within the United Nations]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On the morning of Dec. 9, 2023, The Times of India published a piece on China recently using it&#8217;s veto power within the United Nations Security Council (UNSC) to vote against providing humanitarian aid for the for the Russia-Ukraine war. &#8220;This is a blatant example of poor press from the Times of India&#8221; says the Chinese delegation.</p>



<p>In interviews with both the Washington Post and Xinhua State News Agency, China explained that the delegation has every right to execute its veto powers in the UNSC whenever the state deems it necessary and that the veto was used in this instance specifically due to China believing that the Security Council should be diverting more of it&#8217;s time to the development of peace talks. In a sense, China seeks to pour more funding into preventing additional conflict between the nations, rather than simply supplying the band-aids to heal those affected by it.</p>



<p>China expressed to the Post directly that it was actually disappointed in the direction that the UNSC has been moving in and that &#8220;the lack of action from the Security Council to even issue a statement requesting peace talks is honesty a tragedy in and of itself and reflects extremely poorly upon the UNSC, especially when aid packages have already been sent before.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>PRESS RELEASE: The Chicago City Council</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/press-release-the-chicago-city-council/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ari Ramjit, Pan African News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:13:54 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=608</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Ald. Reilly, 42nd, spoke out about breaking news following the passed ordinances and the achievements that the Chicago City Council have accomplished during their committee]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Ald. Reilly, 42nd, spoke out about breaking news following the passed ordinances and the achievements that the Chicago City Council have accomplished during their committee sessions. </p>



<p>&#8220;The government is actually passing ordinances. We&#8217;ve had a variety of topics from addressing the migrant housing and homelessness, address city cleanliness that we all know metropolitan areas desperately needs, we&#8217;ve also addressed municipal marketing and even something about the Chicago Bears. We are now addressing topics about health care, guns and public safety.&#8221; </p>



<p>&#8220;All of these issues, which have been on topic vote for so long have been brought towards with collaboration between myself and other Ald. Additionally, we have made progress on other pressing national issues that have a relationship with the community. We have put old geriences aside and put needs to our constitutions first as our governments should.&#8221; </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who Can Be Trusted?: Tencent Disregards Accusations of Spreading Misinformation on Taiwanese Election</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/who-can-be-trusted-tencent-disregards-accusations-of-spreading-misinformation-on-taiwanese-election/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 21:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a run-in with an anonymous source from the Tencent Corporate Board (TNCT), the Washington Post was able to gather that a response to the allegations]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a run-in with an anonymous source from the Tencent Corporate Board (TNCT), the Washington Post was able to gather that a response to the allegations of spreading misinformation about the Taiwanese election. Tencent made it clear that the Chinese tech conglomerate stands by the results of the election and expresses wishes for the nations of the world to respect said results as well.</p>



<p>The source claimed that the accusations against Tencent are simply due to negative US sentiments held against China and its enterprises, leading to finger-pointing whenever the western press sees fit. </p>



<p>Especially in a world where the truth can be so easily manipulated by those in power and of influence. The Washington Post stands with the publications and journalists internationally that practice their craft ethically, and contribute their energy to the fight of bringing life to the truth, no matter the issue or stakes at hand</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago City Council: Updates from Alderperson Pat Dowell from Ward Three</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/chicago-city-council-updates-from-alderperson-pat-dowell-from-ward-three/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 21:54:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=577</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Updates on what has been going on within the past few days have been shared from Alderperson Pat Dowell from Ward three. This includes updates]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Updates on what has been going on within the past few days have been shared from Alderperson Pat Dowell from Ward three. This includes updates on recent bills that were passed, historical sites, the education system, and the migrant situation throughout Chicago. </p>



<p>Today, there was a bill passed that Dowell was included in that will allow Chicago to bring some of the historical sites back to life. It was mentioned how there was some concern in structural changes, but, it was reassured that no exterior structural changes would be made to any historical structures, and that the interior would be dealt with by the private investors. The main structural changes that would be made would be if there is serious damage to the site. </p>



<p>More recently, there is a bill in the works that relates to mental health awareness in students and teachers. As well as awareness to any issues in relation to bus drivers, which not detail was given on. Other important issues that Dowell is currently looking into and discussing is the issue of environmental education. </p>



<p>After working with Alderperson Nicole Lee from the eleventh ward, the pair were able to pass a bill relating to the migrant situation. This bill aims to reuse old buildings that can be quickly fixed up into housing. This would be a short term solution that would be implemented until a longer term solution is found for this crisis. </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago City Council ordinance calls on feds to provide work authorization for migrants</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/chicago-city-council-ordinance-calls-on-feds-to-provide-work-authorization-for-migrants/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ari Ramjit, Pan African News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:58:07 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=343</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Alds. Sigcho-Lopez, Gardiner, Villegas, Sposato, Reilly and Vasquez from the Chicago City Council have now formally passed an ordinance known as FAM or Federal Aid]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Alds. Sigcho-Lopez, Gardiner, Villegas, Sposato, Reilly and Vasquez from the Chicago City Council have now formally passed an ordinance known as FAM or Federal Aid to Migrants emphasizing the importance of housing for migrants to Chicago and suggesting community involvement and support.</p>



<p>Previously, there have been debates on what topic should be discussed during committee and after consideration and voting, topic 3 municipal marketing has been chosen. In the passed ordinance, they deeply described how pushing for migrant work visas in sanctuary cities, citizen involvement, federal intervention and access to safe temporary housing is important.</p>



<p> &#8220;The FAM plan is mainly for pushing the youth to have a more supporting environment in Chicago and especially making sure the next generation doesn&#8217;t have the same struggles as the ones that just migrated. We&#8217;re putting a heavy focus on real estate and abandoned buildings,&#8221; Ald. Sigcho-Lopez, 25th, stated in an interview regarding the FAM paper.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago City Council passes ordinance to improve cleanliness and reduce pollution</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/chicago-city-council-passes-ordinance-to-improve-cleanliness-and-reduce-pollution/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ari Ramjit, Pan African News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:53:59 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=456</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[During the committee today, Alds. Cardona, Sposato, Ramirez-Rosa, Taylor, Villegas, Gardiner, Reilly, Sigcho-Lopez and Napolitano wrote a paper addressing the fact that Chicago is not]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>During the committee today, Alds. Cardona, Sposato, Ramirez-Rosa, Taylor, Villegas, Gardiner, Reilly, Sigcho-Lopez and Napolitano wrote a paper addressing the fact that Chicago is not the cleanest city. </p>



<p>The passed paper included detailed topics on convention establishment, speakers, environmentally beneficial inventions, pollution’s effect on Chicagoans, funding, revenue, pest control, cleaning patrol and pricing.</p>



<p>Alds. Ramirez-Rosa, Cardona, Taylor and Sposato started the green convention and were supported by every delegate besides one. &#8220;We are establishing a green convention that will take place at McCormick Place where issues such as environment and city cleanliness will be discussed,&#8221; Ramirez-Rosa stated in an interview.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Chicago City Council working on healthcare, housing, and historical sites</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/chicago-city-council-working-on-healthcare-housing-and-historical-sites/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 20:49:45 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Chicago City Council]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=547</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Chicago City Council is attempting to pass a paper, or even multiple papers, in regard to healthcare and housing in relation to migrants, and]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Chicago City Council is attempting to pass a paper, or even multiple papers, in regard to healthcare and housing in relation to migrants, and historical sites and bringing in revenue. A group discussion was held to hear what some had talked about when they had time for smaller group discussions. </p>



<p>On the historical sites aspect of the conversation, Ald. Rossana Rodriguez-Sanchez, 33rd, brought up how she wants to see how they can attempt to bring back the old tourism-based economy. On a similar note to that, Ald. Pat Dowell, 3rd, mentioned everything in historical sites should stay the same unless there is severe damage to a site, and at that point in time they will help to reconstruct it to make it almost, if not, the same. Revenue has also been mentioned by Ald. Brendan Reilly, 42nd, and the Ald. Andre Vasquez, 40th, mentioning that roughly $550 million worth of revenue can be generated from historical sites. </p>



<p>Ald. Dowell also noted that there should be more healthcare for migrants. In relation to that, Ald. Reilly mentioned how healthcare is a complex topic, but there is an ordinance that will soon be ready to be passed that can tie into such things like healthcare. </p>



<p>Yet another issue, which relates to migrants, is the issue of housing. It was brought up that drug use and addiction was one of the issues that related to homelessness in Chicago. Something that was brought up to help this issue of drug addiction is better healthcare options for people who are struggling with drug addiction. It has been agreed upon that getting help for this addiction can decrease the issue relating to homelessness, not only for migrants, but for others living in Chicago.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
