<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>United Nations Security Council (1962) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/category/historical-committees/united-nations-security-council-1962/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 05:58:03 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>UN will not allocate military or humanitarian resources to India</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/13/un-will-not-allocate-military-or-humanitarian-resources-to-india/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Caleb Renner, Ha'aretz]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 14 Dec 2023 04:50:08 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Union Council of Ministers of the Republic of India (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=648</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Amidst the unbelievable drama surrounding the Sino-Indian conflict, everyone is left wondering what will happen next. Following a visit to the United Nations Security Council,]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Amidst the unbelievable drama surrounding the Sino-Indian conflict, everyone is left wondering what will happen next. Following a visit to the United Nations Security Council, a vote among all members resulted in only one representative voting to give military resources to India while all 10 others voted no. Consequentially, a nearly unanimous vote to send humanitarian aid to India has been vetoed by the Republic of China, resulting in the U.N. not reserving any resources to the Indian Council. </p>



<p>The Republic of China, independent from the People&#8217;s Republic of China and which does not have U.N. representation, accepted an interview where they shared some important information about how the cabinet has been acting on the issue. Both nations China and India continue to be shocked by each other&#8217;s actions with their militaries and hatred towards both sides is building up.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Senators are Voting Against Their Own Views</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/senators-are-voting-against-their-own-views/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Kaitlin Ritchie, Chicago Tribune]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 15:39:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=508</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Many United States senators have gathered in an attempt to discuss their opposing views, similar views, and create resolutions to solve their issues that they]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Many United States senators have gathered in an attempt to discuss their opposing views, similar views, and create resolutions to solve their issues that they are combating. Senator Mike Mansfields has mentioned, “Some senators have lost sight of that given power that they have, they are working with the interest of their own minds and not the the best of the people.” Allowing yourself to stay in line and work for what is best for the people is critical in this position, which some are clearly struggling to do. </p>



<p>Senator Humphrey, who was previously the majority whip, was not present, so it was elected by the rest of the senate that Senator Johnston would be whip, to cover in his absence. The responsibility of the whip is to keep everyone in line so they are following policy, which is important information to note. “There have been some conflicts that Senator Johnston has been involved in, but in the end, some senators, like Senator Young from Ohio, have been working across the aisle with Republican minorities, instead of working with democratic Allies,” Mansfield mentioned in an interview. It is already being seen that the whip who was elected is already working with opposing parties, which sparks the question, is that someone who you want to be representing your party? </p>



<p>Mansfield has been able to work around, listening in on what others are doing and saying, and has had many resolutions to the issue at hand, an example of one of the people who are staying in line, as one should be doing. A quote from Mansfield, “I went and worked with Senator Adkin of Vermont and we wrote a paper on agriculture that just passed. Other bills we have passed, in regards to our first topic which was innovation, and industrialism and developing the American interior, all four bills passed, which they don’t directly step over each other, but they do.” Mansfield has passed many bills, further showing that he is one of the few that can stay in line, as the senate should be doing. </p>



<p>There have been resolutions passed by both the Republican and Democratic Parties, two specific ones being written in part by Senator Young, and another by a Republican senator; both passing with 27 votes. But, it was seen that opposing parties were voting with papers that were from the opposing parties, which were directly seen in this situation. This is causing conflict within the Democratic Party because it is not allowing them to vote properly because some are voting for Republic papers that have opposing views to what they are trying to pass. </p>



<p></p>



<p></p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Navigating the Cuban Missile Crisis: Diplomatic Dilemmas and the Turkish Predicament</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/navigating-the-cuban-missile-crisis-diplomatic-dilemmas-and-the-turkish-predicament/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Swadha Garnaik, BBC]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 18:56:51 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=161</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In the midst of the Cuban Missile Crisis, the U.S. Cabinet is grappling with the challenge of addressing Soviet missiles in Cuba while delicately managing]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In the midst of the Cuban Missile Crisis, the U.S. Cabinet is grappling with the challenge of addressing Soviet missiles in Cuba while delicately managing relations with their NATO ally, Turkey. Key quotes from Cabinet members reveal the complexities of diplomatic strategies during this difficult situation.</p>



<p>One proposal discussed was the removal of U.S. missiles from Turkey in exchange for the withdrawal of Soviet missiles from Cuba. However, the Cabinet debated how to approach this delicate issue. While there was determination to address the Turkish missile situation, the debate also acknowledged the unequal nature of the Cuban and Turkish arsenals. Members recognized that the situations were not equivalent and proposed relocating missiles to ensure Turkey&#8217;s security. The plan included providing military personnel to address Turkey&#8217;s defense needs while addressing the core issue of missile removal.</p>



<p>The Secretary of the Treasury emphasized economic considerations, expressing that the United States &#8220;cannot afford to ostracize Turkey and antagonize key allies at this time&#8221;. Instead, the suggestion was to seek Turkey&#8217;s consent for missile removal, accompanied by a proposal for reimbursement of naval and soldier expenses. This approach aimed to maintain regional stability while avoiding unnecessary strain on international alliances.</p>



<p>Conversely, the U.N. Ambassador urged against displaying weakness in negotiations. She advocated for a mutually beneficial deal, implying commitment to peaceful relations and reduced tensions. The Ambassador cautioned against outright succumbing to the demands, favoring a strategic compromise that benefited both parties.</p>



<p>However, not everyone in the Cabinet favored compromise. Some argued against any concession, fearing it would be perceived as weakness. They advocated for a firm stance to protect U.S. interests and the integrity of the NATO alliance.</p>



<p>The Cabinet&#8217;s discussions during the Cuban Missile Crisis underscore the delicate diplomatic balance required to address the crisis without alienating critical allies. The U.S. government is seeking a solution that balances the interests of all parties, recognizing the need for strategic compromise and the imperative to avoid direct military confrontation. Decisions made during this critical moment will shape international relations and set the stage for future negotiations between superpowers.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Friday Liveblog (Historical)</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/friday-liveblog-historical/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Michael McCarthy, Deputy USG for Media]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:05:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical Committees]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Presidential Commission on the Status of Women (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (1962)]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=191</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
