<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>JSC Sukhoi Company &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2021/category/jsc-sukhoi-company/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2021</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Wed, 10 Feb 2021 01:37:20 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=5.6.1</generator>
<site xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">188894732</site>	<item>
		<title>Tony Soprano becomes new CEO of Sukhoi-TMC Task Force</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/tony-soprano-becomes-new-ceo-of-sukhoi-tmc-task-force/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 18:53:40 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[For Fun]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[The Boeing Company]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=359</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[With former CEO of Tactical Missile Corporation Boris Obnosov appointed the new President of Belarus, the largest shareholder of the corporation, Tony Soprano (Big Tony),]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>With former CEO of Tactical Missile Corporation Boris Obnosov appointed the new President of Belarus, the largest shareholder of the corporation, Tony Soprano (Big Tony), was named the new CEO. The Italian mafia gained control of Sukhoi-TMC and now hope for  “the Russians to start becoming Italians” Soprano said. The corporation hopes to restore the glory of the mafia. </p>



<p>“In order to reclaim the Italian heritage, we must end the reign of Domino’s,” Smaller Tony said. The ministry is discussing the response to Boeing’s creation of a lightsaber business.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The new mafia-led ministry hopes to “start a civil war between Domino’s and Papa John’s and turn New Jersey into an empire” Soprano said. The ministry is joining the Boeing Corporation and repeating the mantra “HEY IM WALKING HERE” over and over to “assert their dominance,” Mafia Joe said.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">359</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Evidence of CIA involvement in Belarus: report</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/evidence-of-cia-involvement-in-belarus-report/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 01:47:21 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Central Intelligence Agency]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=310</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Sukhoi-TCM Ministry has discovered evidence of CIA involvement in Belarus that directly led to the presidency of Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya. The Joint TMC-Sukhoi ministry released]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Sukhoi-TCM Ministry has discovered evidence of CIA involvement in Belarus that directly led to the presidency of Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya. The Joint TMC-Sukhoi ministry released a statement to Russia Today, detailing their reaction and condemning the United States.</p>



<p>“The Joint TMC-Sukhoi taskforce, on behalf of the Russian Federation, would like to condemn the CIA and its affiliates for their manipulation and destabilization of the Belarusian region that has led to countless atrocities. We have well grounded evidence that they have taken these actions. Now is the time for the world to take a definitive stance in order to hold NATO accountable for their unethical actions. For far too long, the United States and their affiliates have undermined the sovereignty of developing and unstable countries and unjustly accused truthful nations of heinous acts. They have caused chaos and destruction. They have toppled governments and taken the lives of innocent bystanders. They have created opportunities for themselves by creating conflicts and disregarding the path of destruction they have left. The Joint TMC-Sukhoi taskforce is taking a stand against the tyranny of the West. We call our fellow nations in the East to stand with us as we condemn these perpetrators of countless meaningless wars.<br>With discontent,<br>Joint TMC-Sukhoi Taskforce of the Russian Federation”</p>



<p>The ministry has been outraged by the CIA involvement but they “are not surprised” according to Deputy McMahan, due to the past actions of American imperialism. The ministry is springing to action bringing forth directives for Putin to call on the U.N. to condemn the United States, calling for Sviatlana’s resignation, greater surveillance to protect against further unethical U.S. involvement, and mobilization of forces to ensure the security and safety of the Russian and Belarusian people.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">310</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia Planning Attack on Belarusian Government</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/russia-planning-attack-on-belarusian-government/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sun, 07 Feb 2021 00:50:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=301</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Members of Tactical Missiles Corporation and Sukhoi, currently under the control of the government of the Russian Federation, are deliberating actions to be taken against]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Members of Tactical Missiles Corporation and Sukhoi, currently under the control of the government of the Russian Federation, are deliberating actions to be taken against the current situation in Belarus. Executives are debating cyberattacks, a possibility of cutting communication networks or electricity, and the possibility of arming the public, which could incite an insurrection against the newly placed government. A speech by President Vladimir Putin in front of the United Nations has also been promoted by members of the board in order to inject Russia’s voice into the Belarusian matters.&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russian executives have also uncovered evidence of intervention by the Central Intelligence Agency, likely behind Sviatlana Tsikhanouskaya’s recent rise to power. This discovery has caused strong reactions among Russian executives, with some proposing the idea of war on the grounds of this involvement, with a near consensus regarding some type of action against the United States. Plans are in progress by Russian executives to launch a military offensive against Minsk, the capital of Belarus, in order to unseat the government and remove the influence of members of the North Atlantic Treaty Organization (NATO). Executives have developed a rough plan to deploy 100,000 troops to Minsk, along with a fleet of armored vehicles. The exact impacts of these movements remains unclear, but escalating and sustained unrest in Belarus is a near certainty.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">301</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russian government nationalizes Sukhoi and Tactical Missile Corporation</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/russian-government-nationalizes-sukhoi-and-tactical-missile-corporation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 23:38:05 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=261</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After the chaos in Belarus at the hand of the United States, Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin announced the formation of a new joint ministry]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After the chaos in Belarus at the hand of the United States, Russian Federation President Vladimir Putin announced the formation of a new joint ministry made up of the Sukhoi and Tactical Missile Corporation. The corporations are now nationalized and are under the direction of Putin.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The Deputy of Public Relations released a statement discussing the excitement of both corporations to now be a “part of the [Russian] national economic system”. The statement is as follows.&nbsp;</p>



<p>“The T.M.C. and J.S.C. Sukhoi is excited to announce that we are now national corporations,” the statement reads. “As national companies, we are now owned by the government. In our case, the Russian Government is part of the national economic system. The Russian Government is now in charge of both companies, with President Putin overseeing this new ministry’s operations. The previous C.E.O.s are now ministers in the Russian Government and all former executives are deputies. We would like to make it explicitly clear that both deputies and ministers will maintain their roles as vice presidents and consultants to the national company. The future of our companies are looking optimistic as there are a multitude of possibilities and improvements to be made.”</p>



<p>In addition, the new nationalized Joint Ministry commented on the growing violence in Bealrus and the United States involvement. In a second press release to Russia Today, the Joint Ministry condemned the U.S. actions and called for the America and NATO forces to withdraw.</p>



<p>“The new national company has learned that there is likely a presence of NATO or American forces stationed in Belarus. It deeply concerns the Russian Government and its people to see such a blatant disregard for Belarusian independence. The Russian Federation condemns all forms of western intervention and demands that American and NATO forces immediately withdraw from the country. Further Western involvement will only continue to destabilize the country and force the Russian Federation to take action. The Russian government will be left no other choice to pursue sanctions should western forces choose to not notify the Russian government of their intention to withdraw from Belarus as soon as possible upon receiving this press release.”</p>



<p>The Ministry is “not afraid to take action” Minister Freeman said to ensure the protection and security of the Russian people.&nbsp;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">261</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Russia Obtains Sukhoi and Tactical Missiles Corporation</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/russia-obtains-sukhoi-and-tactical-missiles-corporation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Nikki Maly, The Jerusalem Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:32:49 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=221</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[A temporary merger between Sukhoi and the Tactical Missiles Corporation has evolved, with the Russian Federation taking control of the two corporations. Sukhoi and TMC]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>A temporary merger between Sukhoi and the Tactical Missiles Corporation has evolved, with the Russian Federation taking control of the two corporations. Sukhoi and TMC will now work to execute the will of the Russian government, specifically moving in relation to the ongoing crisis in Belarus. Russian President Vladimir Putin, in a statement to the employees of the two companies, directed executives to take whatever action necessary to remove American presence in Belarus, saying that “anything and everything is on the table.”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Russian executives presented suspicion that Belarus is making moves towards NATO, with Minister Boris Obnosov stating that the presence of NATO troops in Belarus is “all but certain.” The disruption and crippling of the fragile new Belarusian government was encouraged by Putin, with his suggestions including cyberattacks and the bribery of officials. Putin urged the two companies to avoid military force, but to take any other steps to interfere with the presence of U.S. and other NATO officials within Belarus. At this time, multiple directives are being considered to take action on this front, but no concrete steps have been taken.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">221</post-id>	</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sukhoi Executives Respond to Anti-Russia Claims</title>
		<link>/archive/2021/sukhoi-executives-respond-to-anti-russia-claims/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Quinn Riordan, Russia Today]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 06 Feb 2021 21:10:26 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[JSC Sukhoi Company]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tactical Missiles Corporation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2021/?p=211</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While working with the Tactical Missile Corporation (TMC) to protect and ensure security for the Bealrusean people, Sukhoi was accused of “working with the Americans]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>While working with the Tactical Missile Corporation (TMC) to protect and ensure security for the Bealrusean people, Sukhoi was accused of “working with the Americans and being Anti-Russian”, by TMC CEO Boris Obnosov.&nbsp;</p>



<p>The actors who made this claim have not been identified and there has been no evidence found that corroborates this accusation. The Sukhoi Executives wanted to reassure the Russian Federation of their loyalty. The Sukhoi VP of Public Relations released a statement in response.</p>



<p>“In response to the heinous and baseless assertions made, claiming JSC Sukhoi is maintaining an “Anti-Russian” sentiment, the board first and foremost would like to say that we are appalled. The assertion that JSC Sukhoi, a historic and vital portion of Russia’s history, could turn against the motherland is absolutely absurd. Throughout our company&#8217;s history, we have done nothing but aid and support the motherland’s intentions. This statement is obviously an attempt to deface our company’s historic standing as an industry giant. To the group that made this statement, you do not hold any credibility. Your shallow attempt to destroy our companies standing is nothing but a feeble and shameful attempt to taint a respected Russian company. Your claim is baseless yet speaks volumes regarding your intentions. Our company never foresaw the day when we would have to reestablish our allegiance to the very government that created us, yet here we are. да здравствует родина Board of JSC Sukhoi”&nbsp;</p>



<p>Sukhoi has seemed to regain and maintain support by the Russian Federation with a new nationalization of their corporation by the Russian government. Sukhoi and the Tactical Missile Corporation have been merged and nationalized by President Vladimir Putin, after the US intervention in Belarus and the mounting conflict.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
		<post-id xmlns="com-wordpress:feed-additions:1">211</post-id>	</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
