<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Top Stories &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/archive/2022/category/top-articles/feed/?simply_static_page=160" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/archive/2022</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 23:23:31 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>WHO, Gates Foundation promote vaccine distribution in underdeveloped countries</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/who-gates-foundation-promote-vaccine-distribution-in-underdeveloped-countries/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miriam Israel, Buzzfeed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:54:30 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[World Health Organization (WHO)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=617</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Currently, Nigeria, Kenya, Paraguay, and Trinidad and Tobago are working together in the World Health Organization to create a resolution that would target the issue]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Currently, Nigeria, Kenya, Paraguay, and Trinidad and Tobago are working together in the World Health Organization to create a resolution that would target the issue of vaccine distribution within underdeveloped countries. After the EU passed over Nigeria for a grant that would have severely helped Nigeria create more vaccine manufacturing factories, the country decided to take matters into their own hands.</p>



<p>As the previously mentioned countries wait to hear back from the Bill and Melinda Gates foundation, their tentative sponsor, they have plans ready to be set in motion. These include the increase in the speed of the creation of current vaccine manufacturing and storage facilities that are being built in Kenya, more vaccine creation in these countries.</p>



<p>According to the Nigerian WHO delegate, “Nigeria would like to further the research toward its own COVID vaccine because we want to be more self-reliant and less at the whim of other countries,&#8221; according to the representative to WHO from Nigeria. This pandemic has made it known that we need to worry both about possible supply shortages and the current global enemy, the coronavirus.</p>



<p>As they move forward into committee session 3, this group is hopeful that their resolution will successfully pass. If it does indeed pass, these nations and their citizens will certainly thrive.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>WMUN – CIMUN News Radio Episode 2</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/wmun-cimun-news-radio-episode-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruchi Akula, Assistant Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:38:28 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=610</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speaker 1 0:06You’re Listening to WMUN- CIMUN News Radio This news update has been brought to you by the Duck and Cover! Parents, make sure]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-audio" datatext=""><audio controls src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/CIMUN-Podcast-4.mp3"></audio></figure>



<p><strong>Speaker 1 0:06</strong><br>You’re Listening to WMUN- CIMUN News Radio</p>



<p>This news update has been brought to you by the Duck and Cover!</p>



<p>Parents, make sure to teach your children the importance of Duck and Cover! In the event of total nuclear annihilation, you can trust that a school desk will keep your children safe from falling debris, right before they are vaporized! That’s right, in the event of an atomic detonation, get under the nearest piece of furniture and brace for the force of the sun in your backyard!</p>



<p>The New York Times received a transcript of an emergency military budget proposal president Truman sent to the senate in response to the growing red menace. The president requested that the Senate immediately approve a 100% increase in military spending in an effort to strengthen the military in response to the growing communist threat. But the senate rebuked the president, only approving a 75% increase.</p>



<p><strong>Speaker 2 1:03</strong><br>The senate has also approved a bill addressing the Korean conflict. It calls for armed neutrality, and approved funds for arming South Korea, as well as funds for humanitarian aid to displaced Korean citizens.</p>



<p>The New York Times is also reporting that an unnamed Chinese official has called for moving Chinese troops away from the Korean border due to health concerns.</p>



<p>Finally, the Chicago Tribune is reporting that the Red Scare is gripping the United States. The United States Representative to the UN Security council warned other countries the dangers of the so-called Domino Effect of countries falling to communism. U.S. Senator McCarthy has reportedly collected a list of more than 200 communists within the U.S., while others such as Senator Murray, caution against using this list without proper verification.</p>



<p><strong>Speaker 1 1:41</strong><br>This has been your NEWS on the Hour. Stay tuned to WMUN- CIMUN News Radio</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Nightcap Episode 2</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/the-nightcap-episode-2/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruchi Akula, Assistant Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 22:12:52 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=596</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Speaker 1 0:07Welcome back to the Nightcap, brought to you by the CIMUN Chronicle. Today’s World News Roundtable is brought to you by NFTs. For]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-audio" datatext=""><audio controls src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/CIMUN-Podcast-3.mp3"></audio></figure>



<p><strong>Speaker 1 0:07</strong><br>Welcome back to the Nightcap, brought to you by the CIMUN Chronicle.</p>



<p>Today’s World News Roundtable is brought to you by NFTs. For just a few hundred thousand dollars, you can buy a JPEG of an ape with a hat! How does it work you might ask? Simply buy an NFT, then get others to buy NFTs, thus increasing your ape’s value! How do you make money? Once enough people buy NFTs, you can cash out! Imagine a pyramid… uh I mean reverse funnel… of people buying cartoon apes, the more people under you, the more money you make! NFTs, Definitely not a pyramid Scheme. <em>results may vary</em></p>



<p><strong>Speaker 2 0:10</strong><br>Belarusian President Aleksandr Lukashenko released a statement saying that Russia has “spit in our face by unilaterally declaring territory in our country belongs to you,” He also declared that he will block Russia’s efforts to withdraw refugees from the border, and will reconsider their relationship with Russia.</p>



<p>In response, the Russian government released a statement apologizing for not consulting with Lukashenko before taking action involving the Iraqi kurds. Russia emphasized the importance of their relationship with Belarus, and cited their long standing cooperation, dating back to the time of the Soviet Union. Russia also cited the importance of their pipeline sovereignty, and indicated that they hope that Belarus will continue to be a partner on this project.</p>



<p>Meanwhile, President Biden put out a statement regarding his recent talks with Chinese President Xi. He accused the Chinese president of acting undiplomatically, and aggressively. He also called out the Chinese for reportedly launching cyber attacks on the US. He also called out the recent arrest of Bosnian Journalists, and called for freedom of the press to be respected. Milorad Dodik has arrested 7 Bosnian journalists who have been critical of his actions thus far.</p>



<p><strong>Speaker 3 1:45</strong><br>Buzzfeed is reporting The Turkish Minister of Energy and Natural Resources is attempting to pass an economic development plan similar to the former U.S. President Roosevelt’s New Deal. However, these efforts have stalled, as the council has focused mainly on military actions and classical economic sanctions.</p>



<p>As reported in the Sunday Times of South Africa, the United Nations Security council has been working on addressing the ongoing Tigray Conflict in Ethiopia. The United States has pledged to work with other nations in giving humanitarian aid to the region.</p>



<p>Finally, The U.S government has lost interest in Pfizer&#8217;s bioweapon in favor of the Defense Leadership Foundation&#8217;s new Nuclear Space Station. Pfizer&#8217;s stock has plummeted and been delisted from the NYSE; all balance sheets are inaccessible and the Gates Foundation has lost all hope of recovering losses</p>



<p><strong>Speaker 1 2:34</strong><br>Thank you for joining us tonight on the Nightcap, brought to you by the CIMUN Chronicle.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>North Korea is Invading, South Korea is on the run, and The U.S. Senate is too Busy Fighting Each Other to do Anything</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/north-korea-is-invading-south-korea-is-on-the-run-and-the-u-s-senate-is-too-busy-fighting-each-other-to-do-anything/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Zachary Steinhofer, New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 21:44:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1950)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=562</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[As per our previous report on the issue in Korea, the situation was tense, but in the last few hours the tension finally snapped and]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>As per our previous report on the issue in Korea, the situation was tense, but in the last few hours the tension finally snapped and a War is underway. Our reporter listening in to the Senate meetings watched live as reports poured in about the invasion of North Korea (one of these reports can be seen in the breaking news update below), causing the poor state of the Senate to get even worse. This poor state is a result of intense internal conflict, which culminated recently in the accusation of plagiarism against Senator&nbsp;Styles Bridges. But that is just a snapshot of the discord within the government body. </p>



<p>The situation escalated even further when President Truman himself showed up in Senate meeting, almost yelling at them as he informed them that their actions have been slow and had little effect on the worsening situation in Korea. Truman then proceeded to tell the Senate how disappointed he was that his military budget was not fully approved as our South Korean allies die in battle against the communist terror. </p>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">[NYTimes] BREAKING: Sources tell U.S. senate that, quote, &quot;President Syngman Rhee is evacuating Seoul as North Korean forces continue to flood into the Republic of Korea. North Korean capture of the city appears imminent and their forces are approaching&quot; the city</p>&mdash; CIMUN IPD (@cimun_ipd) <a href="https://twitter.com/cimun_ipd/status/1490067163432075273?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 5, 2022</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p>After the President left the meeting more reports came in reporting the Seoul had fallen, but the Senate continued to argue amongst each other. This time accusing each other of being communist spies. Senator Robert Taft is even quoted saying:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;Anyone could be a communist, even the President!&#8221; </p></blockquote>



<p>Senator Russel B. Long then stated that:</p>



<blockquote class="wp-block-quote"><p>&#8220;We need to remove these commies, and I think Mccarthy is SUS!&#8221;</p></blockquote>



<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-rich is-provider-twitter wp-block-embed-twitter"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<blockquote class="twitter-tweet" data-width="550" data-dnt="true"><p lang="en" dir="ltr">[NYTimes] BREAKING: The U.S. Senate receives another update: &quot;Seoul has officially fallen and the North Korean military continues to meet success as they advance further south.&quot;</p>&mdash; CIMUN IPD (@cimun_ipd) <a href="https://twitter.com/cimun_ipd/status/1490076078672592907?ref_src=twsrc%5Etfw">February 5, 2022</a></blockquote><script async src="https://platform.twitter.com/widgets.js" charset="utf-8"></script>
</div></figure>



<p><strong>South Korea is falling, but the U.S. senate can&#8217;t even trust each other</strong>.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>INTERVIEW: Secretary of Defense Austin on China-US relations</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/interview-secretary-of-defense-austin-on-china-us-relations/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janean Edmond, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 20:07:18 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[China]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Cabinet]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=524</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-embed is-type-video is-provider-youtube wp-block-embed-youtube wp-embed-aspect-16-9 wp-has-aspect-ratio"><div class="wp-block-embed__wrapper">
<iframe title="Sunday Times of South Africa does virtual interview with Secretary of Defense of US Cabinet" width="640" height="360" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/32IY-4JdvGI?feature=oembed" frameborder="0" allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture" allowfullscreen></iframe>
</div></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Turkish Cabinet stalled on development programs</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/turkish-cabinet-stalled-on-development-programs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Miriam Israel, Buzzfeed]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 17:50:19 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Presidential Cabinet of Turkey]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=462</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Turkish Minister of Energy and Natural Resources is attempting to pass an economic development plan similar to former U.S. President Roosevelt’s New Deal. Despite]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Turkish Minister of Energy and Natural Resources is attempting to pass an economic development plan similar to former U.S. President Roosevelt’s New Deal. Despite the ingenuity of this plan, which involves cleaning up waterways, limiting carbon emissions, and much more, she has been shut down as the council has focused mainly on military actions and classical economical solutions.</p>



<p>Simply put, these ministers are focusing on receiving monetary benefits in the short term, rather than focusing on long term advantage.</p>



<p>While the majority of Turkey’s Cabinet is searching for these ideas, the energy minister’s plan to promote the achievement of sustainable development goals within Turkey will also provide more jobs, thus stimulating its economic growth, which makes her plan all the more beneficial since it targets multiple points of interest. In the energy minister&#8217;s words, &#8220;I know this will work to stimulate the economy through increasing jobs, without increasing inflation because it has been done before,&#8221; she continues on, stating, &#8220;This solution will not only help solve the crises of Turkey’s Syrian refugees, climate change, and the economic downfall within Turkey, but it will also show other countries that Turkey wants to make a difference and that it cares about global issues.&#8221;</p>



<p>“If we want to no longer be treated as a laughing stock, we must look to tested, project-based plans that will make Turkey better for many years to come,&#8221; she continued. &#8220;Isn’t that the entire point of our work?”</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>The Nightcap Episode 1</title>
		<link>/archive/2022/the-nightcap-episode-1/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Ruchi Akula, Assistant Editor]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 15:10:48 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Podcast]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Top Stories]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/archive/2022/?p=442</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Transcript: Speaker 1 0:00 Hey everyone, welcome to The Nightcap, brought to you by The CIMUN Chronicle. Moving on to world headlines, a fistfight broke]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<figure class="wp-block-audio" datatext=""><audio controls src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/CIMUN-Podcast-1-2022.mp3"></audio></figure>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large" datatext=""><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" width="1024" height="512" src="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-1024x512.jpg" alt="" class="wp-image-446" srcset="/archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-1024x512.jpg 1024w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-300x150.jpg 300w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-768x384.jpg 768w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL-1536x768.jpg 1536w, /archive/2022/wp-content/uploads/2022/02/WM-CSL.jpg 2000w" sizes="(max-width: 1024px) 100vw, 1024px" /></figure>



<p></p>



<pre class="wp-block-preformatted"><strong><span style="text-decoration: underline;">Transcript:</span></strong>

<strong>Speaker 1  0:00 </strong> 
Hey everyone, welcome to The Nightcap, brought to you by The CIMUN Chronicle. 

Moving on to world headlines, a fistfight broke out at the border between Greece and Turkey on the partitioned island of Cyprus. Officials claim that Greek nationals protesting against Turkish companies drilling for oil have crossed the UN-enforced green line separating the island,  instigated by civilians, and set fire to dozens of buildings. They were detained and sent back across the green line. Dozens of injuries have been reported but nobody has been killed. 

In other news, some Turkish officials are becoming increasingly frustrated with President Erdogan. According to one anonymous minister,  "he's [Erdogan] not very effective and "he's not taking necessary steps to keep turkey stable". 

President Erdogan has fired the president of the Turkish Central Bank for his failure to stop the fall the Lira.

<strong>Speaker 2  0:42  </strong>
CIA reported the discovery of intercontinental ballistic missiles in the Gansu province of China, while Pentagon officials report China is rapidly increasing its capacity to develop nuclear warheads. 

Top Taiwanese Officials say, "Pooh Bear got crushed by a building" in reference to President Xi causing outrage on mainland China. 

The Wall Street Journal is reporting that President Xi made it very clear that he was upset and  "wants Taiwan to suffer".

<strong>Speaker 3  1:09 </strong> 
A Chinese national was reportedly injured in an accident at the Port of Hamburg in Germany. German-Chinese relations have been strained since Germany criticized China's human rights violations and Hong Kong's 2020 National Security Law. 

The Chinese national, Wang Xianwen, a Cargo Manager, and father of three is reportedly in critical condition. 

The times of South Africa's reporting that the UN Security Council is asking Russia to stop selling weapons to Ethiopia because of the worsening Tigray conflict. 

Similarly, Buzzfeed is reporting that several Russian officials have claimed that "NATO has been discriminating against Russia because NATO was created in a way that would end up turning certain countries against Russia and making them seem like an antagonist when they are not always the enemy. 

<strong>Speaker 1  1:56 </strong> 
And that's gonna do it for us today at the nightcap. Thank you all for joining us and we'll see you again tomorrow!

</pre>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
<br />
<b>Notice</b>:  ob_end_flush(): failed to send buffer of zlib output compression (0) in <b>/home/public/news/wp-includes/functions.php</b> on line <b>5279</b><br />
