<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>United Nations Security Council (Present Day) &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/2022/category/unsc/feed/?simply_static_page=98" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/2022</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 18:12:16 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>UN Security Council to the rescue in Tigray</title>
		<link>/2022/un-security-council-to-the-rescue-in-tigray/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Janean Edmond, The Times (South Africa)]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 05 Feb 2022 18:12:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (Present Day)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/2022/?p=411</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The United Nations Security Council is working diligently to develop solutions that combat the war in Ethiopia. Many of the nations of the Security Council]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The United Nations Security Council is working diligently to develop solutions that combat the war in Ethiopia. Many of the nations of the Security Council have close relations with Ethiopia and recognize that the problems in Ethiopia can and will directly affect international relations as well as their own nation.&nbsp;The Security Council has two groups that are working to merge their ideas together to effectively aid refugees and prevent further violence with the Tigray conflict.</p>



<p>“The United States of America and their allies are dedicated to resolving the issue of confronting Ethiopia,&#8221; said a representative from the United States. &#8220;The country of Ethiopia is being plagued by political conflict with many human violations taking place. The United States condemns any acts that result in a violation of human rights. The United States has and will give humanitarian assistance to those affected by the situation in Ethiopia.”</p>



<p>The United States is working with Mexico, Kenya, India, and Iran to draft legislation to create a nongovernmental organization focused on refugee safety and work with existing organizations to give humanitarian aid for items like food and water. Other Security Council members had similar ideas and additionally proposed that Russia stop selling weapons to Ethiopia and send military troops into Ethiopia to prevent additional violence. It is clear that the United Nations Security Council is dedicated to stopping the Tigray conflict in Ethiopia and aiding citizens in Ethiopia. The international community should look towards further development of these plans and the execution of these ideas.</p>



<figure class="wp-block-image size-large is-resized" datatext=""><img decoding="async" src="https://live.staticflickr.com/3947/15592141515_ab951ea2b7_b.jpg" alt="" width="724" height="1089"/><figcaption>Ethiopian family in a refugee camp</figcaption></figure>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
