<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Mira Polyakov, The New York Times &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/author/mpolyakov/feed/?simply_static_page=1363" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 18:42:51 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Sustainability! What are it’s goals?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/sustainability-what-are-its-goals/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mira Polyakov, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 04 Feb 2023 15:48:04 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1328</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[After making a visit to the UNEA, Iran, Tunisia, and India introduced their resolution about a more sustainable world. Green economies make a green world]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>After making a visit to the UNEA, Iran, Tunisia, and India introduced their resolution about a more sustainable world. Green economies make a green world right? These economies can provide a low-carbon, resource-efficient, and socially inclusive economy preventing the loss of biodiversity and ecosystem services. </p>



<p>Soon a switch will be made, superseding the irreplaceable non-renewable resources, to more valuable renewable resources. Renewable sources may include wind and solar power, biomass, and bioenergy which would strongly promote sustainability.  Following those, everything hydro comes into play, with hydro-energy, and hydro-thermal energy. But questions remain such as what body of water they plan to use, and what areas are deep enough underground?</p>



<p>With nuclear power our economy can be pushed 3 steps forward, the disposal of nuclear waste, the expansion of the power, and intense research for nuclear facilities all can help rid the atmosphere of harmful byproducts emitted by fossil fuels and significantly contribute to both the economic and environmental dimensions of sustainability. </p>



<p>The world is in good hands, let&#8217;s just hope this is not too good to be true.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Food insecurity takes over globally, where can migrants go?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/food-insecurity-takes-over-globally-where-can-migrants-go/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mira Polyakov, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:26:02 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council (Present Day)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1054</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The Russian invasion began on February 24, 2022, instigating the largest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II. Both Russia and Ukraine account for]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The Russian invasion began on February 24, 2022, instigating the largest refugee crisis in Europe since World War II. Both Russia and Ukraine account for a large proportion of global exports of wheat and grain and limiting those exports caused severe implications for countries around the world, inducing a refugee crisis. Now, food insecurity struggles have been made prominent in the present UNSC committee, presenting insight from several dominant countries. Refugees face the struggle for a safe place to go, luckily, the United Kingdom, United States, and Japan have come to the rescue.</p>



<p>“The U.S. will gratefully help any misplaced person, regardless of background,” said the representative of the United States. </p>



<p>Migrants have a safe land to rely on when they are escaping the upheaval of food insecurity and war in Ukraine. Through a detailed interview, the representative mentioned that the care provided for the new migrants depends on where they go, and the local governments but are generally protected under American rights. However, they made it clear that although anybody will be welcomed, precautions will be taken with Russian migrants or refugees who actively participated in the Russian military. </p>



<p>“The U.S. can safely take in around 10,000 immigrants and refugees.” said the representative. </p>



<p>Minding the carrying capacity and a strong hatred of the Russian empire, the United States wishes to protect its citizens and offer a new haven for people wishing to escape to a new place they’ll call home.<br>The United Kingdom offers an innovative approach with the idea of sponsors. </p>



<p>“U.K. residents can apply to be sponsors and receive 350 pounds every month to house the refugees that are coming, and we’ve taken over about 115,000 refugees in this manner,” said the representative from the United Kingdom. </p>



<p>Over the years, the United Kingdom has donated 150 million pounds; about 181 million dollars to these refugee services, allowing a new way of life. Reliance on imports directly from the Russian-Ukrainian trade is not particularly important in the United Kingdoms, yet, a total of 9.7 million adults have fallen to food insecurity. With solutions to improve this globally, a confident statement that refugees will be well-supported stands true, opening their arms to migrants.</p>



<p>The flow of refugees is inevitable, yet it can be reduced. Safety and management are key to a growing population, but will this flow ever stop?</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Where should Ukrainian refugees go?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/where-should-ukrainian-refugees-go/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Mira Polyakov, The New York Times]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Thu, 02 Feb 2023 17:09:47 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Cabinet of the United States of America]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Council of Ministers of the Russian Federation]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=816</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[The wave of migrants and refugees has persisted due to the crisis between Russia and Ukraine, and the upheaval of food insecurity in Africa. The]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>The wave of migrants and refugees has persisted due to the crisis between Russia and Ukraine, and the upheaval of food insecurity in Africa.  The international community will discuss the question: where should they go? The refugee crisis in Europe began in late February 2022, when the majority of 8 million refugees fled Ukraine to Poland. As this war continues, residents in both Russia and Ukraine will be forced to migrate globally for security. Each country has an obligation to provide asylum for someone escaping persecution, with concern for their economy and safety.</p>



<p>The African Union promotes their notion of an “integrated, prosperous and peaceful Africa, driven by its citizens and representing a dynamic force in the global arena,” where immigrants and refugees purpose this intent. However, Africa’s DRC and Congo face the struggle of food insecurity impacting a third of the country&#8217;s population, and creating a surge of internally displaced persons or IDPs. Luckily, the African countries of Gabon and Ghana open their arms to those who struggle and welcome many IDPs.</p>



<p>“For migration, we believe that it is necessary for a country to grow, however, safety is always in consideration,” said the representative of Ghana to the African Union.</p>



<p>Acceptance of migrants, refugees, and IDPs will support a growing population benefiting the country’s economy and GDP, they said.</p>



<p>With this in mind, the safety of the people is kept in consideration, as these immigrants bring new insight to the country. </p>



<p>“When it comes to the issue of immigration and asylum seekers, Gabon&#8217;s initial approach has always been to find the means to accommodate refugees while still ensuring the safety and security of official residents,” the representative from Gabon said.</p>



<p>Importance of understanding who is entering the country and for what reasons assures the safety<br>and security of the people living in it. As for the IDPs and refugees eluding hunger and war, they intend to improve their way of life. Every human being is entitled to a safe environment to live a secure lifestyle, and with the acceptance from countries for migrants, refugees, and IDPs, this lifestyle will be achieved.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
