<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Aaron Pryear, Washington Post &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XX23/author/apryear/feed/" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:58:24 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.4.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>LATEST FROM THE POST: Southern Democratic Senators Double Down on Their Stance and Address the Nation</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/latest-from-the-post-southern-democratic-senators-double-down-on-their-stance-and-address-the-nation/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:58:23 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Hist Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=659</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In an exclusive interview with the Washington Post, Democratic Senator Olin D. Johnston and his colleauges wished to provide us with a message for the]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In an exclusive interview with the Washington Post, Democratic Senator Olin D. Johnston and his colleauges wished to provide us with a message for the nation. The address reads as follows: </p>



<p>&#8220;Today I, Senator Olin D. Johnston, stand before members of the Press to address a very important matter. John Locke contended that if the government the people created in the state of nature violated the rights of the citizens and the set laws of the land, the right of revolution would entitle the people to use force to punish that government and depose its rulers. Today, In light of the drastic motions and efforts of the United States Federal Government related to the infringement of state’s rights, it is time that YOU, the people take initiative today, putting the power back in your hands.&nbsp;In accordance with the Second Southern Manifesto, and the Federal Government’s complete disregard of the statements within that document, the people must adhere to those same words of John Locke and impose the &#8216;right of revolution&#8217;. Align yourselves, and make your voices heard by marching to THE CAPITOL. If the United States Government isn’t willing to listen to the representatives of the people, let them hear from the people themselves. “</p>



<p>The colleagues supporting this address are senators Allen J. Ellender, Richard Russell Jr., Harry F. Byrd, Robert Byrd, and Herman Talmadge</p>



<p>The implications of this incitement of revolt are yet to be seen, and the Washington Post advises all Americans to stay alert as the situation develops.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>China Expresses Discontent With an Article They say is &#8220;Unrepresentative of Our Beliefs&#8221;</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/china-expresses-discontent-with-an-article-they-say-is-unrepresentative-of-our-beliefs/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 22:18:16 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United Nations Security Council]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=552</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[On the morning of Dec. 9, 2023, The Times of India published a piece on China recently using it&#8217;s veto power within the United Nations]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>On the morning of Dec. 9, 2023, The Times of India published a piece on China recently using it&#8217;s veto power within the United Nations Security Council (UNSC) to vote against providing humanitarian aid for the for the Russia-Ukraine war. &#8220;This is a blatant example of poor press from the Times of India&#8221; says the Chinese delegation.</p>



<p>In interviews with both the Washington Post and Xinhua State News Agency, China explained that the delegation has every right to execute its veto powers in the UNSC whenever the state deems it necessary and that the veto was used in this instance specifically due to China believing that the Security Council should be diverting more of it&#8217;s time to the development of peace talks. In a sense, China seeks to pour more funding into preventing additional conflict between the nations, rather than simply supplying the band-aids to heal those affected by it.</p>



<p>China expressed to the Post directly that it was actually disappointed in the direction that the UNSC has been moving in and that &#8220;the lack of action from the Security Council to even issue a statement requesting peace talks is honesty a tragedy in and of itself and reflects extremely poorly upon the UNSC, especially when aid packages have already been sent before.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Who Can Be Trusted?: Tencent Disregards Accusations of Spreading Misinformation on Taiwanese Election</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/who-can-be-trusted-tencent-disregards-accusations-of-spreading-misinformation-on-taiwanese-election/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 21:56:03 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[PD Ticker]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=553</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[In a run-in with an anonymous source from the Tencent Corporate Board (TNCT), the Washington Post was able to gather that a response to the allegations]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>In a run-in with an anonymous source from the Tencent Corporate Board (TNCT), the Washington Post was able to gather that a response to the allegations of spreading misinformation about the Taiwanese election. Tencent made it clear that the Chinese tech conglomerate stands by the results of the election and expresses wishes for the nations of the world to respect said results as well.</p>



<p>The source claimed that the accusations against Tencent are simply due to negative US sentiments held against China and its enterprises, leading to finger-pointing whenever the western press sees fit. </p>



<p>Especially in a world where the truth can be so easily manipulated by those in power and of influence. The Washington Post stands with the publications and journalists internationally that practice their craft ethically, and contribute their energy to the fight of bringing life to the truth, no matter the issue or stakes at hand</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Taiwanese Election Dispute: Department of Justice Sues X, Countersuit from X is Imminent</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/09/taiwanese-election-dispute-department-of-justice-sues-x-countersuit-from-x-is-imminent/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 08:21:11 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=479</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Following the KMT and DDP disputes that erupted within Taiwan over the legitimacy of the nation&#8217;s presidential election, the United States Department of Justice (DOJ)]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Following the KMT and DDP disputes that erupted within Taiwan over the legitimacy of the nation&#8217;s presidential election, the United States Department of Justice (DOJ) filed a lawsuit against social networking corporation X, on the grounds of violating the Sherman Antitrust Act. The Sherman Antitrust Act of 1890 is a United States antitrust law with statutes developed by governments to protect consumers from predatory business practices and ensure fair competition.</p>



<p>X, in defense of it&#8217;s name and absolutely appalled by the accusations against the corporation, has successfully launched a countersuit against the DOJ. The verdict of this countersuit is undoubtedly one to track over the coming days as developments arise.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>New X, New Problems?: X Loses Two Board Members and Takes on Three in Replacement</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/new-x-new-problems-x-loses-two-board-members-and-takes-on-three-in-replacement/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 04:28:14 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Tencent Corporate Board]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=418</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Elon Musk has made his decision. At approximately 9:15pm on Dec. 8, 2023, X saw two of its board members promptly resign upon the announcement]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Elon Musk has made his decision. At approximately 9:15pm on Dec. 8, 2023, X saw two of its board members promptly resign upon the announcement of Mr. Musk possibly taking members off the board himself. These members were the Director of Marketing and Director of Operations, and upon their resignation they donated all of their stocks to the charity foundations backed by Elon Musk. In their replacement, the X corporate board added a Director of Investments in addition to a Department Chair of IT. </p>



<p>Furthermore, rival company Tencent has gained 10% of X&#8217;s shares in a previous transaction with Vanguard, an investment management company. Due to Tencent holding at least a 10% share within the corporation, they have earned themselves a seat at the table of X&#8217;s corporate board, one with the additional right to cast votes that can held guide the course in which things go for the corporation</p>



<p>Now, X struggles yet again with internal issues that could prove detrimental to the security of the board as an American corporation as well as users of X and X-Connect.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X in Distress?: Suspicions Over a &#8220;mole&#8221; Within the X Corporate Board Erupt to Unforeseen Heights</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/x-in-distress-suspicions-over-a-mole-within-the-x-corporate-board-erupt-to-unforeseen-heights/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 03:29:36 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=382</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Earlier today, the Washington Post received an anonymous tip on a member of the board planning to use legal loopholes in order to expedite user]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Earlier today, the Washington Post received an anonymous tip on a member of the board planning to use legal loopholes in order to expedite user data to foreign nations such as China. This has now erupted into an all out finger-pointing war within the corporate board room. Only time will tell what happens next as Elon Musk himself comments that he will take it upon himself to decide the fate of the board.</p>



<p></p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>LATEST FROM THE POST: Conservative Southern Democrats Make Their Voices Heard</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/latest-from-the-post-conservative-southern-democrats-make-their-voices-heard/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 03:28:24 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=390</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Over the past few years, the United States government has made significant pushes in the direction of improved civil rights and breaking down gender-based disparities.]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Over the past few years, the United States government has made significant pushes in the direction of improved civil rights and breaking down gender-based disparities. However, Democratic Senator Olin. D. Johnston believes that in doing so, the government on several occasions has infringed the rights of individual states and their constitutional ability to create laws the reflect the views of their people. </p>



<p>This is why he, alongside other conservative democrats from the south, have drafted the Declaration on States Rights and Constitutional Principals, also known as the &#8220;Second Southern Manifesto&#8221;. This  manifesto stresses the importance of recognizing how badly state sovereignty has been disrespected within the United States. Additionally, Senator Johnston himself states that &#8220;The recent advocacy for legislation targeted towards civil rights is &#8216;Un-American&#8217; and as unwarranted as it is unconstitutional.&#8221; </p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Sen. Byrd apologizes for association with Nazi sympathizer, Sen. Johnston denies allegations</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/latest-from-the-post-bbc-questionable-sympathies/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Sat, 09 Dec 2023 01:45:00 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=360</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[LATEST FROM THE POST &#38; BBC: Questionable Sympathies? The following senators have been identified as potential Nazi sympathizers via association with Nazi apologist and founder]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p><strong>LATEST FROM THE POST &amp; BBC: Questionable Sympathies?</strong></p>



<p>The following senators have been identified as potential Nazi sympathizers via association with Nazi apologist and founder of the Christian Nationalist Crusade Gerald L.K. Smith, Stuart Symington, Clinton Anderson, Olin D. Johnston, John Little McClellan, Allen J. Ellender, and Harry F. Byrd Sr.</p>



<p>Both the BBC and Washington Post were able to conduct interviews with Senators Harry F. Byrd Sr. and Olin D Johnston respectively. Senator Byrd Sr. confessed to the allegations against him stating &#8220;I apologize for saying that, that was very radical and extreme of me&#8230; I meant to say something else, more as a joke than anything.&#8221; Senator Byrd Sr.&#8217;s jokes will likely not be as comedic as he hoped as this breaking information does not seem like it could be of much benefit to his career or credibility within American politics.</p>



<p>Alternatively, Senator Johnston was baffled when approached about the allegations against him but after collecting his thoughts he was able to formulate a response. &#8220;I&#8217;ve served the US Government for a long time now, I&#8217;ve served in both the first and second World Wars, and any claims of me being associated with the Nazi is honestly just ridiculous,&#8221; said Johnston. Senator Johnston believes he&#8217;s done an insurmountable amount of work for the United States and wishes nothing but the support of the nation that he&#8217;s served so over the course of his career.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>X unveils plan for &#8216;everything&#8217; app</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/x-unveils-plan-for-everything-app/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 22:05:37 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Top Stories Slider]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[X Corporate Board]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=194</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Social network company X (formerly known as Twitter) has recently announced its transition from solely social media into an &#8220;everything app.&#8221; Everything apps, also called]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>Social network company X (formerly known as Twitter) has recently announced its transition from solely social media into an &#8220;everything app.&#8221; Everything apps, also called &#8220;super apps,&#8221; are mobile apps that can handle many aspects of digital life. These aspects include but are not limited to: direct messaging, video calls, location sharing, mobile payments, online shopping, games, online banking, and delivery services. </p>



<p>In an closed door interview with the Washington Post, X Director of Human Resources and Chair of Legal Department released specifics on some of the new features coming to the platform. These features will all be contained within a new app called X-Connect. It should be noticed that this will separate the parent company X from the daughter everything app that will be X-Connect, a situation similar to that of Uber and UberEats. Some of the features that can be expected to be found on X-Connect are an in-app browser extension, a professional business social network, an in-app streaming platform, and an artificial intelligence (A.I.) assistant.</p>



<p>Moreover, during a press conference Thursday, X Director of Public Relations made the promise that X will be the app that connects us all, in addition that &#8220;[X] will be the app that everyone has and everyone uses&#8221;. If the features that the company plans to release can successfully connect with its intended global audience, X&#8217;s aspirations may not be as unobtainable as they may seem.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>Ushering in a New Age of Patriotism: GOP senators seek to revolutionize US economy</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XX23/2023/12/08/ushering-in-a-new-age-of-patriotism-gop-senators-seek-to-revolutionize-us-economy/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Aaron Pryear, Washington Post]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 08 Dec 2023 16:38:15 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[United States Senate (1962)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">/ipd-archive/XX23/?p=198</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[It couldn&#8217;t be put any more clearly, &#8220;We are focused on American issues, American solutions, and the American people&#8221;, said Republican Senator James B. Pearson]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[
<p>It couldn&#8217;t be put any more clearly, &#8220;We are focused on American issues, American solutions, and the American people&#8221;, said Republican Senator James B. Pearson (R-Kan.). Within the Democratic Party there are various counts of division over the matters of economic development and civil rights. However, the Republican Party speaks very vocally upon their unity and their commitment to creating a spark within the American economy and the people that drive it.</p>



<p>The party is specifically lobbying to impose protective tariffs to combat the effects of the Chinese steel industry, cooperating with American organizations such as Boeing to aid in the Space Race, and funding programs to promote American workforce participation across the nation.</p>



<p>In order to address the concerns over civil rights looming across the nation, the Republican Party plans to enact welfare programs in order to aid those less fortunate. Additionally, Republican Sen. George Aiken of Vermont and Sen. Pearson both openly support the rights of women and intend to develop avenues for women to become more active within society as a whole. These avenues include but are not limited to an increased role in the workforce, enforcing equal pay, and expanding women&#8217;s access to secondary education. These strategies will boost the American economy as well as aid the nation&#8217;s citizens in need of federal support as they seek to chase the American dream and create a prosperous life for themselves.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
