<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?><rss version="2.0"
	xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/"
	xmlns:wfw="http://wellformedweb.org/CommentAPI/"
	xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/"
	xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"
	xmlns:sy="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/syndication/"
	xmlns:slash="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/slash/"
	
	xmlns:georss="http://www.georss.org/georss"
	xmlns:geo="http://www.w3.org/2003/01/geo/wgs84_pos#"
	>

<channel>
	<title>Elly Noble-Schueller, Islamic Republic News Agency &#8211; The CIMUN Chronicle</title>
	<atom:link href="/ipd-archive/XIX23/author/enoble/feed/?simply_static_page=1383" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
	<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23</link>
	<description>News from the International Press Delegation</description>
	<lastBuildDate>Sat, 22 Jul 2023 19:03:06 +0000</lastBuildDate>
	<language>en-US</language>
	<sy:updatePeriod>
	hourly	</sy:updatePeriod>
	<sy:updateFrequency>
	1	</sy:updateFrequency>
	<generator>https://wordpress.org/?v=6.1.1</generator>
	<item>
		<title>Has UNGA reached a resolution?</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/has-unga-reached-a-resolution/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elly Noble-Schueller, Islamic Republic News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 22:48:25 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Historical]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[United Nations General Assembly (1982)]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1144</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[Things are getting hot at the UN General Assembly! The UNGA talks about military technology that exists in space and beyond the planet. The delegations]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-03-4.30.56-PM-150x150.png" alt="" width="240" height="240"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Space exploration</figcaption></figure></div>


<p class="has-black-color has-text-color has-medium-font-size">Things are getting hot at the UN General Assembly! The UNGA talks about military technology that exists in space and beyond the planet. The delegations appear to get along well and have been able to come to some sort of consensus. They underscore, grabbing the Paraguayan delegation aside, &#8220;A resolution that helps underdeveloped and developed countries have equal opportunity in outer space has around 20 signatories and I am hopeful that the resolution will pass.&#8221; Despite the partial agreement, it was clear from seeing the unmoderated caucus that this committee was not all love and peace. Several developing nations, including Zambia and Paraguay, have said they wish to pool their resources, money, and energies to the best of their abilities to make the world&#8217;s outer space more equal. Other nations, like Iran, prioritize developing nations and their resources to build the &#8220;footing&#8221; of space. Only time will tell how the chips lay in UNGA. I think whoever has the money to fund it should just fund everything.</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
		<item>
		<title>UNEA Progression</title>
		<link>/ipd-archive/XIX23/unea-progression/</link>
		
		<dc:creator><![CDATA[Elly Noble-Schueller, Islamic Republic News Agency]]></dc:creator>
		<pubDate>Fri, 03 Feb 2023 19:30:13 +0000</pubDate>
				<category><![CDATA[Present Day]]></category>
		<category><![CDATA[UN Environment Assembly]]></category>
		<guid isPermaLink="false">https://press.cimun.org/news/?p=1035</guid>

					<description><![CDATA[While spectating the UNEA, also known as the United Nations Environment Assembly, they were ferociously debating weighty issues surrounding climate change that could be deemed]]></description>
										<content:encoded><![CDATA[<div class="wp-block-image">
<figure class="alignright is-resized"><img decoding="async" loading="lazy" src="https://press.cimun.org/news/wp-content/uploads/2023/02/Screenshot-2023-02-03-1.26.17-PM-150x150.png" alt="" width="270" height="270"/><figcaption class="wp-element-caption">Iran&#8217;s expansion of nuclear power</figcaption></figure></div>


<p class="has-black-color has-white-background-color has-text-color has-background has-medium-font-size">While spectating the UNEA, also known as the United Nations Environment Assembly, they were ferociously debating weighty issues surrounding climate change that could be deemed detrimental to humankind and all other possible living things on the planet Earth. The delegation from Uruguay discusses the three environmental issues covered by UNEA this weekend while participating in an exclusive moderated caucus, &#8220;We need to focus on sources for renewable energy, ocean biodiversity, and natural disasters resulting from the effects of climate change&#8221;. The committee then discussed which issue needed to be tackledfirst depending on their country&#8217;s idea of importance. Pulling the Iranian delegation of the UNEA aside, they voice their strong opinion,  &#8220;We want to create aid, to then increase the amount of nuclear energy being used in developing countries since these tend to be the countries suffering most from climate change.&#8221;</p>
]]></content:encoded>
					
		
		
			</item>
	</channel>
</rss>
